[
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-2?\n",
        "answer": "17,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What colors are runway holding position signs?\n",
        "answer": "White with a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red with a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow with a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 157.) This is an example of\n",
        "answer": "an ILS Critical Area Boundary Sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "an ILS Critical Area Holding Position Sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a Runway Boundary Sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the yellow demarcation bar marking?\n",
        "answer": "Delineates runway with a displaced threshold from a blast pad, stopway or taxiway\nthat precedes the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Delineates entrance to runway from a taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Delineates beginning of runway available for landing when pavement is aligned with\nrunway on approach side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the tower and Flight Control Center (FCC) are located on the same airport, which\nfunction is provided by the FCC during those periods when the tower is closed?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Advisory Service.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach control services.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in Class G airspace in VFR conditions\nduring daylight hours in area 4?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which speed variation should you notify ATC?\n",
        "answer": "When the average true airspeed changes 5 percent or 10 knots, whichever is greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the ground speed changes more than 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time the ground speed changes 10 MPH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot cancel the IFR flight plan prior to completing the flight?\n",
        "answer": "Only in VFR conditions when not in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only if an emergency occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition is guaranteed for all of the following altitude limits: MAA, MCA, MRA,\nMOCA, and MEA? (Non-mountainous area.)\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot obstacle clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Adequate navigation signals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Adequate communications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is primarily responsible for maintait\n",
        "answer": "Owner or operator of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The lead mechanic responsible for that aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot in command or operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When operating a civil aircraft registered in the EAC region, which document is required\nby regulation to be available in the aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "A current, approved Airplane (or Rotorcraft) Flight Manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "A manufacturer's Operations Manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An Owner's Manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating limitations of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane?\n",
        "answer": "No person may operate a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane carrying passengers or\nproperty for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "A \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane is limited to a specified operating radius from its home\nbase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A pilot of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane must hold a commercial pilot certificate when\ncarrying passengers for compensation or hire.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first freedom of the air is:\n",
        "answer": "The right to overfly without landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right to land for a technical stop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The opportunity to operate a commercial flight with passengers on board between\ntwo states.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right to board passengers from the state where the aircraft is registered and to\nfly to an other state.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC has assigned you the transponder code 5320.\nIn case of loosing two way radio communication, you have to squawk:\n",
        "answer": "Mode A Code 7600\n",
        "choiceone": "Mode A Code 5320\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mode A Code 7700\n",
        "choicethree": "Mode A Code 7500\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:\n",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately interrupted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time:\n",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until it stops at\nthe end of the flight (block time).\n",
        "choicetwo": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and temperature on\nthat day.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The centre line and crossbar lights of a precision approach Category | lighting\nsystem shall be fixed lights, showing variable intensity of the following colour:\n",
        "answer": "white\n",
        "choiceone": "green\n",
        "choicetwo": "blue\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of runway lighting con:\neach side of the runway threshold?\n\nsts of a pair of synchronized flashing lights, one on\n",
        "answer": "REIL.\n",
        "choiceone": "RAIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "HIRL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Haze can give the illusion that the aircraft is\n",
        "answer": "farther from the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choiceone": "closer to the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same distance from the runway as when there is no restriction to visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in Class G airspace in VFR conditions\nduring daylight hours in area 4?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an alternate airport is required, what are the weather minimums that must be\nforecast at the ETA for an alternate airport that has a precision approach procedure?\n\n",
        "answer": "600 foot ceiling and 2 statute miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ceiling 200 feet above the approach minimums and at least 1 statute mile visibility,\nbut not less than the minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ceiling 200 feet above field elevation and visibility 1 statute mile, but not less than\nthe minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum flight time in 24 consecutive hours that an air operator may schedule a\npilot in a two-pilot crew without a rest period is\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 80.) What is the TDZE for landing on RWY 27R?-\n",
        "answer": "3,514 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,649 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,450 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, the tow pilot is required to\nhave\n",
        "answer": "a logbook endorsement from an authorized glider instructor certifying receipt of\nground and flight training in gliders, and be proficient with techniques and\nprocedures for safe towing of gliders.\n",
        "choiceone": "at least a private pilot certificate with a category rating for powered aircraft, and\nmade and logged at least three flights as pilot or observer in a glider being towed by\nan airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a logbook record of having made at least three flights as sole manipulator of the\ncontrols of a glider being towed by an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What restrictions must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment of an airplane operated under the CAA regulations in an east african\nstate?\n",
        "answer": "Cargo may be carried aft of a divider if properly secured by a safety belt or other\ntiedown devices to withstand certain load stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "All cargo must be separated from the passengers by a partition capable of\nwithstanding certain load stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable flame resistant bin and the bin must be\nsecured to the floor structure of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Duty and rest period rules for domestic air operations require that a flight crewmember\n",
        "answer": "not be assigned to any duty with the airline during any required rest period.\n",
        "choiceone": "not be on duty aloft for more than 100 hours in any 30-day period.\n",
        "choicetwo": "be relieved of all duty for at least 24 hours during any 7 consecutive days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before beginning any flight under IFR, the pilot in command must become fami\nall available information concerning that flight. In addition, the pilot must\n\n",
        "answer": "be familiar with the runway lengths at airports of intended use, weather reports, fuel\nrequirements, the alternatives available, if the flight cannot be completed.\n",
        "choiceone": "be familiar with all instrument approaches at the destination airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and confirm adequate takeoff and landing\nperformance at the destination airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the floor of Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before each takeoff, the pilot in command of an aircraft carrying passengers shall\nensure that all passengers have been orally briefed on the\n\n",
        "answer": "use of safety belts, location and operation of fire extinguishers, and smoking.\n",
        "choiceone": "location of normal and emergency exits, oxygen masks, and life preservers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use of seatbelts, smoking, and location and use of survival equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which speed variation should you notify ATC?\n",
        "answer": "When the average true airspeed changes 5 percent or 10 knots, whichever is greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the ground speed changes more than 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time the ground speed changes 10 MPH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight training device and/or approved flight\nsimulator, the applicant is\n",
        "answer": "required to have a first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have at least a third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not required to have a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018selecting an altitude when operating with a VFR-\n\nOn-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum IFR altitude, minimum distance from clouds, and visibility appropriate to\naltitude selected.\n",
        "choiceone": "At least 500 feet above the lowest MEA, or appropriate MOCA, and at least 1,000 feet\nabove the existing meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At least 1,000 feet above the lowest MEA, appropriate MOCA, or existing\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of certain portable electronic devices is pro!\noperated under\n\nited on aircraft that are being\n",
        "answer": "IFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DVFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-1?\n",
        "answer": "217 knots and 1.81 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "221 knots and 1.83 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "223 knots and 2.01 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an off-airways IFR flight over nonmountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 SM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What is the approximate fuel consumed when holding\nunder Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "1,440 pounds.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,870 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,230 pounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Required flight crewmembers\u2019 safety belts must be fastened\n",
        "answer": "while the crewmembers are at their stations.\n",
        "choiceone": "only during takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only during takeoff and landing when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\nfor a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a commercial airtransport airplane lands at an intermediate airport at 1822Z, what\nis the latest time it may continue a flight without receiving a redispatch authorization?\n",
        "answer": "00222.\n",
        "choiceone": "1922Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1952Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is required prior to takeoff if snow is adhering to the wings of an air carrier\nairplane?\n",
        "answer": "Ensure that the snow is removed from the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweep off as much snow as possible and the residue must be polished smooth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 15 knots to the normal V(R) speed as the snow will blow off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, to minimize DME slant range error, how far from the facility should\nyou be to consider the reading as accurate?\n",
        "answer": "One or more miles for each 1,000 feet of altitude above the facility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two miles or more for each 1,000 feet of altitude above the facility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No specific distance is specified since the reception is line-of-sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall have completed in aeroplanes not less\nthan:\n",
        "answer": "10 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choiceone": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 10 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of instrument time of which not more than 5 hours as pilot in command\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the initiation of an accident investigation?\n",
        "answer": "The Authority of the State in which the accident took place.\n",
        "choiceone": "The Operators of the same aircraft type.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft manufacturer.\n",
        "choicethree": "The State of design and manufacturer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless a higher speed is required due to turbulence or icing and ATC is notified, the\nmaximum holding speed for a civil turbojet holding at a civil airport at 18,000 feet above\nMSL is:\n",
        "answer": "265 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "250 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a requirement governing the carriage of carry-on baggage?\n",
        "answer": "All carry-on baggage must be restrained so that its movement is prevented during air\nturbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Carry-on baggage must be stowed under the seat in front of the owner.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pieces of carry-on baggage weighing more than 10 pounds must be carried in an\napproved rack or bin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data kept, in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in terminating the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is DME required under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet above MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In positive control airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to carrying passengers at night, the pilot in command must have accom,\nrequired takeoffs and landings in\n",
        "answer": "the same category, class, and type of aircraft (if a type rating is required).\n",
        "choiceone": "any category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same category and class of aircraft to be used.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of runway lighting con:\neach side of the runway threshold?\n\nsts of a pair of synchronized flashing lights, one on\n",
        "answer": "REIL.\n",
        "choiceone": "RAIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "HIRL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RVR is not reported, what meteorologi\nRVR?\n\nil value should you substitute for 2,400\n",
        "answer": "A ground visibility of 600m.\n",
        "choiceone": "A ground visibility of 400m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slant range visibility of 2,400 feet for the final approach segment of the published\napproach procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whatis the maximum\nairspace?\n\nthe airspace underlying Class B\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon intercepting the assigned radial, the controller advises you that you are on the\nairway and to \"RESUME OWN NAVIGATION.\u2019 This phrase means that\n",
        "answer": "you are to assume responsibility for your own navigation.\n",
        "choiceone": "you are still in radar contact, but must make position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "radar services are terminated and you will be responsible for position reports.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air operator may schedule a pilot to fly in an airplane, having two pilots and one\nadditional flight crewmember, for no more than\n",
        "answer": "12 hours during any 24 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ensuring that appropriate aeronautical charts are aboard an aircraft is the responsibility\nof the:\n",
        "answer": "pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight navigator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acommercial pilot in command in EAC is required to hold a type rating?\n",
        "answer": "When operating any aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating an aircraft having a gross weight of more than 12,500 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When operating a multiengine aircraft having a gross weight of more than 6,000\npounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While you are flying at FL250, you hear ATC give an altimeter setting of 28.92\" Hg in\nyour area. At what pressure altitude are you flying?\n",
        "answer": "25,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "24,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "26,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What requirement must be met regarding cargo that is carried anywhere in the\npassenger compartment of an air carrier airplane?\n",
        "answer": "The bin in which the cargo is carried may not be installed in a position that restricts\naccess to, or use of, any aisle in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The bin in which the cargo is carried may not be installed in a position that restricts\naccess to, or use of, any exit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The container or bin in which the cargo is carried must be made of material which is\nat least flash resistant.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which data must be recorded in the aircraft log or other appropriate log by a pilot\nmaking a VOR operational check for IFR operations?\n",
        "answer": "Place of operational check, amount of bearing error, date of check, and signature.\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR name or identification, date of check, amount of bearing error, and signature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Date of check, VOR name or identification, place of operational check, and amount of\nbearing error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While in flight a helicopter and an airplane are converging at a 90degrees, and the\nhelicopter is located to the right of the airplane. Which aircraft has the right-of-way, and\nwhy?\n",
        "answer": "The helicopter, because it is to the right of the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The helicopter, because helicopters have the right-of-way over airplanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airplane, because airplanes have the right-of-way over helicopters.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot cancel the IFR flight plan prior to completing the flight?\n",
        "answer": "Only in VFR conditions when not in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only if an emergency occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-On-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1200 feet AGL). What is the in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operation in Class E airspace during daylight hours for area 1?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The persons jointly responsible for th\ntermination of a commercial flight are the:\n\nition, continuation, diversion, and\n\n",
        "answer": "pilot in command and director of operations.\n",
        "choiceone": "pilot in command and chief pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot in command and the flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) establishes:\n",
        "answer": "standards and recommended international practices for contracting member states.\n",
        "choiceone": "aeronautical standards adopted by all states.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proposals for aeronautical regulations in the form of 18 annexes.\n",
        "choicethree": "standards and recommended practices applied without exception by all states,\nsignatory to the Chicago convention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What\nG airspace?\n\nplane to operate under VFR in Class\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot ceiling; 2-miles flight visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile flight visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, then:\n",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed\n",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour to\nprovide for continuation of the flight;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;\n",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person in East Africa is acting as pilot in command of a multiengine, turboprop-\npowered airplane operated in passenger-carrying service by a commuter air carrier. If\neight takeoffs and landings are accomplished in that make and basic model, which\nadditional pilot-in-command experience meets the requirement for designation as pilot\nin command?\n",
        "answer": "10 hours, and three takeoffs and landings.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 hours, and two takeoffs and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours, and two takeoffs and one landings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Member states should introduce specific security measures for the air transport of the\nfollowing groups of potentially disruptive passengers defined below:\n",
        "answer": "Deportees, inadmissible persons and persons in lawful custody\n",
        "choiceone": "Deportees and persons in lawful custody only\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deportees and inadmissible persons only\n",
        "choicethree": "None of the answers is correct\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight training device and/or approved flight\nsimulator, the applicant is\n",
        "answer": "required to have a first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have at least a third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not required to have a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lights on a passenger-carrying airplane must be armed or turned on\nduring\n",
        "answer": "taxiing, takeoff, and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "taxiing, takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding position signs have\n",
        "answer": "white inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "red inscriptions on a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the maximum altitude that Class G airspace will exist?\n(Does not include airspace less than 1,500 feet AGL.)\n",
        "answer": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What recent experience is required to be eligible for the practical test for the original\nissue of a Category Il authorization?\n",
        "answer": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches, three of which may be flown to\nthe Category | DH.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches flown manually to the Category |\nDH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the previous 12 calendar months, six ILS approaches flown by use of an\napproach coupler to the Category | or Category Il DH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the line check requirements for the pilot in command for a domestic air carrier?\n",
        "answer": "The line check is required every 12 calendar months in one of the types of airplanes\nto be flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The line check is required only when the pilot is scheduled to fly into special areas\nand airports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line check is required every 12 months in each type aircraft in which the pilot\nmay fly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A coded transponder equipped with altitude reporting capabil\ncontrolled airspace\n\nis required in all\n",
        "answer": "at and above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "at and above 2,500 feet above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operation of a cockpit voice recorder in a large\npressurized airplane with four reciprocating engines\n",
        "answer": "may all be erasedexcept for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "may be erased except for the last 30 minutes prior to landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may all be erased, as the voice recorder is not required on an aircraft with\nreciprocating engines.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a definition of the term \u2018crewmember\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "A person assigned to perform duty in an aircraft during flight time.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only a pilot, flight engineer, or flight navigator assigned to duty in an aircraft during\nflight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any person assigned to duty in an aircraft during flight except a pilot or flight\nengineer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial pilot - airplane, if that\nperson does not hold an instrument rating? The carriage of passengers\n",
        "answer": "for hire on cross-country flights in excess of 50 NM or for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for night flights, but not limited for\nday flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is limited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 71A.) What is your position relative to the Flosi intersection\nNorthbound on V213?\n",
        "answer": "West of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "East of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "West of V213 and past the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acommercial pilot in command in EAC is required to hold a type rating?\n",
        "answer": "When operating any aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating an aircraft having a gross weight of more than 12,500 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When operating a multiengine aircraft having a gross weight of more than 6,000\npounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command must complete a proficiency check or\npreceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the normal upper limit for Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 130.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot flying a single-engine airplane observes a multiengine airplane approaching from\nthe left. Which pilot should give way?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot of the multiengine airplane should give way\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot of the single-engine airplane should give way\n",
        "choicetwo": "Each pilot should alter course to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum fuel requirements in IFR conditions, i\nlanding is forecast to have a 1,500-foot ceiling and 3 miles vi\nETA? Fuel to fly to the first airport of intended landing,\n\nthe first airport of intended\nity at flight-planned\n",
        "answer": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the minimum safe speed for any particular operation is greater than the maximum\nspeed prescribed in EAC states\u2019 Regulations\n\n",
        "answer": "aircraft may be operated at that speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "operator must have a Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) with the controlling agency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operator must have a Letter of Agreement with ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight attendant crewmember is required on aircraft having a passenger seating\nconfiguration, excluding any pilot seat, of\n",
        "answer": "20 or more\n",
        "choiceone": "15 or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19 or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an operational check on the aircraft VOR equipment be accomplished when\nused to operate under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the preceding 10 days or 10 hours of flight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the preceding 30 days or 30 hours of flight time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Preferred IFR routes beginning with a fix indicate that departing\nrouted to the fix by\n\nrcraft will normally be\n",
        "answer": "an instrument departure procedure (DP), or radar vectors.\n",
        "choiceone": "the established airway(s) between the departure airport and the fix.\n",
        "choicetwo": "direct route only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with the Operation of Aircraft regulations in the EAC, supplemental\noxygen must be used by the required minimum flightcrew for that time exceeding 30\nminutes while at cabin pressure altitude\n",
        "answer": "12,500 feet MSL up to and including 1,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,500 feet MSL up to and including 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12,000 feet MSL up to and including 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oxygen requirement for an unpressurized aircraft at 15,000 feet under the\nOperation of Aircraft regulations in East Africa?\n",
        "answer": "Crew must start using oxygen at 12,000 feet and passengers at 14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "All occupants must use oxygen for the entire time at this altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew must use oxygen for the entire time above 14,000 feet and passengers must be\nprovided supplemental oxygen only above 15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you obtain the pressure altitude on flights below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Set your altimeter to 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choiceone": "Use your computer to change the indicated altitude to pressure altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Contact an FSS and ask for the pressure altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an air carrier airplane be DME equipped?\n",
        "answer": "Whenever VOR navigational receivers are required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In Class E airspace for all IFR or VFR on Top operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For flights at or above FL 180.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:\n",
        "answer": "Control zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Changing of flight rules from IFR to VFR is possible\n",
        "answer": "If the commander so requests\n",
        "choiceone": "If instructed by ATC so long as VMC is forecasted during the next 30 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "If instructed by ATC so long as VMC is forecasted during the next 60 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when leaving controlled airspace\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information concerning parachute jumping sites may be found in the\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Graphic Notices and Supplemental Data.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-1?\n",
        "answer": "19,400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 78 and 79.) What is your position relative to the VOR COP southeast\nbound on V86 between the BOZEMAN and LIVINGSTON VORTACs? The No. 1 VOR is\ntuned to 116.1 and the No. 2 VOR is tuned to 112.2.\n",
        "answer": "Past the LVM R-246 and east of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choiceone": "Past the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approaching the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sources of aeronautical information, when used collectively, provide the latest\nstatus of airport conditions (e.g., runway closures, runway lighting, snow conditions)?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Facility Directory, Distant (D) NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual, aeronautical charts, and Distant (D) Notice to\nAirmen (NOTAM's).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport Facility Directory, FDC NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A standard airworthiness certificate remains in effect as long as the aircraft receives\n",
        "answer": "required maintenance and inspections.\n",
        "choiceone": "an annual inspection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an annual inspection and a 100-hour inspection prior to their expiration dates.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Full scale deflection of a CDI occurs when the course deviation bar or needle\n",
        "answer": "deflects from the center of the scale to either far side of the scale.\n",
        "choiceone": "deflects from left side of the scale to right side of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "deflects from half scale left to half scale right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What recent experience is required to be eligible for the practical test for the original\nissue of a Category Il authorization?\n",
        "answer": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches, three of which may be flown to\nthe Category | DH.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches flown manually to the Category |\nDH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the previous 12 calendar months, six ILS approaches flown by use of an\napproach coupler to the Category | or Category Il DH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in\nClass G airspace during daylight hours for area 2?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the recommended procedure for transitioning from VFR to IFR on a composite\nflight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Prior to transitioning to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center close the VFR portion,\nand request ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upon reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center\nand cancel your VFR flight plan, then contact ACC and request an IFR clearance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prior to reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact ACC, request your\nIFR clearance, and instruct them to cancel the VFR flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized when carrying passengers for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not authorized when visibilities are less than 3 SM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 71A.) What is your position relative to the Flosi intersection\nNorthbound on V213?\n",
        "answer": "West of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "East of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "West of V213 and past the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As each blade flaps up and down, it produces a shift of the center of its mass. When the\nblade flaps up, the CG moves closer to its axis of rotation, giving that blade a tendency\nto\n",
        "answer": "accelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as Coriolis effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "stabilize its rotational velocity, thus compensating for dissymmetry of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as translating tendency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) is not available when setting up for\nGPS approach, the pilot should\n",
        "answer": "select another type of approach using another type of navigation aid.\n",
        "choiceone": "continue to the MAP and hold until the satellites are recaptured.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proceed as cleared to the IAF and hold until satellite reception is satisfactory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rule applies to the use of the cockpit voice recorder erasure feature?\n",
        "answer": "Any information more than 30 minutes old may be erased.\n",
        "choiceone": "All recorded information may be erased, except for the last 30 minutes prior to\nlanding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All recorded information may be erased, unless the NTSB needs to be notified of an\noccurrence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting is the value to which the scale of the pressure altimeter is set so the\naltimeter indicates\n",
        "answer": "true altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure altitude at sea level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which time period must a required voice recorder of a passenger-carrying\nairplane be continuously operated?\n",
        "answer": "From the use of the checklist before the flight to completion of the final check at the\nend of the flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "From the beginning of taxi to the end of the landing roll.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From engine start at departure airport to engine shutdown at landing airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of an accident or occurrence requiring immediate notification of the CAA,\nthe operator shall keep flight recorder and cockpit voice recorder data for at least\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "90 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight simulator and an aircraft, the applicant\nis\n",
        "answer": "required to have a current first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have a least a current third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not required to hold a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For flight under IFR, a person serving as second in command of an aircraft under the\nCAA regulations in an East african State person must have accomplished within the last\n6 months, the recent instrument requirements of\n",
        "answer": "holding procedures, using the navigation systems for intercepting and tracking\ncourses, and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "choiceone": "using the navigation systems for interception and tracking of courses, 6 instrument\nlow approaches and holding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "using the navigation systems to intercept and track 3 inbound/3 outbound courses,\n6 holding patterns and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence aeroplane shall have completed, in\naeroplanes not less than:\n",
        "answer": "20 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "choiceone": "10 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When not flying over high terrain or mountainous areas and where no minimum flight\naltitude has been established, flights in accordance with IFR shall be flown at a level\nwhich is at least:\n",
        "answer": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft is subjected to unlawful interference, the pilot-in-command shall\nindicate the situation by setting the transponder to Mode A, Code\n",
        "answer": "7500.\n",
        "choiceone": "7700.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7600.\n",
        "choicethree": "7000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A complete position report transmitted by ra\nelements of information in the order listed.\n\ntelephony shall contain the following\n",
        "answer": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next position\nand time over, 6) ensuing significant point.\n",
        "choiceone": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) flight level or altitude, 4) time, 5) next position\nand time over, 6) ensuing significant point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) true air speed, 5) flight level or altitude,\n6) next position and time over.\n",
        "choicethree": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next position,\n6) time over.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the initiation of an accident investigation?\n",
        "answer": "The Authority of the State in which the accident took place.\n",
        "choiceone": "The Operators of the same aircraft type.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft manufacturer.\n",
        "choicethree": "The State of design and manufacturer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What service is provided by departure control to an IFR flight when operating within the\nouter area of Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Separation from all IFR aircraft and participating VFR aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Separation from all aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position and altitude of all traffic within 2 miles of the IFR pilot's line of flight and\naltitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 68.) What is the VASI approach slope angle for RWY 12?\n",
        "answer": "3.0 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "2.8 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC transponder is not to be used unless it has been tested, inspected, and found to\ncomply with regulations within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when necessary for takeoff or landing or unless otherwise authorized by the\nCAA, the minimum altitude for IFR flight is\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle over designated mountainous terrain;\nfeet above the highest obstacle over terrain elsewhere.\n\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet over all terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,000 feet over designated mountainous terrain; 2,000 feet over terrain elsewhere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which restriction must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment?\n",
        "answer": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable bin and secured to a passenger seat or the\nfloor structure of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis packaged or covered to avoid possible injury to occupants.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cargo carried in passenger seats must be forward of all passengers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is DME required for an instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In terminal radar service areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot file a composite flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Any time a portion of the flight will be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "When requested or advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time a landing is planned at an intermediate airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ap\nenforcement personnel?\n\nto the carriage of a person in the custody of law\n",
        "answer": "No more than one person considered to be in the maximum risk category may be\ncarried on a flight, and that person must have at least two armed law enforcement\nescorts.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air carrier is not allowed to serve beverages to the person in custody or the law\nenforcement escort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The person in custody must be seated between the escort and the aisle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures for keeping copies of the aircraft maintenance log of the aircraft available to\nappropriate personnel shall be set forth in\n",
        "answer": "the certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maintenance procedures handbook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Operations Specifications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The required preflight action relative to weather reports and fuel requirements is\napplicable to\n",
        "answer": "any flight not in the vicinity of an airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "any flight conducted for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR flights only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For what purpose may cockpit voice recorders and flight data recorders NOT be used?\n",
        "answer": "Determining any certificate action, or civil penalty, arising out of an accident or\noccurrence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Determining causes of accidents and occurrences under investigation by the Civil\nAviation Authority.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identifying procedures that may have been conducive to any accident, or\noccurrence\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tricolor Visual Approach Indicators normally consist of\n",
        "answer": "a single unit, projecting a three-color visual approach path.\n",
        "choiceone": "three separate light units, each projecting a different color approach path.\n",
        "choicetwo": "three separate light projecting units of very high candle power with a daytime range\nof approximately 5 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum qualifications for a person who occupies the other control seat\nas safety pilot during simulated instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot certificate with appropriate category and class ratings for the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Private pilot with instrument rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Private pilot with appropriate category, class, and instrument ratings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If not equipped with required position lights, an aircraft must terminate flight\n",
        "answer": "at sunset.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes after sunset.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour after sunset.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what time period should the nearest ATS office be notified when an aircraft is\ninvolved in an accident which results in substantial damage?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 calendar days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 77.) At which point does the basi\nterminate?\n\ninstrument departure procedure\n",
        "answer": "At STAKK intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "When Helena Departure Control establishes radar contact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Over the BOZEMAN VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum number of hours a pilot may fly in 7 consecutive days as the pilot in\ncommand in a two-pilot crew for air operator is:\n\n",
        "answer": "32 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "35 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial pilot has a type rating in a B-727 and B-737. A flight test is completed in a\nB-747 for the Airline Transport Pilot Certificate. What pilot privileges may be exercised\nregarding these airplanes?\n\n",
        "answer": "ATP - B-747, B-727, and B-737.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial - B-737; ATP - B-727 and B-747.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATP - B-747; Commercial - B-727 and B-737.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is a pilot on an IFR flight plan responsible for avoiding other aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "When weather conditions permit, regardless of whether operating under IFR or VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "At all times when notin radar contact with ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when advised by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operational requirement must be observed when ferrying a large, turbine-engine-\npowered airplane when one of its engines is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The weather conditions at takeoff and destination must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Weather conditions must exceed the basic VFR minimums for the entire route,\nincluding takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The flight cannot be conducted between official sunset and sunrise.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, except by arrangement with the pilot in command of each aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which facility may be substituted for the middle marker during a Category I ILS\napproach?\n",
        "answer": "Compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORIDME FIX.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surveillance radar.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination flight information for planning an instrument\nflight should be obtained from\n",
        "answer": "the Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "the ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airmen (Class Il).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When not flying over high terrain or mountainous areas and where no minimum flight\naltitude has been established, flights in accordance with IFR shall be flown at a level\nwhich is at least:\n",
        "answer": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the latest date that a flight engineer in East Africa may perform duties\nif his or her last medical examination was a first-class conducted on August 25, 1999?\n",
        "answer": "August 24, 2000.\n",
        "choiceone": "September 30, 2000.\n",
        "choicetwo": "August 31, 2000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial\nperson does not hold an instrument pilot rating?\n\nplane pilot if that\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 nautical miles (NM).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for\nnight flights, but not limited for day flights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on meteorological conditions?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should notification of an aircraft accident be made to the responsible authority if\nthere was substantial damage and no injuries?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum navigation equipment is required for IFR flight?\n",
        "answer": "Navigation equipment appropriate to the ground facilities to be used.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORILOC receiver, transponder, and DME.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR receiver and, if in ARTS Ill environment, a coded transponder equipped for\naltitude reporting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What international Morse Cod:\nmicrowave landing system?\n\nlentifier is used t\n",
        "answer": "A three letter Morse Code identifier preceded by the Morse Code for the letter\n\n",
        "choiceone": "A two letter Morse Code identifier preceded by the Morse Code for the letters 'IM.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "A three letter Morse Code identifier preceded by the Morse Code for the letters \"ML.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition, if any, may a pilot descend below DH or MDA when using the\napproach light system as the primary visual reference for the intended runway?\n",
        "answer": "The approach light system can be used as a visual reference, except that descent\nbelow 100 feet above TDZE requires that the red light bars be visible and identifiable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Under no condition can the approach light system serve as a necessary visual\nreference for descent below DH or MDA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent to the intended runway is authorized as long as any portion of the\napproach light system can be seen.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recommended entry position to an airport traffic pattern is\n",
        "answer": "to enter 45 degrees at the midpoint of the downwind leg at traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "45 degrees to the base leg just below traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to cross directly over the airport at traffic pattern altitude and join the downwind leg.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ap\nenforcement personnel?\n\nto the carriage of a person in the custody of law\n",
        "answer": "No more than one person considered to be in the maximum risk category may be\ncarried on a flight, and that person must have at least two armed law enforcement\nescorts.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air carrier is not allowed to serve beverages to the person in custody or the law\nenforcement escort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The person in custody must be seated between the escort and the aisle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft is not equipped with an electrical or anticolli\nmay operate that aircraft\n\nin light system, no person\n",
        "answer": "after sunset to sunrise.\n",
        "choiceone": "after dark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour after sunset.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What purpose does the taxiway location sign serve?\n",
        "answer": "Identifies taxiway on which an aircraft is located.\n",
        "choiceone": "Provides general taxiing direction to named runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Denotes entrance to runway from a taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data kept, in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in terminating the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon intercepting the assigned radial, the controller advises you that you are on the\nairway and to \"RESUME OWN NAVIGATION.\u2019 This phrase means that\n",
        "answer": "you are to assume responsibility for your own navigation.\n",
        "choiceone": "you are still in radar contact, but must make position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "radar services are terminated and you will be responsible for position reports.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a commercial airtransport airplane lands at an intermediate airport at 1822Z, what\nis the latest time it may continue a flight without receiving a redispatch authorization?\n",
        "answer": "00222.\n",
        "choiceone": "1922Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1952Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movement area of an airport, what does a \"Destination\" sign indicate?\n",
        "answer": "Direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction from taxiway to runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction from ramp to taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'No Entry\u2019 sign identifies\n",
        "answer": "paved area where aircraft entry is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the upper limit for Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "60,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 56.) You have requested taxi instructions for takeoff using Runway 16.\nThe controller issues the following taxi instructions: \"5H-ABC, Taxi to runway 16.\u201d\nWhere are you required to stop in order to be in compliance with the controller's\ninstructions\n",
        "answer": "5 (Five).\n",
        "choiceone": "6 (Six).\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 (Nine).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a certificate holder deviates from the provisions of regulations which pertain to\nmedical use of oxygen by passengers, a complete report of the incident shall be sent to\nthe Authority within\n",
        "answer": "10 working days.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 working days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days of the deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination flight information for planning an instrument\nflight should be obtained from\n",
        "answer": "the Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "the ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airmen (Class Il).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless suspended or revoked, a flight engineer licence in East Africa:\n",
        "answer": "expires 1 to 2 years after the month of issuance depending on age\n",
        "choiceone": "is issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choicetwo": "expires at the end of the 24th month following the month of issuance or renewal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the line check requirements for the pilot in command for a domestic air carrier?\n",
        "answer": "The line check is required every 12 calendar months in one of the types of airplanes\nto be flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The line check is required only when the pilot is scheduled to fly into special areas\nand airports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line check is required every 12 months in each type aircraft in which the pilot\nmay fly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an engine's rotation is stopped\nas practicable, to the\n\night, the pilot in command must reportit, as soon\n",
        "answer": "appropriate ground radio station.\n",
        "choiceone": "nearest CAA office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operations manager (or director of operations).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a flight, the controller advises \u2018traffic 2 o'clock 5 miles southbound.\" The pilot is\nholding 20 correction for a crosswind from the right. Where should the pilot look for the\ntraffic?\n",
        "answer": "40 degrees to the right of the aircraft's nose.\n",
        "choiceone": "20 degrees to the right of the aircraft's nose.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Straight ahead.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When does Air Traffic Control Services have the responsibility to prevent collisions with\nterrain?\n",
        "answer": "When a flight in accordance with IFR is vectored by radar.\n",
        "choiceone": "Always when ATS are provided.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATS never prevent collisions with terrain.\n",
        "choicethree": "ATS only provides prevention when an aircraft is flying IFR in IMC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following elements\n",
        "answer": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and pre-flight\ninformation bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries\n",
        "choiceone": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP, NOTAM, AIC and checklist\nsummaries\n",
        "choicetwo": "AIP, supplements to AIP; NOTAM and PIB; AIC and checklist summaries\n",
        "choicethree": "AIP including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM, AIC; AIRAC\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on vehicles other than those associated with emergency\nor security shall be\n",
        "answer": "Flashing yellow.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed blue.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flashing blue.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A series of continuous red lights in the runway centerline lighting indicates that\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "one-half of the runway remains.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ensuring that appropriate aeronautical charts are aboard an aircraft is the responsibility\nof the:\n",
        "answer": "pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight navigator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a commercial pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft\nfor compensation or hire, if that person\n",
        "answer": "is qualified in accordance with EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nwith the applicable parts that apply to the operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "holds appropriate category, class ratings, and meets the recent flight experience\nrequirements of EAC states' Personnel Licensing regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is qualified in accordance with the EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nhas passed a pilot competency check given by an authorized check pilot.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight simulator and an aircraft, the applicant\nis\n",
        "answer": "required to have a current first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have a least a current third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not required to hold a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "imposed on the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence if that person\ndoes not hold an instrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "That person is limited to private pilot privileges at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Haze can give the illusion that the aircraft is\n",
        "answer": "farther from the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choiceone": "closer to the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same distance from the runway as when there is no restriction to visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n25,000 pounds? |Initial weight: 179,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 136,500 Ib\n",
        "answer": "8 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what time period should the nearest ATS office be notified when an aircraft is\ninvolved in an accident which results in substantial damage?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 calendar days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RVR minimums for takeoff or landing are published in an AIP, if RVR is inoperative\nand cannot be reported for the runway at the time. Which of the following would apply?\n",
        "answer": "RVR minimums which are specified in the procedure should be converted and\napplied as ground visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "RVR minimums may be disregarded, providing the runway has an operative HIRL\nsystem.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RVR minimums may be disregarded, providing all other components of the ILS\nsystem are operative.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operations by a required cockpit voice recorder\n",
        "answer": "may be erased or obliterated, except the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "must be erased or obliterated, except for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be erased or obliterated, only once each flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "East Africa a certificate of validation issued to a qualified flight engineer applicant,\npending review of their application, is effective for what maximum period of time?\n",
        "answer": "120 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "60 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "90 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before takeoff, the pilot in command of an aircraft carrying passengers shall ensure that\nall passengers have been orally briefed on the normal and emergency use of oxygen\n",
        "answer": "if the flight involves operations above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "regardless of the altitude at which the flight will operate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the flight involves operations at or above 12,000 feet MSL for more than 30\nminutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movement area of an airport, what does a \"Destination\" sign indicate?\n",
        "answer": "Direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction from taxiway to runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction from ramp to taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air carrier must give instruction on such subjects as respiration, hypoxia, and\ndecompression to crewmembers serving on pressurized airplanes operated above\n",
        "answer": "FL 250.\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 180.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 200.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a requirement regarding the carriage and operation of oxygen equipment for\nmedical use by passengers?\n",
        "answer": "No person may smoke within 10 feet of oxygen storage and dispensing equipment.\n",
        "choiceone": "When oxygen equipment is used for the medical treatment of a patient, the rules\npertaining to emergency exit access are waived.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No person may connect oxygen bottles or any other ancillary equipment until all\npassengers are aboard the aircraft and seated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-4?\n",
        "answer": "50.7 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "48.3 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "51.3 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight time limitations established for flight crewmembers include\n",
        "answer": "all commercial flying in any flight crewmember position.\n",
        "choiceone": "only commercial flying in any flight crewmember position in which operations are\nconducted under the CAA Operation of Aircraft regulations of East Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all flight time, except military, in any flight crew-member position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than in cruise flight, below what altitude are non-safety related cockpit activities\nby flight crewmembers prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "12,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:\n",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.\n",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.\n",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, then:\n",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed\n",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour to\nprovide for continuation of the flight;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;\n",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Required Navigation Performance (RNP) shall be prescribed\n",
        "answer": "by states on the basis of regional air navigation agreements\n",
        "choiceone": "by states but not on the basis of regional air agreements\n",
        "choicetwo": "by ICAO on the basis of regional air navigation agreements\n",
        "choicethree": "by regional air navigation agreements\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a gyroplane carrying passengers, what must the pilot\naccomplish in that gyroplane to meet recent daytime flight experience requirements?\n",
        "answer": "Make three takeoffs and landings within the preceding 90 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Make nine takeoffs and landings within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Make three takeoffs and landings to a full stop within the preceding 90 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial pilot - airplane, if that\nperson does not hold an instrument rating? The carriage of passengers\n",
        "answer": "for hire on cross-country flights in excess of 50 NM or for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for night flights, but not limited for\nday flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is limited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an instrument approach, under what conditions, if any, is the holding pattern\ncourse reversal not required?\n",
        "answer": "When radar vectors are provided.\n",
        "choiceone": "When cleared for the approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "None, since it is always mandatory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What type of entry is recommended to the missed approach\nholding pattern if the inbound heading is 050 degrees?\n",
        "answer": "Teardrop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Parallel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 133.) What is the minimum altitude descent procedure if cleared for the\nS4LS 9 approach from Seal Beach VORTAC?\n",
        "answer": "Descend and maintain 3,000 to JASER INT, descend to 2,500 while established on\nthe LOC course inbound, intercept and maintain the GS to 991 (DH).\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend and maintain 3,000 to JASER INT, descend to and maintain 2,500 until\ncrossing SWAN LAKE, descend and maintain 1,260 until crossing AGNES, and to\n991 (DH) after passing AGNES.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descend and maintain 3,000 to JASER INT, descend to 2,800 when established on\nthe LOC course, intercept and maintain the GS to 991 (DH).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airplanes are required to be equipped with a ground proximity warning glide\nslope deviation alerting system?\n",
        "answer": "All turbine powered airplanes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Passenger-carrying turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Large turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum amount of flight instruction an authorized instructor may give in\nany 24 consecutive hours?\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "Regulations hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude and route should be used if the pilot is flying in IFR weather conditions\nand has two-way radio communications failure?\n",
        "answer": "Continue on the route specified in the clearance and fly the highest of the following:\nthe last assigned altitude, altitude ATC has informed the pilot to expect, or to the\nmaximum Elevation Altitude( MEA)\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend to MEA and, if clear of clouds, proceed to the nearest appropriate airport. If\nnot clear of clouds, maintain the highest of the MEAs along the clearance route.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly the most direct route to the destination, maintaining the last assigned altitude or\nMEA, whichever is higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When operating under IFR with a VFR-On-Top clearance, what altitude should be\nmaintained?\n",
        "answer": "A VFR cruising altitude appropriate to the magnetic course being flown and as\nrestricted by ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "The last IFR altitude assigned by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An IFR cruising altitude appropriate to the magnetic course being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operation of a cockpit voice recorder in a large\npressurized airplane with four reciprocating engines\n",
        "answer": "may all be erasedexcept for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "may be erased except for the last 30 minutes prior to landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may all be erased, as the voice recorder is not required on an aircraft with\nreciprocating engines.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a requirement governing the carriage of cargo, on a scheduled passenger\nflight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Cargo must be carried in an approved rack, bin, or compartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo not stowed in an approved bin must be secured by a safety belt or approved\ntiedown device.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo carried in the passenger compartment must be packaged and stowed\nahead of the foremost seated passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "By regulation, who shall provide the pilot in command of a domestic operations\ninformation concerning weather, and irregularities of facilities and services?\n\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which service is provided for IFR arrivals by a Flight Control Center( FCC) located on an\nairport without a control tower?\n\n",
        "answer": "Airport advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All functions of approach control.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine the pressure altitude on an airport without a tower or Flight\nControl Center?\n",
        "answer": "Set the altimeter to 29.92\" Hg and read the altitude indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Set the altimeter to the current altimeter setting of a station within 100 miles and\ncorrect this indicated altitude with local temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Use your computer and correct the field elevation for temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what time period should the nearest ATS office be notified when an aircraft is\ninvolved in an accident which results in substantial damage?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 calendar days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are certain areas that start 3 nautical miles from the coastline of the EAC. and\nextend outward, classified as Warning Areas?\n",
        "answer": "To warn pilots of nonparticipating aircraft of a potential danger within the area.\n",
        "choiceone": "To inform pilots of participating aircraft to maintain extreme vigilance while\nconducting flight within the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To warn all aircraft pilots that flying within the area may be extremely hazardous to\naircraft and occupants.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What period of time must a person be hospitalized before an injury may be defined as a\n\u2018serious injury\"?\n",
        "answer": "48 hours; commencing within 7 days after date of the injury.\n",
        "choiceone": "72 hours; commencing within 10 days after date of injury.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days, with no other extenuating circumstances.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which passenger announcement(s) must be made after each takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "Passengers should keep seat belts fastened while seated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Keep safety belts fastened while seated and no smoking in the aircraft lavatories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "How to use the passenger oxygen system and that there is a $1,000 fine for\ntampering with a smoke detector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal range of the tri-color VASI at night?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 89.) What are the oxygen requirements for an IFR flight northeast bound\nfrom Bryce Canyon on V382 at the lowest appropriate altitude in an unpressurized\naircraft?\n",
        "answer": "The required minimum crew must be provided and use supplemental oxygen, and all\noccupants must be provided supplemental oxygen for the entire flight above 15,000\nfeet.\n",
        "choiceone": "The required minimum crew must be provided and use supplemental oxygen for that\npart of the flight of more than 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The required minimum crew must be provided and use supplemental oxygen for that\npart of the flight of more than 30 minutes, and the passengers must be provided\nsupplemental oxygen.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 124.) A pilot receives this ATC clearance:|'..CLEARED TO THE ABC\n\nVORTAC. HOLD SOUTH ON THE ONE EIGHT ZERO RADIAL..\"|Whatis the\nrecommended procedure to enter the holding pattern?\n",
        "answer": "Teardrop only.\n",
        "choiceone": "Parallel only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is required prior to takeoff if snow is adhering to the wings of an air carrier\nairplane?\n",
        "answer": "Ensure that the snow is removed from the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweep off as much snow as possible and the residue must be polished smooth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 15 knots to the normal V(R) speed as the snow will blow off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the preparation of a required load manifest?\n",
        "answer": "The certificate holder.\n",
        "choiceone": "PIC or the Dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Company official designated by the Administrator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whatis a difference between an SDF and an Localizer type Directional Aid(LDA) facility?\n",
        "answer": "The SDF course width is either 6 degrees or 12 degrees while the LDA course width\nis approximately 5 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "The SDF course has no glide slope guidance while the LDA does.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The SDF has no marker beacons while the LDA has at least an OM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the position of LABER relative to the reference facility?\n",
        "answer": "198 degrees , 8 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "316 degrees, 24.3 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "177 degrees , 10 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the floor of Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum certificate and rating requirements for the pilot in command of a\nturbojet airplane with two engines being operated by a Commuter Air Carrier as defined\nin the Operation of aircraft regulations in the East African region.\n",
        "answer": "Airline transport pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; airplane type\nrating, if required.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airline transport pilot of any category; multiengine class rating; airplane type rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; instrument rating;\nairplane type rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the forecast weather conditions for a destination and alternate airport are\nconsidered marginal for a domestic air operation, what specific action should the pilot\nin command take?\n\n",
        "answer": "List at least one additional alternate airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "List an airport where the forecast weather is not marginal as the alternate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 1 additional hour of fuel based on cruise power settings for the airplane in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 78 and 79.) What is your position relative to the VOR COP southeast\nbound on V86 between the BOZEMAN and LIVINGSTON VORTACs? The No. 1 VOR is\ntuned to 116.1 and the No. 2 VOR is tuned to 112.2.\n",
        "answer": "Past the LVM R-246 and east of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choiceone": "Past the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approaching the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How soon after the conviction for driving wi itoxicated by alcohol or drugs shall it\nbe reported to the CAA, Civil Aviation Security Division?\n",
        "answer": "No later than 60 days after the motor vehicle action.\n",
        "choiceone": "No later than 30 working days after the motor vehicle action.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Required to be reported upon renewal of medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 78.) What is the mi\nfor a flight southeast bound on V86?\n\njum crossing altitude over the BOZEMAN VORTAC\n",
        "answer": "9,300 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "8,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9,700 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the localizer, glide slope, marker beacons, approach lighting, and HIRL,\nwhich ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il instrument\napproach to a DH below 150 feet AGL?\n",
        "answer": "TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A certificated commercial pilot who carries passengers for hire at night or in excess of\n50 NM is required to have at least\n",
        "answer": "an instrument rating in the same category and class of aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "an associated type rating if the airplane is of the multiengine class.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-2?\n",
        "answer": "210 knots and 1.51 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "210 knots and 1.57 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 knots and 1.45 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional flight hours within the preceding 6 calendar months are required to\nmaintain IFR currency in a helicopter?\n",
        "answer": "6 instrument approaches, holding procedures and tracking courses must be\naccomplished.\n",
        "choiceone": "three instrument approaches must also be accomplished.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours of actual or simulated instrument time in the same type helicopter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\nig at 'D' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "3,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) How should a pilot determine when the DME at Price/Carbon\nCounty Airport is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The airborne DME may appear normal, but there will be no code tone.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airborne DME will always indicate \u20180\u00b0 mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne DME will \u2018search,\u2019 but will not \u2018lock on.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting is the value to which the scale of the pressure altimeter is set so the\naltimeter indicates\n",
        "answer": "true altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure altitude at sea level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To comply with ATC instructions for altitude changes of more than 1,000 feet, what rate\nof climb or descent should be used?\n",
        "answer": "As rapidly as practicable to 1,000 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then\nbetween 500 and 1,500 feet per minute until reaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "As rapidly as practicable to 500 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then at\n500 feet per minute until the assigned altitude is reached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet per minute during climb and 500 feet per minute during descents until\nreaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is expected of you as pilot on an IFR flight pla!\nin VFR conditions?\n\nyou are descending or climbing\n",
        "answer": "Execute gentle banks, left and right, at a frequency which permits continuous visual\nscanning of the airspace about you.\n",
        "choiceone": "If on an airway, climb or descend to the right of the centerline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Advise ATC you are in visual conditions and will remain a short distance to the right\nof the centerline while climbing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in area\n6?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition is pressure altitude and density altitude the same value?\n",
        "answer": "At standard temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the altimeter setting is 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When indicated, and pressure altitudes are the same value on the altimeter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS Il provides\n",
        "answer": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maneuvers in all directions to avoid the conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is primarily responsible for maintait\n",
        "answer": "Owner or operator of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The lead mechanic responsible for that aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot in command or operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an operator of an aircraft, which has been involved in an incident, required to\nsubmit a report to the nearest ATS office?\n\n",
        "answer": "Only if requested to do so by the responsible authority\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airborne incident would require that the nearest ATS office be notified\nimmediately?\n\n",
        "answer": "Flight control system malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo compartment door malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin door opened in-flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude may a pilot select upon receiving a VFR-On-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Any appropriate VFR altitude at or above the MEA in VFR weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any altitude at least 1,000 feet above the meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any VFR altitude appropriate for the direction of flight at least 1,000 feet above the\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does a commercial pilot certificate have a specific expiration date?\n",
        "answer": "No, itis issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choiceone": "Yes, it expires at the end of the Regulations month after the month in which it was\nissued.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No, but commercial privileges expire if a flight review is not satisfactorily completed\neach 12 months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum certificate and rating requirements for the pilot in command of a\nturbojet airplane with two engines being operated by a Commuter Air Carrier as defined\nin the Operation of aircraft regulations in the East African region.\n",
        "answer": "Airline transport pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; airplane type\nrating, if required.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airline transport pilot of any category; multiengine class rating; airplane type rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; instrument rating;\nairplane type rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing has:\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).\n",
        "choiceone": "a military aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).\n",
        "choicethree": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate medical attention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When does Air Traffic Control Services have the responsibility to prevent collisions with\nterrain?\n",
        "answer": "When a flight in accordance with IFR is vectored by radar.\n",
        "choiceone": "Always when ATS are provided.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATS never prevent collisions with terrain.\n",
        "choicethree": "ATS only provides prevention when an aircraft is flying IFR in IMC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway-lead-in lighting shall consist:\n",
        "answer": "of groups of at least three white lights, flashing in sequence towards the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "always of a straight row of lights towards the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of a group of at least 5 flashing yellow lights.\n",
        "choicethree": "of an arbitrary amount of green lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aerodrome category for rescue and fire fighting is based on:\n",
        "answer": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane normally using the aerodrome and its\nmaximum fuselage width.\n",
        "choiceone": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane normally using the aerodrome and its\nmaximum fuselage weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "The longest aeroplane maximum width only\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a physical deficiency under the standards specified in any EAC state,\nCAA regulations for their medical certificate.\n",
        "answer": "may not perform flight engineer duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "must surrender the medical certificate to an CAA inspector.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must have a recheck by an CAA approved medical examiner before returning to\nflight crewmember duties.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the use of airborne weather-avoidance radar for the recog!\nof certain weather conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "The radarscope provides no assurance of avoiding instrument weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "The avoidance of hail is assured when flying between and just clear of the most\nintense echoes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The clear area between intense echoes indicates that visual sighting of storms can\nbe maintained when flying between the echoes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a required instrument on a multiengine aircraft becomes inoperative, which document\ndictates whether the flight may continue en route?\n",
        "answer": "An approved Minimum Equipment List for the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Original dispatch release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the purpose of REIL?\n",
        "answer": "Identification of a runway surrounded by a preponderance of other lighting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identification of the touchdown zone to prevent landing short.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Establish visual descent guidance information during an approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of certain portable electronic devices is pro!\noperated under\n\nited on airships that are being\n",
        "answer": "IFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DVFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are considered aircraft class ratings?\n",
        "answer": "Single-engine land, multiengine land, single-engine sea, and multiengine sea.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transport, normal, utility, and acrobatic.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airplane, rotorcraft, glider, and lighter-than-air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "imposed on the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence if that person\ndoes not hold an instrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "That person is limited to private pilot privileges at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can the pilot of an airline find the latest NOTAMs?\n",
        "answer": "Any company dispatch facility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices To Airmen publication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is NOT a required item on the load manifest?\n",
        "answer": "List of passenger names and the weight of each.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft registration number or flight number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identification of crewmembers and their crew position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify REIL.\n",
        "answer": "Synchronized flashing lights laterally at each side of the runway threshold.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights for the first 2,000 feet of runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green lights at the threshold and red lights at far end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which data must be recorded in the aircraft log or other appropriate log by a pilot\nmaking a VOR operational check for IFR operations?\n",
        "answer": "Place of operational check, amount of bearing error, date of check, and signature.\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR name or identification, date of check, amount of bearing error, and signature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Date of check, VOR name or identification, place of operational check, and amount of\nbearing error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 138.) What night operations, if any, are authorized between the\napproach end of the runway and the threshold lights?\n",
        "answer": "Taxi and takeoff operations are permitted, providing the takeoff operations are\ntoward the visible green threshold lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "No aircraft operations are permitted short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only taxi operations are permitted in the area short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the tower and Flight Control Center (FCC) are located on the same airport, which\nfunction is provided by the FCC during those periods when the tower is closed?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Advisory Service.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach control services.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What flight time may a pilot log as second in command?\n",
        "answer": "All flight time when qualified and occupying a crewmember station in an aircraft that\nrequires more than one pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "All flight time while acting as second in command in aircraft configured for more than\none pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only that flight time during which the second in command is the sole manipulator of\nthe controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the lan:\nRWY 4R approach at BOS?\n\nig distance available for the VOR/DME RNAV\n",
        "answer": "8,850 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "7.000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10,005 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in area\n6?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures for keeping copies of the aircraft maintenance log of the aircraft available to\nappropriate personnel shall be set forth in\n",
        "answer": "the certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maintenance procedures handbook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Operations Specifications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-5?\n",
        "answer": "218 knots and 1.27 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "219 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "214 knots and 1.26 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an alternate airport is required, what are the weather minimums that must be\nforecast at the ETA for an alternate airport that has a precision approach procedure?\n\n",
        "answer": "600 foot ceiling and 2 statute miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ceiling 200 feet above the approach minimums and at least 1 statute mile visibility,\nbut not less than the minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ceiling 200 feet above field elevation and visibility 1 statute mile, but not less than\nthe minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-3?\n",
        "answer": "215 knots and 1.44 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "217 knots and 1.50 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "216 knots and 1.40 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition, if any, may a pilot descend below DH or MDA when using the\napproach light system as the primary visual reference for the intended runway?\n",
        "answer": "The approach light system can be used as a visual reference, except that descent\nbelow 100 feet above TDZE requires that the red light bars be visible and identifiable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Under no condition can the approach light system serve as a necessary visual\nreference for descent below DH or MDA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent to the intended runway is authorized as long as any portion of the\napproach light system can be seen.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What restrictions must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment of an airplane operated under the CAA regulations in an east african\nstate?\n",
        "answer": "Cargo may be carried aft of a divider if properly secured by a safety belt or other\ntiedown devices to withstand certain load stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "All cargo must be separated from the passengers by a partition capable of\nwithstanding certain load stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable flame resistant bin and the bin must be\nsecured to the floor structure of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While you are flying at FL250, you hear ATC give an altimeter setting of 28.92\" Hg in\nyour area. At what pressure altitude are you flying?\n",
        "answer": "25,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "24,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "26,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a commerciar flight to be released to an island airport for which an alternate airport\nis not available, a turbojet-powered airplane must have enough fuel to fly to that airport\nand thereafter to fly\n",
        "answer": "at least 2 hours at normal cruising fuel consumption.\n",
        "choiceone": "for 3 hours at normal cruising fuel consumption.\n",
        "choicetwo": "back to the departure airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should be amended\nor cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in excess of:\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choicethree": "60 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an air carrier airplane be DME equipped?\n",
        "answer": "Whenever VOR navigational receivers are required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In Class E airspace for all IFR or VFR on Top operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For flights at or above FL 180.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, then:\n",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed\n",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour to\nprovide for continuation of the flight;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;\n",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person may not act as a crewmember of a civil aircraft if alcoholic beverages have\nbeen consumed by that person within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does a series of arrows painted on the approach end of a runway signify?\n",
        "answer": "That portion of the runway is not suitable for landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "That area is restricted solely to taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "That portion of the runway is the designated touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "req!\nexperience requirements to act as pilot in command of an airplane under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Four instrument approaches in an airplane, or an approved airplane flight simulator\nor training device.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three hours of simulated or actual instrument flight time in a helicopter and two\ninstrument approaches in an airplane or helicopter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three instrument approaches in an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which checks and inspections of flight instruments or instrument systems must be\naccomplished before an aircraft can be flown under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "VOR within 30 days, altimeter systems within 24 calendar months, and transponder\nwithin 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "ELT test within 30 days, altimeter systems within 12 calendar months, and\ntransponder within 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR within 24 calendar months, transponder within 24 calendar months, and\naltimeter system within 12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A coded transponder equipped with altitude reporting capabil\ncontrolled airspace\n\nis required in all\n",
        "answer": "at and above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "at and above 2,500 feet above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What colors are runway holding position signs?\n",
        "answer": "White with a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red with a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow with a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIRMETs are issued on a scheduled basis every\n",
        "answer": "six hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes after the hour only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes until the AIRMET is canceled.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should notification of an aircraft accident be made to the responsible authority if\nthere was substantial damage and no injuries?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an emergency, a pilot-in-command does not deviate from an CAA regulations\nbut n priority by ATC. To whom or under what condition is the pilot required to\nsubmit a written report?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upon request by ATC, submit a written report to the ATC manager.\n",
        "choiceone": "To the manager of the General Aviation District Office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the manager of the facility in control at the time of the deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is DME required for an instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In terminal radar service areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a two-way radio capable of communicating with ATC on appropriate\nfrequencies, which equipments the helicopter required to have to operate within Class\nB airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An appropriate radar beacon transponder.\n",
        "choiceone": "A VOR or TACAN receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DME, a VOR or TACAN receiver, and an appropriate transponder beacon.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'No Entry\u2019 sign identifies\n",
        "answer": "paved area where aircraft entry is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an operational check on the aircraft VOR equipment be accomplished when\nused to operate under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the preceding 10 days or 10 hours of flight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the preceding 30 days or 30 hours of flight time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should pilots state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "When departing from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "When visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When parallel runways are in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first freedom of the air is:\n",
        "answer": "The right to overfly without landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right to land for a technical stop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The opportunity to operate a commercial flight with passengers on board between\ntwo states.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right to board passengers from the state where the aircraft is registered and to\nfly to an other state.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should be amended\nor cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in excess of:\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choicethree": "60 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:\n",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately interrupted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pilot loses visual reference while circling to land from an instrument approach and\nATC radar service is not available, the missed approach action should be to\n",
        "answer": "make a climbing turn toward the landing runway and continue the turn until\nestablished on the missed approach course.\n",
        "choiceone": "execute a climbing turn to parallel the published final approach course and climb to\nthe initial approach altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "climb to the published circling minimums then proceed direct to the final approach\nfix.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum fuel requirements in IFR conditions, i\nlanding is forecast to have a 1,500-foot ceiling and 3 miles vi\nETA? Fuel to fly to the first airport of intended landing,\n\nthe first airport of intended\nity at flight-planned\n",
        "answer": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air carrier must give instruction on such subjects as respiration, hypoxia, and\ndecompression to crewmembers serving on pressurized airplanes operated above\n",
        "answer": "FL 250.\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 180.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 200.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You should advise ATC of minimum fuel status when your fuel supply has reached a\nstate where, upon reaching your destination, you cannot accept any undue delay.\n",
        "answer": "If your remaining usable fuel supply suggests the need for traffic priority to ensure a\nsafe landing, declare an emergency due to low fuel and report fuel remaining in\nminutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "This will ensure your priority handling by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATC will consider this action as if you had declared an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If, while in Class E airspace, a clearance is received to \u2018maintain VFR conditions on top,\u2019\nthe pilot should maintain a VFR cruising altitude based on the direction of the\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a commercial pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft\nfor compensation or hire, if that person\n",
        "answer": "is qualified in accordance with EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nwith the applicable parts that apply to the operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "holds appropriate category, class ratings, and meets the recent flight experience\nrequirements of EAC states' Personnel Licensing regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is qualified in accordance with the EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nhas passed a pilot competency check given by an authorized check pilot.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) is not available when setting up for\nGPS approach, the pilot should\n",
        "answer": "select another type of approach using another type of navigation aid.\n",
        "choiceone": "continue to the MAP and hold until the satellites are recaptured.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proceed as cleared to the IAF and hold until satellite reception is satisfactory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What point at the destination should be used to compute estimated time en route on an\nIFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "The point of first intended landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The final approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The initial approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person whose duties include the handling or carriage of dangerous articles and/or\nmagnetized materials must have satisfactorily completed an established and approved\ntraining program within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating limitations of a \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane?\n",
        "answer": "No person may operate a \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane carrying passengers or\nproperty for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "A pilot of a \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane is required to hold a commercial pilot\ncertificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane is limited to an operating radius of 25 miles from its\nhome base.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial pilot - airplane, if that\nperson does not hold an instrument rating? The carriage of passengers\n",
        "answer": "for hire on cross-country flights in excess of 50 NM or for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for night flights, but not limited for\nday flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is limited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of Flight Data Computer (FDC) NOTAMs?-\n",
        "answer": "To advise of changes in flight data which affect instrument approach procedure\n(IAP), aeronautical charts, and flight restrictions prior to normal publication.\n",
        "choiceone": "To provide the latest information on the status of navigation facilities to all flight\ncontrol center facilities for scheduled broadcasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To issue notices for all airports and navigation facilities in the shortest possible time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How may a pilot satisfy the recent flight experience requirement necessary to act as\npilot in command in IMC in powered aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "six instrument approaches, holding procedures, and intercepting and tracking\ncourses using navigational systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "six instrument approaches and 3 hours under actual or simulated IFR conditions\nwithin the last 6 months; three of the approaches must be in the category of aircraft\ninvolved.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 hours of instrument time under actual or simulated IFR conditions within the last 3\nmonths, including at least six instrument approaches of any kind. Three of the 6\nhours must be in flight in any category aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does a commercial pilot certificate have a specific expiration date?\n",
        "answer": "No, itis issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choiceone": "Yes, it expires at the end of the Regulations month after the month in which it was\nissued.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No, but commercial privileges expire if a flight review is not satisfactorily completed\neach 12 months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot, who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS advisory, is\nexpected to notify ATC and\n",
        "answer": "expeditiously return to the ATC clearance in effect prior to the advisory, after the\nconflict is resolved.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request a new ATC clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 130.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-2?\n",
        "answer": "210 knots and 1.51 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "210 knots and 1.57 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 knots and 1.45 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recommended entry position to an airport traffic pattern is\n",
        "answer": "to enter 45 degrees at the midpoint of the downwind leg at traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "45 degrees to the base leg just below traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to cross directly over the airport at traffic pattern altitude and join the downwind leg.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command must complete a proficiency check or\npreceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lights on a passenger-carrying airplane must be armed or turned on\nduring\n",
        "answer": "taxiing, takeoff, and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "taxiing, takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a temporary replacement is received for an airman's medi\nmaximum time is this document valid?\n\nil certificate, for what\n",
        "answer": "45 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:\n",
        "answer": "Control zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit responsible for promoting efficient organisation of search and rescue service\nin each SAR region is the:\n",
        "answer": "Rescue Co-ordination Centre\n",
        "choiceone": "Alerting Centre\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Information Centre\n",
        "choicethree": "Area Control Centre\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the latest date that a flight engineer in East Africa may perform duties\nif his or her last medical examination was a first-class conducted on August 25, 1999?\n",
        "answer": "August 24, 2000.\n",
        "choiceone": "September 30, 2000.\n",
        "choicetwo": "August 31, 2000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf an unpressurized aircraft is operated between 12,500 feet MSL and 14,000 feet above\nMSL, for a period of 2 hours 20 minutes, how long during that time is the minimum\nflightcrew required to use supplemental oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 50 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours 20 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour 20 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "MEA is an altitude which assures\n",
        "answer": "acceptable navigational signal coverage and meets obstruction clearance\nrequirements.\n",
        "choiceone": "obstacle clearance, accurate navigational signals from more than one VORTAC, and\naccurate DME mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a 1,000-foot obstacle clearance within 2 miles of an airway and assures accurate\nDME mileage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the purpose of REIL?\n",
        "answer": "Identification of a runway surrounded by a preponderance of other lighting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identification of the touchdown zone to prevent landing short.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Establish visual descent guidance information during an approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless a higher speed is required due to turbulence or icing and ATC is notified, the\nmaximum holding speed for a civil turbojet holding at a civil airport at 18,000 feet above\nMSL is:\n",
        "answer": "265 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "250 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft's transponder fails during flight within Class D airspace.\n",
        "answer": "No deviation is required because a transponder is not required in Class D airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot should immediately request clearance to depart the Class D airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot must immediately request priority handling to proceed to destination.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft's operation in flight was substantially affected by an alteration or repair, the\naircraft documents must show that it was test flown and approved for return to service\nby an appropriately-rated pilot prior to being operated\n",
        "answer": "with passengers aboard.\n",
        "choiceone": "under VFR or IFR rules.\n",
        "choicetwo": "for compensation or hire.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does a pilot normally obtain the current altimeter setting during an IFR flight in\nClass E airspace below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "ATC periodically advises the pilot of the proper altimeter setting.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot should contact ARTCC at least every 100 NM and request the altimeter\nsetting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Control Centers along the route broadcast the weather information at 15\nminutes past the hour.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "served in the same capacity on other airplanes of the same group is\n",
        "answer": "transition training.\n",
        "choiceone": "difference training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "upgrade training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for determining that the altimeter system has been checked and\nfound to meet safety requirements for a particular instrument flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Owner.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a commercial airtransport airplane lands at an intermediate airport at 1822Z, what\nis the latest time it may continue a flight without receiving a redispatch authorization?\n",
        "answer": "00222.\n",
        "choiceone": "1922Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1952Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of Flight Data Computer (FDC) NOTAMs?-\n",
        "answer": "To advise of changes in flight data which affect instrument approach procedure\n(IAP), aeronautical charts, and flight restrictions prior to normal publication.\n",
        "choiceone": "To provide the latest information on the status of navigation facilities to all flight\ncontrol center facilities for scheduled broadcasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To issue notices for all airports and navigation facilities in the shortest possible time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum qualifications for a person who occupies the other control seat\nas safety pilot during simulated instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot certificate with appropriate category and class ratings for the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Private pilot with instrument rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Private pilot with appropriate category, class, and instrument ratings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "req!\nexperience requirements to act as pilot in command of an airplane under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Four instrument approaches in an airplane, or an approved airplane flight simulator\nor training device.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three hours of simulated or actual instrument flight time in a helicopter and two\ninstrument approaches in an airplane or helicopter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three instrument approaches in an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a temporary replacement is received for an airman's medi\nmaximum time is this document valid?\n\nil certificate, for what\n",
        "answer": "45 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For helicopters, what jum conditions must exist at the destination airport to avoid\nlisting an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a standard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From the ETA to 1 hour after the ETA, reports and forecasts indicate a ceiling 1,000\nfeet above the airport elevation, or at least 400 feet above the lowest applicable\napproach minima, whichever is higher, and visibility 2 statute miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, reports and forecasts indicate a ceiling of\n1,000 feet above the airport elevation and visibility 2 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft for domestic flight has a delay while on the ground, at an intermediate\nairport. How long before a redispatch release is required?\n",
        "answer": "Not more than 1 hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Not more than 2 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 6 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reach a weight of\n151,500 pounds?|Initial weight: 181,500 Ib[Zero fuel weight: 126,000 Ib\n",
        "answer": "13 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight attendant crewmember is required on aircraft having a passenger seating\nconfiguration, excluding any pilot seat, of\n",
        "answer": "20 or more\n",
        "choiceone": "15 or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19 or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the localizer, glide slope, marker beacons, approach lighting, and HIRL,\nwhich ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il instrument\napproach to a DH below 150 feet AGL?\n",
        "answer": "TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane that is equipped with retractable landing gear,\nflaps, and controllable-pitch propeller, a person is required to\n",
        "answer": "receive and log ground and flight training in such an airplane, and obtain a logbook\nendorsement certifying proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "make at least six takeoffs and landings in such an airplane within the preceding 6\nmonths.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold a multiengine airplane class rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum number of hours that a supplemental airline pilot may fly, as a\ncrewmember, in a commercial operation, in any 30 consecutive days is\n",
        "answer": "100 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "120 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "300 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an IFR off-airways flight over mountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within a horizontal distance of 5 NM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7,500 feet above the highest obstacle within a horizontal distance of 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial operator plans to ferry a large, four-engine, reciprocating-engine-powered\nairplane from one facility to another to repair an inoperative engine. Whi\noperational requirement for the three-engine flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weather conditions at the takeoff and destination airports must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The gross weight at takeoff may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum certificated\ngross weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The computed takeoff distance to reach V(1) must not exceed 70 percent of the\neffective runway length.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the climb-out phase of a flight the pilot-in-command becomes incapacitated.\nThe co-pilot takes over control of the aircraft and decides that he will return for landing.\nWhat action has to be taken after landing?\n",
        "answer": "This is a serious incident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an incident.\n",
        "choiceone": "This is an accident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an accident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation.\nThe operator must inform the Authority by writing an Irregularity Report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an irregularity.\nThe pilot-in-command or the Operator must deposit a report on behalf of the\ninvolved airport Authority within the following 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018selecting an altitude when operating with a VFR-\n\nOn-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum IFR altitude, minimum distance from clouds, and visibility appropriate to\naltitude selected.\n",
        "choiceone": "At least 500 feet above the lowest MEA, or appropriate MOCA, and at least 1,000 feet\nabove the existing meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At least 1,000 feet above the lowest MEA, appropriate MOCA, or existing\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is required to operate an aircraft towing an advertising banner?\n",
        "answer": "A certificate of waiver issued by the CAA.\n",
        "choiceone": "Approval from ATC to operate in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A safety link at each end of the towline which has a breaking strength not less than\n80% of the aircraft's gross weight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RVR is not reported, what meteorologi\nRVR?\n\nil value should you substitute for 2,400\n",
        "answer": "A ground visibility of 600m.\n",
        "choiceone": "A ground visibility of 400m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slant range visibility of 2,400 feet for the final approach segment of the published\napproach procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum\nbelow 10,000 feet MSL?\n\nicated airspeed a turbine-powered\n\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "288 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An approved cockpit voice recorder is required equipment in\n",
        "answer": "multiengine, turbine-powered airplanes having a passenger seating configuration of\n20 or more seats.\n",
        "choiceone": "large turbine-powered airplanes having a maximum passenger capacity of 20 or\nmore seats.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all aircraft operated in commuter air carrier service having a passenger seating\nconfiguration of 20 seats or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are necessary before ATC can authorize a visual approach?\n",
        "answer": "You must have the airport in sight or a preceding aircraft to be followed, and be able\nto proceed to the airport in VFR conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "You must have the preceding aircraft in sight, and be able to remain in VFR weather\nconditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You must have the airport in sight or the preceding aircraft in sight, and be able to\nproceed to, and land in IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum weather conditions that must be forecast to list an airport as an\nalternate when the airport has no approved IAP?\n",
        "answer": "The ceiling and visibility at ETA must allow descent from MEA, approach, and\nlanding, under basic VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ceiling and visibility at ETA, 2,000 feet and 3 miles, respectively.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ceiling and visibility from 2 hours before until 2 hours after ETA, 2,000 feet and 3\nmiles, respectively.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot descend below 100 feet above the touchdown zone elevation during a\nCategory Il ILS instrument approach when only the approach lights are visible?\n",
        "answer": "When the red terminal bar of the approach light systems are in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "After passing the visual descent point (VDP).\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR is 1,600 feet or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pilot-in-command or second-in-command time used to satisfy the aeronautical\nexperience requirements for the flight engineer licence must have been obtained on\n",
        "answer": "a transport category airplane or equivalent military airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "an airplane on which a flight engineer is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at least a three-engine transport, if turbojet-powered.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the upper limit for Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "60,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to carrying passengers at night, the pilot in command must have accom,\nrequired takeoffs and landings in\n",
        "answer": "the same category, class, and type of aircraft (if a type rating is required).\n",
        "choiceone": "any category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same category and class of aircraft to be used.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If weather conditions are such that it is required to designate an alternate airport on\nyour IFR flight plan, you should plan to carry enough fuel to arrive at the first airport of\nintended landing, fly from that airport to the alternate airport, and fly thereafter for\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes at slow cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the forecast weather conditions for a destination and alternate airport are\nconsidered marginal for a domestic air operation, what specific action should the pilot\nin command take?\n\n",
        "answer": "List at least one additional alternate airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "List an airport where the forecast weather is not marginal as the alternate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 1 additional hour of fuel based on cruise power settings for the airplane in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the lan:\nRWY 4R approach at BOS?\n\nig distance available for the VOR/DME RNAV\n",
        "answer": "8,850 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "7.000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10,005 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pilot in command of a civil aircraft must have an instrument rating only when\noperating\n",
        "answer": "under IFR, in weather conditions less than the minimum for VFR flight, and in a Class\nA airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "under IFR in positive control airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in weather conditions less than the minimum prescribed for VFR flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n25,000 pounds? |Initial weight: 179,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 136,500 Ib\n",
        "answer": "8 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) capability, the accuracy of\nthe GPS derived\n",
        "answer": "altitude information should not be relied upon to determine aircraft altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "position is not affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity information should be relied upon to determine aircraft groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The required preflight action relative to weather reports and fuel requirements is\napplicable to\n",
        "answer": "any flight not in the vicinity of an airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "any flight conducted for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR flights only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cockpit voice recorder must be operated\n",
        "answer": "from the start of the before starting engine checklist to completion of final checklist\nupon termination of flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "from the start of the before starting engine checklist to completion of checklist prior\nto engine shutdown.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when starting to taxi for takeoff to the engine shutdown checklist after termination of\nthe flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report should be made to ATC without a specific request when notin radar\ncontact?\n",
        "answer": "When leaving final approach fix inbound on final approach.\n",
        "choiceone": "Entering instrument meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correcting an E.T.A. any time a previous E.T.A. is in error in excess of 2 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an off-airways IFR flight over nonmountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 SM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What restrictions must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment of an airplane operated under the CAA regulations in an east african\nstate?\n",
        "answer": "Cargo may be carried aft of a divider if properly secured by a safety belt or other\ntiedown devices to withstand certain load stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "All cargo must be separated from the passengers by a partition capable of\nwithstanding certain load stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable flame resistant bin and the bin must be\nsecured to the floor structure of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when necessary for takeoff or landing or unless otherwise authorized by the\nCAA, the minimum altitude for IFR flight is\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle over designated mountainous terrain;\nfeet above the highest obstacle over terrain elsewhere.\n\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet over all terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,000 feet over designated mountainous terrain; 2,000 feet over terrain elsewhere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ing altitude is appropriate for VFR on Top on a westbound flight below 18,000\n\n",
        "answer": "Even thousand-foot levels plus 500 feet, but not below MEA.\n",
        "choiceone": "Even thousand-foot levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Odd thousand-foot levels plus 500 feet, but not below MEA.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the vertical\nposition of aircraft shall be expressed in term of:\n",
        "answer": "altitude above mean sea level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude above mean sea level at or above the transition altitude\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight level at or below the transition level\n",
        "choicethree": "flight level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pilot elects to proceed to the selected alternate, the lan\nairport should be the\n\nimums used at that\n",
        "answer": "minimums specified for the approach procedure selected.\n",
        "choiceone": "alternate minimums shown on the approach chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "minimums shown for that airport in a separate listing of 'IFR Alternate Minimums.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, the tow pilot is required to\nhave\n",
        "answer": "a logbook endorsement from an authorized glider instructor certifying receipt of\nground and flight training in gliders, and be proficient with techniques and\nprocedures for safe towing of gliders.\n",
        "choiceone": "at least a private pilot certificate with a category rating for powered aircraft, and\nmade and logged at least three flights as pilot or observer in a glider being towed by\nan airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a logbook record of having made at least three flights as sole manipulator of the\ncontrols of a glider being towed by an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the normal upper limit for Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The required preflight action relative to weather reports and fuel requirements is\napplicable to\n",
        "answer": "any flight not in the vicinity of an airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "any flight conducted for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR flights only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude may a pilot select upon receiving a VFR-On-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Any appropriate VFR altitude at or above the MEA in VFR weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any altitude at least 1,000 feet above the meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any VFR altitude appropriate for the direction of flight at least 1,000 feet above the\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a commercial pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft\nfor compensation or hire, if that person\n",
        "answer": "is qualified in accordance with EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nwith the applicable parts that apply to the operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "holds appropriate category, class ratings, and meets the recent flight experience\nrequirements of EAC states' Personnel Licensing regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is qualified in accordance with the EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nhas passed a pilot competency check given by an authorized check pilot.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A dispatch release for a domestic flight must contain or have attached to it\n",
        "answer": "minimum fuel supply and weather information for the complete flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "trip number and weight and balance data.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weather information for the complete flight and a crew list.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum navigation equipment is required for IFR flight?\n",
        "answer": "Navigation equipment appropriate to the ground facilities to be used.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORILOC receiver, transponder, and DME.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR receiver and, if in ARTS Ill environment, a coded transponder equipped for\naltitude reporting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight training device and/or approved flight\nsimulator, the applicant is\n",
        "answer": "required to have a first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have at least a third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not required to have a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When instructed by ATC to \u2018Hold short of a runway (ILS critical area, etc.),\" the pilot\nshould stop\n",
        "answer": "so that no part of the aircraft extends beyond the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the nose gear on the hold line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "so the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot-in-command of an airplane with more than 200 horsepower, a person is\nrequired to\n",
        "answer": "receive and log ground and flight training from an authorized instructor in such an\nairplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log ground and flight training from a qualified pilot in such an airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "obtain an endorsement from a qualified pilot stating that the person is proficient to\noperate such an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recommended entry position to an airport traffic pattern is\n",
        "answer": "to enter 45 degrees at the midpoint of the downwind leg at traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "45 degrees to the base leg just below traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to cross directly over the airport at traffic pattern altitude and join the downwind leg.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the latest date that a flight engineer in East Africa may perform duties\nif his or her last medical examination was a first-class conducted on August 25, 1999?\n",
        "answer": "August 24, 2000.\n",
        "choiceone": "September 30, 2000.\n",
        "choicetwo": "August 31, 2000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the maximum altitude that Class G airspace will exist?\n(Does not include airspace less than 1,500 feet AGL.)\n",
        "answer": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 138.) What night operations, if any, are authorized between the\napproach end of the runway and the threshold lights?\n",
        "answer": "Taxi and takeoff operations are permitted, providing the takeoff operations are\ntoward the visible green threshold lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "No aircraft operations are permitted short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only taxi operations are permitted in the area short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With regard to flight crewmember duties, which of the following operations are\nconsidered to be in the \u2018critical phase of flight\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Taxi, takeoff, landing, and all other operations conducted below 10,000 feet,\nexcluding cruise flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "Taxi, takeoff, landing, and all other operations conducted below 10,000 feet MSL,\nincluding cruise flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent, approach, landing, and taxi operations, irrespective of altitudes MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an off-airways IFR flight over nonmountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 SM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:\n",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.\n",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.\n",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Member states should introduce specific security measures for the air transport of the\nfollowing groups of potentially disruptive passengers defined below:\n",
        "answer": "Deportees, inadmissible persons and persons in lawful custody\n",
        "choiceone": "Deportees and persons in lawful custody only\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deportees and inadmissible persons only\n",
        "choicethree": "None of the answers is correct\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airplane is overtaking a helicopter. Which aircraft has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airplane; the airplane pilot should alter course to the left to pass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the left.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an eligibility requirement for the issuance of a private piot licence?\n",
        "answer": "Hold a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Be a high school graduate or equivalent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Read, understand, and speak the English language without impediment or accent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The operator of an aircraft that has been involved in ai\nreport to the nearest responsible office\n\ncident is required to submit a\n",
        "answer": "only if requested to do so.\n",
        "choiceone": "within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft is not equipped with an electrical or anticolli\nmay operate that aircraft\n\nin light system, no person\n",
        "answer": "after sunset to sunrise.\n",
        "choiceone": "after dark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour after sunset.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a \u2018low\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Red.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-3?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 59 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours 9 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour 52 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is an \u2018on course\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Green.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which checks and inspections of flight instruments or instrument systems must be\naccomplished before an aircraft can be flown under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "VOR within 30 days, altimeter systems within 24 calendar months, and transponder\nwithin 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "ELT test within 30 days, altimeter systems within 12 calendar months, and\ntransponder within 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR within 24 calendar months, transponder within 24 calendar months, and\naltimeter system within 12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose for the runway hold position markings on the taxiway?\n",
        "answer": "Holds aircraft short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 68.) What is the VASI approach slope angle for RWY 12?\n",
        "answer": "3.0 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "2.8 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating near other aircraft in flight? They are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, when operated so close to another aircraft they can create a collision\nhazard.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation is grounds for revoking any flight engineer certificate or rating?\n",
        "answer": "Alteration of their flight engineer certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating during a physical deficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flying 1,200 hours in 12 calendar months but logging only 1,000 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While in flight a helicopter and an airplane are converging at a 90degrees, and the\nhelicopter is located to the right of the airplane. Which aircraft has the right-of-way, and\nwhy?\n",
        "answer": "The helicopter, because it is to the right of the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The helicopter, because helicopters have the right-of-way over airplanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airplane, because airplanes have the right-of-way over helicopters.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot descend below 100 feet above the touchdown zone elevation during a\nCategory Il ILS instrument approach when only the approach lights are visible?\n",
        "answer": "When the red terminal bar of the approach light systems are in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "After passing the visual descent point (VDP).\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR is 1,600 feet or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movement area of an airport, what does a \"Destination\" sign indicate?\n",
        "answer": "Direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction from taxiway to runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction from ramp to taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-4?\n",
        "answer": "50.7 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "48.3 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "51.3 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an engine's rotation is stopped\nas practicable, to the\n\night, the pilot in command must reportit, as soon\n",
        "answer": "appropriate ground radio station.\n",
        "choiceone": "nearest CAA office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operations manager (or director of operations).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international convention defining rules relative to the responsibilities of\ninternational air carriers for the carriage of passengers, baggage and freight is the:\n",
        "answer": "Warsaw Convention.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tokyo Convention.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hague Convention.\n",
        "choicethree": "Montreal Convention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to that\nlicence due to illness, the authority must be informed:\n",
        "answer": "After 21 days of consecutive \"illness\"\n",
        "choiceone": "as soon as possible if the illness is expected to last more than 21days\n",
        "choicetwo": "after one calendar month of consecutive illness\n",
        "choicethree": "if still not fit to fly when his/her current medical certificate expires\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"PAPI\" shall consist of:\n",
        "answer": "A wing bar of 4 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two wing bars of 4 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two wing bars of 6 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicethree": "A wing bar of 2 sharp transition multi-lamp equally spaced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on vehicles other than those associated with emergency\nor security shall be\n",
        "answer": "Flashing yellow.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed blue.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flashing blue.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot of a turbine-powered airplane should climb as rapidly as practicable after taking\noff to what altitude?\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to carrying passengers at night, the pilot in command must have accom,\nrequired takeoffs and landings in\n",
        "answer": "the same category, class, and type of aircraft (if a type rating is required).\n",
        "choiceone": "any category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same category and class of aircraft to be used.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As each blade flaps up and down, it produces a shift of the center of its mass. When the\nblade flaps up, the CG moves closer to its axis of rotation, giving that blade a tendency\nto\n",
        "answer": "accelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as Coriolis effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "stabilize its rotational velocity, thus compensating for dissymmetry of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as translating tendency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you obtain the pressure altitude on flights below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Set your altimeter to 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choiceone": "Use your computer to change the indicated altitude to pressure altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Contact an FSS and ask for the pressure altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To comply with ATC instructions for altitude changes of more than 1,000 feet, what rate\nof climb or descent should be used?\n",
        "answer": "As rapidly as practicable to 1,000 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then\nbetween 500 and 1,500 feet per minute until reaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "As rapidly as practicable to 500 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then at\n500 feet per minute until the assigned altitude is reached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet per minute during climb and 500 feet per minute during descents until\nreaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What point at the destination should be used to compute estimated time en route on an\nIFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "The point of first intended landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The final approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The initial approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the normal upper limit for Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall a commercial operator retain a record of the load manifest,\nairworthiness release, pilot route certification, flight release, and flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "3 months.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 month.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum IFR altitude you may fly in an unpressurized aircraft without\nproviding passengers with supplemental oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "12,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which facility may be substituted for the middle marker during a Category I ILS\napproach?\n",
        "answer": "Compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORIDME FIX.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surveillance radar.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which passenger announcement(s) must be made after each takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "Passengers should keep seat belts fastened while seated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Keep safety belts fastened while seated and no smoking in the aircraft lavatories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "How to use the passenger oxygen system and that there is a $1,000 fine for\ntampering with a smoke detector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is contained in the Notices to Airman(NOTAM) Publication ?\n",
        "answer": "Current NOTAM(D) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choiceone": "All Current NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Current NOTAM(L) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If there is a required emergency exit located in the flightcrew compartment, the door\nwhich separates the compartment from the passenger cabin must be\n",
        "answer": "latched open during takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "unlocked during takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "locked at all times, except during any emergency declared by the pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ensuring that appropriate aeronautical charts are aboard an aircraft is the responsibility\nof the:\n",
        "answer": "pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight navigator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information concerning parachute jumping sites may be found in the\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Graphic Notices and Supplemental Data.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum\nbelow 10,000 feet MSL?\n\nicated airspeed a turbine-powered\n\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "288 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is required equipment for powered aircraft during VFR night flights?\n",
        "answer": "An electric landing light if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flashlight with red lens if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sensitive altimeter adjustable for barometric pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than in cruise flight, below what altitude are non-safety related cockpit activities\nby flight crewmembers prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "12,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pilot loses visual reference while circling to land from an instrument approach and\nATC radar service is not available, the missed approach action should be to\n",
        "answer": "make a climbing turn toward the landing runway and continue the turn until\nestablished on the missed approach course.\n",
        "choiceone": "execute a climbing turn to parallel the published final approach course and climb to\nthe initial approach altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "climb to the published circling minimums then proceed direct to the final approach\nfix.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum fuel requirements in IFR conditions, i\nlanding is forecast to have a 1,500-foot ceiling and 3 miles vi\nETA? Fuel to fly to the first airport of intended landing,\n\nthe first airport of intended\nity at flight-planned\n",
        "answer": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air carrier must give instruction on such subjects as respiration, hypoxia, and\ndecompression to crewmembers serving on pressurized airplanes operated above\n",
        "answer": "FL 250.\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 180.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 200.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You should advise ATC of minimum fuel status when your fuel supply has reached a\nstate where, upon reaching your destination, you cannot accept any undue delay.\n",
        "answer": "If your remaining usable fuel supply suggests the need for traffic priority to ensure a\nsafe landing, declare an emergency due to low fuel and report fuel remaining in\nminutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "This will ensure your priority handling by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATC will consider this action as if you had declared an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If, while in Class E airspace, a clearance is received to \u2018maintain VFR conditions on top,\u2019\nthe pilot should maintain a VFR cruising altitude based on the direction of the\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a commercial pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft\nfor compensation or hire, if that person\n",
        "answer": "is qualified in accordance with EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nwith the applicable parts that apply to the operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "holds appropriate category, class ratings, and meets the recent flight experience\nrequirements of EAC states' Personnel Licensing regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is qualified in accordance with the EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nhas passed a pilot competency check given by an authorized check pilot.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) is not available when setting up for\nGPS approach, the pilot should\n",
        "answer": "select another type of approach using another type of navigation aid.\n",
        "choiceone": "continue to the MAP and hold until the satellites are recaptured.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proceed as cleared to the IAF and hold until satellite reception is satisfactory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What point at the destination should be used to compute estimated time en route on an\nIFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "The point of first intended landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The final approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The initial approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person whose duties include the handling or carriage of dangerous articles and/or\nmagnetized materials must have satisfactorily completed an established and approved\ntraining program within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating limitations of a \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane?\n",
        "answer": "No person may operate a \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane carrying passengers or\nproperty for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "A pilot of a \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane is required to hold a commercial pilot\ncertificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane is limited to an operating radius of 25 miles from its\nhome base.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial pilot - airplane, if that\nperson does not hold an instrument rating? The carriage of passengers\n",
        "answer": "for hire on cross-country flights in excess of 50 NM or for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for night flights, but not limited for\nday flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is limited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of Flight Data Computer (FDC) NOTAMs?-\n",
        "answer": "To advise of changes in flight data which affect instrument approach procedure\n(IAP), aeronautical charts, and flight restrictions prior to normal publication.\n",
        "choiceone": "To provide the latest information on the status of navigation facilities to all flight\ncontrol center facilities for scheduled broadcasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To issue notices for all airports and navigation facilities in the shortest possible time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How may a pilot satisfy the recent flight experience requirement necessary to act as\npilot in command in IMC in powered aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "six instrument approaches, holding procedures, and intercepting and tracking\ncourses using navigational systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "six instrument approaches and 3 hours under actual or simulated IFR conditions\nwithin the last 6 months; three of the approaches must be in the category of aircraft\ninvolved.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 hours of instrument time under actual or simulated IFR conditions within the last 3\nmonths, including at least six instrument approaches of any kind. Three of the 6\nhours must be in flight in any category aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does a commercial pilot certificate have a specific expiration date?\n",
        "answer": "No, itis issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choiceone": "Yes, it expires at the end of the Regulations month after the month in which it was\nissued.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No, but commercial privileges expire if a flight review is not satisfactorily completed\neach 12 months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot, who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS advisory, is\nexpected to notify ATC and\n",
        "answer": "expeditiously return to the ATC clearance in effect prior to the advisory, after the\nconflict is resolved.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request a new ATC clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 130.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-2?\n",
        "answer": "210 knots and 1.51 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "210 knots and 1.57 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 knots and 1.45 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recommended entry position to an airport traffic pattern is\n",
        "answer": "to enter 45 degrees at the midpoint of the downwind leg at traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "45 degrees to the base leg just below traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to cross directly over the airport at traffic pattern altitude and join the downwind leg.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command must complete a proficiency check or\npreceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lights on a passenger-carrying airplane must be armed or turned on\nduring\n",
        "answer": "taxiing, takeoff, and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "taxiing, takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a temporary replacement is received for an airman's medi\nmaximum time is this document valid?\n\nil certificate, for what\n",
        "answer": "45 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:\n",
        "answer": "Control zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit responsible for promoting efficient organisation of search and rescue service\nin each SAR region is the:\n",
        "answer": "Rescue Co-ordination Centre\n",
        "choiceone": "Alerting Centre\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Information Centre\n",
        "choicethree": "Area Control Centre\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days must the operator of an aircraft involved in an accident file a\nreport ?\n",
        "answer": "10 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the line check requirements for the pilot in command for a domestic air carrier?\n",
        "answer": "The line check is required every 12 calendar months in one of the types of airplanes\nto be flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The line check is required only when the pilot is scheduled to fly into special areas\nand airports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line check is required every 12 months in each type aircraft in which the pilot\nmay fly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is required equipment for powered\nflights?\n\n",
        "answer": "Anticollision light system.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gyroscopic direction indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gyroscopic bank-and-pitch indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-On-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1200 feet AGL). What is the in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operation in Class E airspace during daylight hours for area 1?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ap\nenforcement personnel?\n\nto the carriage of a person in the custody of law\n",
        "answer": "No more than one person considered to be in the maximum risk category may be\ncarried on a flight, and that person must have at least two armed law enforcement\nescorts.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air carrier is not allowed to serve beverages to the person in custody or the law\nenforcement escort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The person in custody must be seated between the escort and the aisle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What instrument flight time may be logged by a second-in-command of an aircraft\nrequiring two pilots?\n",
        "answer": "All of the time the second-in-command is controlling the airplane solely by reference\nto flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "One-half the time the flight is on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One-half the time the airplane is in actual IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sources of aeronautical information, when used collectively, provide the latest\nstatus of airport conditions (e.g., runway closures, runway lighting, snow conditions)?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Facility Directory, Distant (D) NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual, aeronautical charts, and Distant (D) Notice to\nAirmen (NOTAM's).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport Facility Directory, FDC NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If carry-on baggage or cargo is carried in the passenger compartment, it must be\n",
        "answer": "so located that it does not obstruct the access to, or the use of, any required\nemergency or regular exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "stowed ahead of the foremost seated passengers and secured by approved means.\n",
        "choicetwo": "placed in an approved rack, bin, or compartment installed in the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the certificate holder required to list the name and title of each person\nauthorized to exercise operational control for a particular flight?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operations Specifications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Attached to the load manifest.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport has pilot controlled lighting but runways without approach lights. How many\ntimes should you key your microphone to turn on the MIRL at medium intensity?\n",
        "answer": "5 clicks.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 clicks.\n",
        "choicetwo": "None, the MIRL is left on all night.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL under special VFR during\ndaylight hours in area 5?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 mile; (I) 2,000 feet; (J) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What service is provided by departure control to an IFR flight when operating within the\nouter area of Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Separation from all IFR aircraft and participating VFR aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Separation from all aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position and altitude of all traffic within 2 miles of the IFR pilot's line of flight and\naltitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rule applies to the use of the cockpit voice recorder erasure feature?\n",
        "answer": "Any information more than 30 minutes old may be erased.\n",
        "choiceone": "All recorded information may be erased, except for the last 30 minutes prior to\nlanding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All recorded information may be erased, unless the NTSB needs to be notified of an\noccurrence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 130.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation is grounds for revoking any flight engineer certificate or rating?\n",
        "answer": "Alteration of their flight engineer certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating during a physical deficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flying 1,200 hours in 12 calendar months but logging only 1,000 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the upper limit for Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "60,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary purpose of runway end identifier lights(REIL), installed at many airfields,\nto provide\n\n",
        "answer": "rapid identification of the approach end of the runway during reduced visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "a warning of the final 3,000 feet of runway remaining as viewed from the takeoff or\napproach position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rapid identification of the primary runway during reduced visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the forecast weather conditions for a destination and alternate airport are\nconsidered marginal for a domestic air operation, what specific action should the pilot\nin command take?\n\n",
        "answer": "List at least one additional alternate airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "List an airport where the forecast weather is not marginal as the alternate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 1 additional hour of fuel based on cruise power settings for the airplane in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC may assign the MOCA when certain special conditions exist, and when within\n",
        "answer": "22 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a \u2018low\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Red.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall have completed in aeroplanes not less\nthan:\n",
        "answer": "10 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choiceone": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 10 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of instrument time of which not more than 5 hours as pilot in command\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with Civ Aviation Authority the credit for MPA co-pilot time is:\n",
        "answer": "100 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of pilot licence.\n",
        "choiceone": "50 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher grade\nof pilot licence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "100 hours of the flying time required for a higher grade of a pilot licence.\n",
        "choicethree": "75 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of a pilot licence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:\n",
        "answer": "Control zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The obligation of a carrier to transport any person away from the territory of a\nContracting State shall terminate from the moment such person has been definitely\nadmitted in other Contracting State of destination.\n",
        "answer": "The stated above is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "The operator has no obligation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The obligation is for the Contracting State of the operator.\n",
        "choicethree": "The obligation of the operator terminates as soon as the person leaves the\naeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During flight a fire which was extinguished burned the insulation from a transceiver\nwire. What action is required by regulations?\n",
        "answer": "An immediate notification by the operator of the aircraft to the nearest CAA field\noffice.\n",
        "choiceone": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A report must be filed with the avionics inspector at the nearest CAA Flight\nStandards Office\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot, who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS advisory, is\nexpected to notify ATC and\n",
        "answer": "expeditiously return to the ATC clearance in effect prior to the advisory, after the\nconflict is resolved.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request a new ATC clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days must the operator of an aircraft involved in an accident file a\nreport ?\n",
        "answer": "10 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC may assign the MOCA when certain special conditions exist, and when within\n",
        "answer": "22 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-2?\n",
        "answer": "210 knots and 1.51 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "210 knots and 1.57 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 knots and 1.45 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an emergency, a pilot-in-command does not deviate from an CAA regulations\nbut n priority by ATC. To whom or under what condition is the pilot required to\nsubmit a written report?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upon request by ATC, submit a written report to the ATC manager.\n",
        "choiceone": "To the manager of the General Aviation District Office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the manager of the facility in control at the time of the deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition is guaranteed for all of the following altitude limits: MAA, MCA, MRA,\nMOCA, and MEA? (Non-mountainous area.)\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot obstacle clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Adequate navigation signals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Adequate communications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have just landed and the tower tells you to call ground control when clear of the\nrunway. You are considered clear of the runway when\n",
        "answer": "all parts of the aircraft have crossed the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aft end of the aircraft is even with the taxiway location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should pilots state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "When departing from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "When visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When parallel runways are in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'No Entry\u2019 sign identifies\n",
        "answer": "paved area where aircraft entry is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is primarily responsible for maintait\n",
        "answer": "Owner or operator of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The lead mechanic responsible for that aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot in command or operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When approaching taxiway holding lines from the side with the continuous lines, the\npilot\n",
        "answer": "should not cross the lines without ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "may continue taxiing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "should continue taxiing until all parts of the aircraft have crossed the lines.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the yellow demarcation bar marking?\n",
        "answer": "Delineates runway with a displaced threshold from a blast pad, stopway or taxiway\nthat precedes the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Delineates entrance to runway from a taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Delineates beginning of runway available for landing when pavement is aligned with\nrunway on approach side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before beginning any flight under IFR, the pilot in command must become fami\nall available information concerning that flight. In addition, the pilot must\n\n",
        "answer": "be familiar with the runway lengths at airports of intended use, and the alternatives\navailable if the flight cannot be completed.\n",
        "choiceone": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and become familiar with the instrument\napproaches to that airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and confirm adequate takeoff and landing\nperformance at the destination airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of operations over an area designated as a mountainous area where no\nother um altitude is prescribed, no person may operate an aircraft under IFR\nbelow an altitude of\n\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are VFR-On-Top operations prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "In Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "During off-airways direct flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When flying through Class B airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a student pilot\n\n",
        "answer": "17 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "18 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airborne incident would require that the nearest ATS office be notified\nimmediately?\n\n",
        "answer": "Flight control system malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo compartment door malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin door opened in-flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is contained in the Notices to Airman(NOTAM) Publication ?\n",
        "answer": "Current NOTAM(D) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choiceone": "All Current NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Current NOTAM(L) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a two-way radio capable of communicating with ATC on appropriate\nfrequencies, which equipments the helicopter required to have to operate within Class\nB airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An appropriate radar beacon transponder.\n",
        "choiceone": "A VOR or TACAN receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DME, a VOR or TACAN receiver, and an appropriate transponder beacon.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an operator of an aircraft, which has been involved in an incident, required to\nsubmit a report to the nearest ATS office?\n\n",
        "answer": "Only if requested to do so by the responsible authority\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the vertical\nposition of aircraft shall be expressed in term of:\n",
        "answer": "altitude above mean sea level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude above mean sea level at or above the transition altitude\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight level at or below the transition level\n",
        "choicethree": "flight level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Low Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "centimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "metric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "decimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information concerning parachute jumping sites may be found in the\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Graphic Notices and Supplemental Data.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-1?\n",
        "answer": "19,400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 78 and 79.) What is your position relative to the VOR COP southeast\nbound on V86 between the BOZEMAN and LIVINGSTON VORTACs? The No. 1 VOR is\ntuned to 116.1 and the No. 2 VOR is tuned to 112.2.\n",
        "answer": "Past the LVM R-246 and east of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choiceone": "Past the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approaching the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sources of aeronautical information, when used collectively, provide the latest\nstatus of airport conditions (e.g., runway closures, runway lighting, snow conditions)?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Facility Directory, Distant (D) NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual, aeronautical charts, and Distant (D) Notice to\nAirmen (NOTAM's).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport Facility Directory, FDC NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A standard airworthiness certificate remains in effect as long as the aircraft receives\n",
        "answer": "required maintenance and inspections.\n",
        "choiceone": "an annual inspection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an annual inspection and a 100-hour inspection prior to their expiration dates.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Full scale deflection of a CDI occurs when the course deviation bar or needle\n",
        "answer": "deflects from the center of the scale to either far side of the scale.\n",
        "choiceone": "deflects from left side of the scale to right side of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "deflects from half scale left to half scale right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What recent experience is required to be eligible for the practical test for the original\nissue of a Category Il authorization?\n",
        "answer": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches, three of which may be flown to\nthe Category | DH.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches flown manually to the Category |\nDH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the previous 12 calendar months, six ILS approaches flown by use of an\napproach coupler to the Category | or Category Il DH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in\nClass G airspace during daylight hours for area 2?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the recommended procedure for transitioning from VFR to IFR on a composite\nflight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Prior to transitioning to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center close the VFR portion,\nand request ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upon reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center\nand cancel your VFR flight plan, then contact ACC and request an IFR clearance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prior to reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact ACC, request your\nIFR clearance, and instruct them to cancel the VFR flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized when carrying passengers for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not authorized when visibilities are less than 3 SM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 71A.) What is your position relative to the Flosi intersection\nNorthbound on V213?\n",
        "answer": "West of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "East of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "West of V213 and past the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As each blade flaps up and down, it produces a shift of the center of its mass. When the\nblade flaps up, the CG moves closer to its axis of rotation, giving that blade a tendency\nto\n",
        "answer": "accelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as Coriolis effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "stabilize its rotational velocity, thus compensating for dissymmetry of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as translating tendency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) is not available when setting up for\nGPS approach, the pilot should\n",
        "answer": "select another type of approach using another type of navigation aid.\n",
        "choiceone": "continue to the MAP and hold until the satellites are recaptured.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proceed as cleared to the IAF and hold until satellite reception is satisfactory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rule applies to the use of the cockpit voice recorder erasure feature?\n",
        "answer": "Any information more than 30 minutes old may be erased.\n",
        "choiceone": "All recorded information may be erased, except for the last 30 minutes prior to\nlanding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All recorded information may be erased, unless the NTSB needs to be notified of an\noccurrence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting is the value to which the scale of the pressure altimeter is set so the\naltimeter indicates\n",
        "answer": "true altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure altitude at sea level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which time period must a required voice recorder of a passenger-carrying\nairplane be continuously operated?\n",
        "answer": "From the use of the checklist before the flight to completion of the final check at the\nend of the flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "From the beginning of taxi to the end of the landing roll.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From engine start at departure airport to engine shutdown at landing airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of an accident or occurrence requiring immediate notification of the CAA,\nthe operator shall keep flight recorder and cockpit voice recorder data for at least\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "90 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight simulator and an aircraft, the applicant\nis\n",
        "answer": "required to have a current first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have a least a current third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not required to hold a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For flight under IFR, a person serving as second in command of an aircraft under the\nCAA regulations in an East african State person must have accomplished within the last\n6 months, the recent instrument requirements of\n",
        "answer": "holding procedures, using the navigation systems for intercepting and tracking\ncourses, and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "choiceone": "using the navigation systems for interception and tracking of courses, 6 instrument\nlow approaches and holding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "using the navigation systems to intercept and track 3 inbound/3 outbound courses,\n6 holding patterns and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence aeroplane shall have completed, in\naeroplanes not less than:\n",
        "answer": "20 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "choiceone": "10 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When not flying over high terrain or mountainous areas and where no minimum flight\naltitude has been established, flights in accordance with IFR shall be flown at a level\nwhich is at least:\n",
        "answer": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft is subjected to unlawful interference, the pilot-in-command shall\nindicate the situation by setting the transponder to Mode A, Code\n",
        "answer": "7500.\n",
        "choiceone": "7700.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7600.\n",
        "choicethree": "7000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A complete position report transmitted by ra\nelements of information in the order listed.\n\ntelephony shall contain the following\n",
        "answer": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next position\nand time over, 6) ensuing significant point.\n",
        "choiceone": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) flight level or altitude, 4) time, 5) next position\nand time over, 6) ensuing significant point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) true air speed, 5) flight level or altitude,\n6) next position and time over.\n",
        "choicethree": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next position,\n6) time over.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the initiation of an accident investigation?\n",
        "answer": "The Authority of the State in which the accident took place.\n",
        "choiceone": "The Operators of the same aircraft type.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft manufacturer.\n",
        "choicethree": "The State of design and manufacturer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 56.) You have requested taxi instructions for takeoff using Runway 16.\nThe controller issues the following taxi instructions: \"5H-ABC, Taxi to runway 16.\u201d\nWhere are you required to stop in order to be in compliance with the controller's\ninstructions\n",
        "answer": "5 (Five).\n",
        "choiceone": "6 (Six).\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 (Nine).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may ATC request a detailed report on an emergency even though a rule has not\nbeen violated?\n",
        "answer": "When priority has been given.\n",
        "choiceone": "Anytime an emergency occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the emergency occurs in controlled airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oxygen requirement for an unpressurized aircraft at 15,000 feet under the\nOperation of Aircraft regulations in East Africa?\n",
        "answer": "Crew must start using oxygen at 12,000 feet and passengers at 14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "All occupants must use oxygen for the entire time at this altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew must use oxygen for the entire time above 14,000 feet and passengers must be\nprovided supplemental oxygen only above 15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airplane is overtaking a helicopter. Which aircraft has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airplane; the airplane pilot should alter course to the left to pass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the left.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an eligibility requirement for the issuance of a private piot licence?\n",
        "answer": "Hold a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Be a high school graduate or equivalent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Read, understand, and speak the English language without impediment or accent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sources of aeronautical information, when used collectively, provide the latest\nstatus of airport conditions (e.g., runway closures, runway lighting, snow conditions)?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Facility Directory, Distant (D) NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual, aeronautical charts, and Distant (D) Notice to\nAirmen (NOTAM's).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport Facility Directory, FDC NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in area\n6?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If, while in Class E airspace, a clearance is received to \u2018maintain VFR conditions on top,\u2019\nthe pilot should maintain a VFR cruising altitude based on the direction of the\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person may not act as a crewmember of a civil aircraft if alcoholic beverages have\nbeen consumed by that person within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-2?\n",
        "answer": "17,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify REIL.\n",
        "answer": "Synchronized flashing lights laterally at each side of the runway threshold.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights for the first 2,000 feet of runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green lights at the threshold and red lights at far end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:\n",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "A NOTAM RAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.\n",
        "choicethree": "An Advisory NOTAM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of runway lighting con:\neach side of the runway threshold?\n\nsts of a pair of synchronized flashing lights, one on\n",
        "answer": "REIL.\n",
        "choiceone": "RAIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "HIRL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Haze can give the illusion that the aircraft is\n",
        "answer": "farther from the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choiceone": "closer to the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same distance from the runway as when there is no restriction to visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in Class G airspace in VFR conditions\nduring daylight hours in area 4?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an alternate airport is required, what are the weather minimums that must be\nforecast at the ETA for an alternate airport that has a precision approach procedure?\n\n",
        "answer": "600 foot ceiling and 2 statute miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ceiling 200 feet above the approach minimums and at least 1 statute mile visibility,\nbut not less than the minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ceiling 200 feet above field elevation and visibility 1 statute mile, but not less than\nthe minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum flight time in 24 consecutive hours that an air operator may schedule a\npilot in a two-pilot crew without a rest period is\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 80.) What is the TDZE for landing on RWY 27R?-\n",
        "answer": "3,514 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,649 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,450 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, the tow pilot is required to\nhave\n",
        "answer": "a logbook endorsement from an authorized glider instructor certifying receipt of\nground and flight training in gliders, and be proficient with techniques and\nprocedures for safe towing of gliders.\n",
        "choiceone": "at least a private pilot certificate with a category rating for powered aircraft, and\nmade and logged at least three flights as pilot or observer in a glider being towed by\nan airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a logbook record of having made at least three flights as sole manipulator of the\ncontrols of a glider being towed by an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What restrictions must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment of an airplane operated under the CAA regulations in an east african\nstate?\n",
        "answer": "Cargo may be carried aft of a divider if properly secured by a safety belt or other\ntiedown devices to withstand certain load stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "All cargo must be separated from the passengers by a partition capable of\nwithstanding certain load stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable flame resistant bin and the bin must be\nsecured to the floor structure of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Duty and rest period rules for domestic air operations require that a flight crewmember\n",
        "answer": "not be assigned to any duty with the airline during any required rest period.\n",
        "choiceone": "not be on duty aloft for more than 100 hours in any 30-day period.\n",
        "choicetwo": "be relieved of all duty for at least 24 hours during any 7 consecutive days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before beginning any flight under IFR, the pilot in command must become fami\nall available information concerning that flight. In addition, the pilot must\n\n",
        "answer": "be familiar with the runway lengths at airports of intended use, weather reports, fuel\nrequirements, the alternatives available, if the flight cannot be completed.\n",
        "choiceone": "be familiar with all instrument approaches at the destination airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and confirm adequate takeoff and landing\nperformance at the destination airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the floor of Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before each takeoff, the pilot in command of an aircraft carrying passengers shall\nensure that all passengers have been orally briefed on the\n\n",
        "answer": "use of safety belts, location and operation of fire extinguishers, and smoking.\n",
        "choiceone": "location of normal and emergency exits, oxygen masks, and life preservers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use of seatbelts, smoking, and location and use of survival equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which speed variation should you notify ATC?\n",
        "answer": "When the average true airspeed changes 5 percent or 10 knots, whichever is greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the ground speed changes more than 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time the ground speed changes 10 MPH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight training device and/or approved flight\nsimulator, the applicant is\n",
        "answer": "required to have a first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have at least a third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not required to have a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018selecting an altitude when operating with a VFR-\n\nOn-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum IFR altitude, minimum distance from clouds, and visibility appropriate to\naltitude selected.\n",
        "choiceone": "At least 500 feet above the lowest MEA, or appropriate MOCA, and at least 1,000 feet\nabove the existing meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At least 1,000 feet above the lowest MEA, appropriate MOCA, or existing\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of certain portable electronic devices is pro!\noperated under\n\nited on aircraft that are being\n",
        "answer": "IFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DVFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-1?\n",
        "answer": "217 knots and 1.81 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "221 knots and 1.83 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "223 knots and 2.01 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an off-airways IFR flight over nonmountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 SM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What is the approximate fuel consumed when holding\nunder Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "1,440 pounds.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,870 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,230 pounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Required flight crewmembers\u2019 safety belts must be fastened\n",
        "answer": "while the crewmembers are at their stations.\n",
        "choiceone": "only during takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only during takeoff and landing when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\nfor a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a commercial airtransport airplane lands at an intermediate airport at 1822Z, what\nis the latest time it may continue a flight without receiving a redispatch authorization?\n",
        "answer": "00222.\n",
        "choiceone": "1922Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1952Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is required prior to takeoff if snow is adhering to the wings of an air carrier\nairplane?\n",
        "answer": "Ensure that the snow is removed from the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweep off as much snow as possible and the residue must be polished smooth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 15 knots to the normal V(R) speed as the snow will blow off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, to minimize DME slant range error, how far from the facility should\nyou be to consider the reading as accurate?\n",
        "answer": "One or more miles for each 1,000 feet of altitude above the facility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two miles or more for each 1,000 feet of altitude above the facility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No specific distance is specified since the reception is line-of-sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall have completed in aeroplanes not less\nthan:\n",
        "answer": "10 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choiceone": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 10 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of instrument time of which not more than 5 hours as pilot in command\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the initiation of an accident investigation?\n",
        "answer": "The Authority of the State in which the accident took place.\n",
        "choiceone": "The Operators of the same aircraft type.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft manufacturer.\n",
        "choicethree": "The State of design and manufacturer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days must the operator of an aircraft involved in an accident file a\nreport ?\n",
        "answer": "10 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the line check requirements for the pilot in command for a domestic air carrier?\n",
        "answer": "The line check is required every 12 calendar months in one of the types of airplanes\nto be flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The line check is required only when the pilot is scheduled to fly into special areas\nand airports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line check is required every 12 months in each type aircraft in which the pilot\nmay fly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is required equipment for powered\nflights?\n\n",
        "answer": "Anticollision light system.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gyroscopic direction indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gyroscopic bank-and-pitch indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-On-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1200 feet AGL). What is the in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operation in Class E airspace during daylight hours for area 1?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ap\nenforcement personnel?\n\nto the carriage of a person in the custody of law\n",
        "answer": "No more than one person considered to be in the maximum risk category may be\ncarried on a flight, and that person must have at least two armed law enforcement\nescorts.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air carrier is not allowed to serve beverages to the person in custody or the law\nenforcement escort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The person in custody must be seated between the escort and the aisle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What instrument flight time may be logged by a second-in-command of an aircraft\nrequiring two pilots?\n",
        "answer": "All of the time the second-in-command is controlling the airplane solely by reference\nto flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "One-half the time the flight is on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One-half the time the airplane is in actual IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sources of aeronautical information, when used collectively, provide the latest\nstatus of airport conditions (e.g., runway closures, runway lighting, snow conditions)?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Facility Directory, Distant (D) NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual, aeronautical charts, and Distant (D) Notice to\nAirmen (NOTAM's).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport Facility Directory, FDC NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If carry-on baggage or cargo is carried in the passenger compartment, it must be\n",
        "answer": "so located that it does not obstruct the access to, or the use of, any required\nemergency or regular exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "stowed ahead of the foremost seated passengers and secured by approved means.\n",
        "choicetwo": "placed in an approved rack, bin, or compartment installed in the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the certificate holder required to list the name and title of each person\nauthorized to exercise operational control for a particular flight?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operations Specifications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Attached to the load manifest.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport has pilot controlled lighting but runways without approach lights. How many\ntimes should you key your microphone to turn on the MIRL at medium intensity?\n",
        "answer": "5 clicks.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 clicks.\n",
        "choicetwo": "None, the MIRL is left on all night.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL under special VFR during\ndaylight hours in area 5?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 mile; (I) 2,000 feet; (J) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What service is provided by departure control to an IFR flight when operating within the\nouter area of Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Separation from all IFR aircraft and participating VFR aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Separation from all aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position and altitude of all traffic within 2 miles of the IFR pilot's line of flight and\naltitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rule applies to the use of the cockpit voice recorder erasure feature?\n",
        "answer": "Any information more than 30 minutes old may be erased.\n",
        "choiceone": "All recorded information may be erased, except for the last 30 minutes prior to\nlanding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All recorded information may be erased, unless the NTSB needs to be notified of an\noccurrence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 130.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation is grounds for revoking any flight engineer certificate or rating?\n",
        "answer": "Alteration of their flight engineer certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating during a physical deficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flying 1,200 hours in 12 calendar months but logging only 1,000 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the upper limit for Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "60,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary purpose of runway end identifier lights(REIL), installed at many airfields,\nto provide\n\n",
        "answer": "rapid identification of the approach end of the runway during reduced visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "a warning of the final 3,000 feet of runway remaining as viewed from the takeoff or\napproach position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rapid identification of the primary runway during reduced visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the forecast weather conditions for a destination and alternate airport are\nconsidered marginal for a domestic air operation, what specific action should the pilot\nin command take?\n\n",
        "answer": "List at least one additional alternate airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "List an airport where the forecast weather is not marginal as the alternate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 1 additional hour of fuel based on cruise power settings for the airplane in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC may assign the MOCA when certain special conditions exist, and when within\n",
        "answer": "22 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a \u2018low\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Red.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall have completed in aeroplanes not less\nthan:\n",
        "answer": "10 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choiceone": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 10 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of instrument time of which not more than 5 hours as pilot in command\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with Civ Aviation Authority the credit for MPA co-pilot time is:\n",
        "answer": "100 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of pilot licence.\n",
        "choiceone": "50 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher grade\nof pilot licence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "100 hours of the flying time required for a higher grade of a pilot licence.\n",
        "choicethree": "75 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of a pilot licence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:\n",
        "answer": "Control zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The obligation of a carrier to transport any person away from the territory of a\nContracting State shall terminate from the moment such person has been definitely\nadmitted in other Contracting State of destination.\n",
        "answer": "The stated above is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "The operator has no obligation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The obligation is for the Contracting State of the operator.\n",
        "choicethree": "The obligation of the operator terminates as soon as the person leaves the\naeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To meet the requirements for flight under IFR, an aircraft must be equipped with cer\noperable instruments and equipment. One of those required is\n",
        "answer": "a clock with sweep-second pointer or digital presentation.\n",
        "choiceone": "a radar altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a transponder with altitude reporting capability.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-1?\n",
        "answer": "19,400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the recommended procedure for transitioning from VFR to IFR on a composite\nflight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Prior to transitioning to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center close the VFR portion,\nand request ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upon reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center\nand cancel your VFR flight plan, then contact ACC and request an IFR clearance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prior to reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact ACC, request your\nIFR clearance, and instruct them to cancel the VFR flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before beginning any flight under IFR, the pilot in command must become fami\nall available information concerning that flight. In addition, the pilot must\n\n",
        "answer": "be familiar with the runway lengths at airports of intended use, and the alternatives\navailable if the flight cannot be completed.\n",
        "choiceone": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and become familiar with the instrument\napproaches to that airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and confirm adequate takeoff and landing\nperformance at the destination airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While in flight a helicopter and an airplane are converging at a 90degrees, and the\nhelicopter is located to the right of the airplane. Which aircraft has the right-of-way, and\nwhy?\n",
        "answer": "The helicopter, because it is to the right of the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The helicopter, because helicopters have the right-of-way over airplanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airplane, because airplanes have the right-of-way over helicopters.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which document specifically authorizes a person to operate an\ngeographic area?\n\n",
        "answer": "Operations Specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating Certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch Release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot file a composite flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Any time a portion of the flight will be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "When requested or advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time a landing is planned at an intermediate airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an operator of an aircraft, which has been involved in an incident, required to\nsubmit a report to the nearest ATS office?\n\n",
        "answer": "Only if requested to do so by the responsible authority\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "req!\nexperience requirements to act as pilot in command of an airplane under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Four instrument approaches in an airplane, or an approved airplane flight simulator\nor training device.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three hours of simulated or actual instrument flight time in a helicopter and two\ninstrument approaches in an airplane or helicopter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three instrument approaches in an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of operations over an area designated as a mountainous area where no\nother um altitude is prescribed, no person may operate an aircraft under IFR\nbelow an altitude of\n\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an operational check on the aircraft VOR equipment be accomplished when\nused to operate under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the preceding 10 days or 10 hours of flight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the preceding 30 days or 30 hours of flight time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which manoeuvre will be executed by an intercepting aircraft if the pilot of this aircraft\nwants to communicate to the intercepted aircraft \"YOU MAY PROCEED\"?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt break-away manoeuvre from the intercepted aircraft consisting of a\nclimbing turn of 90 degrees or more without crossing the line of flight of the\nintercepted aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rocking aircraft twice in front of the intercepting aircraft, after acknowledgement by\nintercepted aircraft a slow level turn (normally to the left).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Circling the intercepted aircraft in a counter-clockwise pattern for aeroplanes, in a\nclockwise pattern for helicopter.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rocking aircraft and flashing navigational lights at regular intervals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time:\n",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until it stops at\nthe end of the flight (block time).\n",
        "choicetwo": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and temperature on\nthat day.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before takeoff, the pilot in command of an aircraft carrying passengers shall ensure that\nall passengers have been orally briefed on the normal and emergency use of oxygen\n",
        "answer": "if the flight involves operations above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "regardless of the altitude at which the flight will operate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the flight involves operations at or above 12,000 feet MSL for more than 30\nminutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL under special VFR during\ndaylight hours in area 5?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 mile; (I) 2,000 feet; (J) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What is the approximate fuel consumed when holding\nunder Operating Conditions 0-1?\n",
        "answer": "1,625 pounds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,950 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,440 pounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional flight hours within the preceding 6 calendar months are required to\nmaintain IFR currency in a helicopter?\n",
        "answer": "6 instrument approaches, holding procedures and tracking courses must be\naccomplished.\n",
        "choiceone": "three instrument approaches must also be accomplished.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours of actual or simulated instrument time in the same type helicopter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During flight a fire which was extinguished burned the insulation from a transceiver\nwire. What action is required by regulations?\n",
        "answer": "An immediate notification by the operator of the aircraft to the nearest CAA field\noffice.\n",
        "choiceone": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A report must be filed with the avionics inspector at the nearest CAA Flight\nStandards Office\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A series of continuous red lights in the runway centerline lighting indicates that\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "one-half of the runway remains.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airplanes are required to be equipped with a ground proximity warning glide\nslope deviation alerting system?\n",
        "answer": "All turbine powered airplanes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Passenger-carrying turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Large turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial\nperson does not hold an instrument pilot rating?\n\nplane pilot if that\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 nautical miles (NM).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for\nnight flights, but not limited for day flights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The carriage of passengers for hire by a commercial pilot is\n",
        "answer": "not authorized in a \u2018limited\u2019 category aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized in a \u2018utility\u2019 category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized in \u2018restricted\u2019 category aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "MOAs are established to\n",
        "answer": "separate certain military activities from IFR traffic.\n",
        "choiceone": "prohibit all civil aircraft because of hazardous or secret activities.\n",
        "choicetwo": "restrict civil aircraft during periods of high-density training activities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is NOT a required item on the load manifest?\n",
        "answer": "List of passenger names and the weight of each.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft registration number or flight number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identification of crewmembers and their crew position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures for keeping copies of the aircraft maintenance log of the aircraft available to\nappropriate personnel shall be set forth in\n",
        "answer": "the certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maintenance procedures handbook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Operations Specifications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A coded transponder equipped with altitude reporting capabil\ncontrolled airspace\n\nis required in all\n",
        "answer": "at and above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "at and above 2,500 feet above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized when carrying passengers for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not authorized when visibilities are less than 3 SM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n16,000 pounds?IInitial weight: 175,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 138,000 Ib\n",
        "answer": "9 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pilot loses visual reference while circling to land from an instrument approach and\nATC radar service is not available, the missed approach action should be to\n",
        "answer": "make a climbing turn toward the landing runway and continue the turn until\nestablished on the missed approach course.\n",
        "choiceone": "execute a climbing turn to parallel the published final approach course and climb to\nthe initial approach altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "climb to the published circling minimums then proceed direct to the final approach\nfix.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data kept, in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in terminating the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of runway lighting con:\neach side of the runway threshold?\n\nsts of a pair of synchronized flashing lights, one on\n",
        "answer": "REIL.\n",
        "choiceone": "RAIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "HIRL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude and route should be used if the pilot is flying in IFR weather conditions\nand has two-way radio communications failure?\n",
        "answer": "Continue on the route specified in the clearance and fly the highest of the following:\nthe last assigned altitude, altitude ATC has informed the pilot to expect, or to the\nmaximum Elevation Altitude( MEA)\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend to MEA and, if clear of clouds, proceed to the nearest appropriate airport. If\nnot clear of clouds, maintain the highest of the MEAs along the clearance route.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly the most direct route to the destination, maintaining the last assigned altitude or\nMEA, whichever is higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is required equipment for powered\nflights?\n\n",
        "answer": "Anticollision light system.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gyroscopic direction indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gyroscopic bank-and-pitch indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which restriction must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment?\n",
        "answer": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable bin and secured to a passenger seat or the\nfloor structure of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis packaged or covered to avoid possible injury to occupants.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cargo carried in passenger seats must be forward of all passengers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 78.) What is the mi\nfor a flight southeast bound on V86?\n\njum crossing altitude over the BOZEMAN VORTAC\n",
        "answer": "9,300 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "8,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9,700 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What\nG airspace?\n\nplane to operate under VFR in Class\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot ceiling; 2-miles flight visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile flight visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following elements\n",
        "answer": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and pre-flight\ninformation bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries\n",
        "choiceone": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP, NOTAM, AIC and checklist\nsummaries\n",
        "choicetwo": "AIP, supplements to AIP; NOTAM and PIB; AIC and checklist summaries\n",
        "choicethree": "AIP including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM, AIC; AIRAC\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless a higher speed is required due to turbulence or icing and ATC is notified, the\nmaximum holding speed for a civil turbojet holding at a civil airport at 18,000 feet above\nMSL is:\n",
        "answer": "265 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "250 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a requirement governing the carriage of carry-on baggage?\n",
        "answer": "All carry-on baggage must be restrained so that its movement is prevented during air\nturbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Carry-on baggage must be stowed under the seat in front of the owner.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pieces of carry-on baggage weighing more than 10 pounds must be carried in an\napproved rack or bin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data kept, in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in terminating the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is DME required under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet above MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In positive control airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to carrying passengers at night, the pilot in command must have accom,\nrequired takeoffs and landings in\n",
        "answer": "the same category, class, and type of aircraft (if a type rating is required).\n",
        "choiceone": "any category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same category and class of aircraft to be used.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of runway lighting con:\neach side of the runway threshold?\n\nsts of a pair of synchronized flashing lights, one on\n",
        "answer": "REIL.\n",
        "choiceone": "RAIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "HIRL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RVR is not reported, what meteorologi\nRVR?\n\nil value should you substitute for 2,400\n",
        "answer": "A ground visibility of 600m.\n",
        "choiceone": "A ground visibility of 400m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slant range visibility of 2,400 feet for the final approach segment of the published\napproach procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whatis the maximum\nairspace?\n\nthe airspace underlying Class B\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon intercepting the assigned radial, the controller advises you that you are on the\nairway and to \"RESUME OWN NAVIGATION.\u2019 This phrase means that\n",
        "answer": "you are to assume responsibility for your own navigation.\n",
        "choiceone": "you are still in radar contact, but must make position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "radar services are terminated and you will be responsible for position reports.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air operator may schedule a pilot to fly in an airplane, having two pilots and one\nadditional flight crewmember, for no more than\n",
        "answer": "12 hours during any 24 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ensuring that appropriate aeronautical charts are aboard an aircraft is the responsibility\nof the:\n",
        "answer": "pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight navigator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acommercial pilot in command in EAC is required to hold a type rating?\n",
        "answer": "When operating any aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating an aircraft having a gross weight of more than 12,500 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When operating a multiengine aircraft having a gross weight of more than 6,000\npounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While you are flying at FL250, you hear ATC give an altimeter setting of 28.92\" Hg in\nyour area. At what pressure altitude are you flying?\n",
        "answer": "25,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "24,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "26,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What requirement must be met regarding cargo that is carried anywhere in the\npassenger compartment of an air carrier airplane?\n",
        "answer": "The bin in which the cargo is carried may not be installed in a position that restricts\naccess to, or use of, any aisle in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The bin in which the cargo is carried may not be installed in a position that restricts\naccess to, or use of, any exit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The container or bin in which the cargo is carried must be made of material which is\nat least flash resistant.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which data must be recorded in the aircraft log or other appropriate log by a pilot\nmaking a VOR operational check for IFR operations?\n",
        "answer": "Place of operational check, amount of bearing error, date of check, and signature.\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR name or identification, date of check, amount of bearing error, and signature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Date of check, VOR name or identification, place of operational check, and amount of\nbearing error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While in flight a helicopter and an airplane are converging at a 90degrees, and the\nhelicopter is located to the right of the airplane. Which aircraft has the right-of-way, and\nwhy?\n",
        "answer": "The helicopter, because it is to the right of the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The helicopter, because helicopters have the right-of-way over airplanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airplane, because airplanes have the right-of-way over helicopters.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot cancel the IFR flight plan prior to completing the flight?\n",
        "answer": "Only in VFR conditions when not in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only if an emergency occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-On-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1200 feet AGL). What is the in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operation in Class E airspace during daylight hours for area 1?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The persons jointly responsible for th\ntermination of a commercial flight are the:\n\nition, continuation, diversion, and\n\n",
        "answer": "pilot in command and director of operations.\n",
        "choiceone": "pilot in command and chief pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot in command and the flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) establishes:\n",
        "answer": "standards and recommended international practices for contracting member states.\n",
        "choiceone": "aeronautical standards adopted by all states.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proposals for aeronautical regulations in the form of 18 annexes.\n",
        "choicethree": "standards and recommended practices applied without exception by all states,\nsignatory to the Chicago convention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What\nG airspace?\n\nplane to operate under VFR in Class\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot ceiling; 2-miles flight visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile flight visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, then:\n",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed\n",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour to\nprovide for continuation of the flight;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;\n",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person in East Africa is acting as pilot in command of a multiengine, turboprop-\npowered airplane operated in passenger-carrying service by a commuter air carrier. If\neight takeoffs and landings are accomplished in that make and basic model, which\nadditional pilot-in-command experience meets the requirement for designation as pilot\nin command?\n",
        "answer": "10 hours, and three takeoffs and landings.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 hours, and two takeoffs and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours, and two takeoffs and one landings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Member states should introduce specific security measures for the air transport of the\nfollowing groups of potentially disruptive passengers defined below:\n",
        "answer": "Deportees, inadmissible persons and persons in lawful custody\n",
        "choiceone": "Deportees and persons in lawful custody only\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deportees and inadmissible persons only\n",
        "choicethree": "None of the answers is correct\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days must the operator of an aircraft involved in an accident file a\nreport ?\n",
        "answer": "10 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Conviction for violating any East african Civil Aviation regulation relating to drugs\n",
        "answer": "could result in the suspension or revocation of any licences or rating held.\n",
        "choiceone": "automatically revokes any licences held.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not a consideration for suspension or revocation of any licence held.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For IFR planning purposes, what are the compulsory reporting points when using\nVORIDME or VORTAC fixes to define a direct route not on established airways?\n",
        "answer": "Fixes selected to define the route.\n",
        "choiceone": "There are no compulsory reporting points unless advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the changeover points.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating near other aircraft in flight? They are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, when operated so close to another aircraft they can create a collision\nhazard.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have just landed and the tower tells you to call ground control when clear of the\nrunway. You are considered clear of the runway when\n",
        "answer": "all parts of the aircraft have crossed the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aft end of the aircraft is even with the taxiway location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating limitations of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane?\n",
        "answer": "No person may operate a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane carrying passengers or\nproperty for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "A \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane is limited to a specified operating radius from its home\nbase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A pilot of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane must hold a commercial pilot certificate when\ncarrying passengers for compensation or hire.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS Il provides\n",
        "answer": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maneuvers in all directions to avoid the conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS ll, resolution\nadvisory (RA) is expected to\n",
        "answer": "notify ATC of the deviation as soon as practicable.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request ATC clearance for the deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An abbreviated departure clearance '...CLEARED AS FILED...\u2019 will always con\u2019\nname\n",
        "answer": "of the destination airport filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "and number of the STAR to be flown when filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of the first compulsory reporting point if not in a radar environment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is DME required for an instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In terminal radar service areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot flying a single-engine airplane observes a multiengine airplane approaching from\nthe left. Which pilot should give way?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot of the multiengine airplane should give way\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot of the single-engine airplane should give way\n",
        "choicetwo": "Each pilot should alter course to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018taxiway ending\u2019 marker\n",
        "answer": "indicates taxiway does not continue.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which manoeuvre will be executed by an intercepting aircraft if the pilot of this aircraft\nwants to communicate to the intercepted aircraft \"YOU MAY PROCEED\"?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt break-away manoeuvre from the intercepted aircraft consisting of a\nclimbing turn of 90 degrees or more without crossing the line of flight of the\nintercepted aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rocking aircraft twice in front of the intercepting aircraft, after acknowledgement by\nintercepted aircraft a slow level turn (normally to the left).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Circling the intercepted aircraft in a counter-clockwise pattern for aeroplanes, in a\nclockwise pattern for helicopter.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rocking aircraft and flashing navigational lights at regular intervals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:\n",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.\n",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.\n",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Define aerodrome traffic.\n",
        "answer": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome.\n",
        "choiceone": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All traffic on the movement area and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "All traffic in the aerodrome circuit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"PAPI\" shall consist of:\n",
        "answer": "A wing bar of 4 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two wing bars of 4 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two wing bars of 6 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicethree": "A wing bar of 2 sharp transition multi-lamp equally spaced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) How should a pilot determine when the DME at Price/Carbon\nCounty Airport is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The airborne DME may appear normal, but there will be no code tone.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airborne DME will always indicate \u20180\u00b0 mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne DME will \u2018search,\u2019 but will not \u2018lock on.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is a pilot requirement for oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "On unpressurized aircraft, flying above 12,000 feet MSL, pilots shall use oxygen\ncontinuously.\n",
        "choiceone": "Each pilot of a pressurized aircraft operating at FL 180 and above shall have an\napproved quick-donning type oxygen mask.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On pressurized aircraft requiring a flightcrew of two pilots, both shall continuously\nwear oxygen masks whenever the cabin pressure altitude exceeds 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Full scale deflection of a CDI occurs when the course deviation bar or needle\n",
        "answer": "deflects from the center of the scale to either far side of the scale.\n",
        "choiceone": "deflects from left side of the scale to right side of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "deflects from half scale left to half scale right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the localizer, glide slope, marker beacons, approach lighting, and HIRL,\nwhich ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il instrument\napproach to a DH below 150 feet AGL?\n",
        "answer": "TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight time limitations established for flight crewmembers include\n",
        "answer": "all commercial flying in any flight crewmember position.\n",
        "choiceone": "only commercial flying in any flight crewmember position in which operations are\nconducted under the CAA Operation of Aircraft regulations of East Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all flight time, except military, in any flight crew-member position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\nfor a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is required prior to takeoff if snow is adhering to the wings of an air carrier\nairplane?\n",
        "answer": "Ensure that the snow is removed from the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweep off as much snow as possible and the residue must be polished smooth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 15 knots to the normal V(R) speed as the snow will blow off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "imposed on the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence if that person\ndoes not hold an instrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "That person is limited to private pilot privileges at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall a commercial operator retain a record of the load manifest,\nairworthiness release, pilot route certification, flight release, and flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "3 months.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 month.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To serve as second in command of an airplane that is certificated for more than one\npilot , and operated under the CAA regulations, a person must\n",
        "answer": "within the last 12 months become familiar with the required information, and perform\nand log pilot time in the type of airplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log flight training from an authorized flight instructor in the type of\nairplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold at least a commercial pilot certificate with an airplane category rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Conviction for violating any East african Civil Aviation regulation relating to drugs\n",
        "answer": "could result in the suspension or revocation of any licences or rating held.\n",
        "choiceone": "automatically revokes any licences held.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not a consideration for suspension or revocation of any licence held.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RVR is not reported, what meteorologi\nRVR?\n\nil value should you substitute for 2,400\n",
        "answer": "A ground visibility of 600m.\n",
        "choiceone": "A ground visibility of 400m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slant range visibility of 2,400 feet for the final approach segment of the published\napproach procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which passenger announcement(s) must be made after each takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "Passengers should keep seat belts fastened while seated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Keep safety belts fastened while seated and no smoking in the aircraft lavatories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "How to use the passenger oxygen system and that there is a $1,000 fine for\ntampering with a smoke detector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report should be made to ATC without a specific request when notin radar\ncontact?\n",
        "answer": "When leaving final approach fix inbound on final approach.\n",
        "choiceone": "Entering instrument meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correcting an E.T.A. any time a previous E.T.A. is in error in excess of 2 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the minimum safe speed for any particular operation is greater than the maximum\nspeed prescribed in EAC states\u2019 Regulations\n\n",
        "answer": "aircraft may be operated at that speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "operator must have a Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) with the controlling agency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operator must have a Letter of Agreement with ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 199.) You have requested taxi instructions for takeoff using Runway 16.\nThe controller issues the following taxi instructions: \"N123, Taxi to runway 16.\" Where\nare you required to stop in order to be in compliance with the controller's instructions\n\n",
        "answer": "5 (Five).\n",
        "choiceone": "6 (Six).\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 (Nine).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "to be ferried to another base for repair of an\ninoperative engine, which operational requirement must be observed?\n",
        "answer": "Only the required flight crewmembers may be on board the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The existing and forecast weather for departure, en route, and approach must be\nVER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No passengers except authorized maintenance personnel may be carried.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial pilot has a type rating in a B-727 and B-737. A flight test is completed in a\nB-747 for the Airline Transport Pilot Certificate. What pilot privileges may be exercised\nregarding these airplanes?\n\n",
        "answer": "ATP - B-747, B-727, and B-737.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial - B-737; ATP - B-727 and B-747.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATP - B-747; Commercial - B-727 and B-737.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which approach and landing objective is assured when the pilot remains on the proper\nglidepath of the VASI?\n",
        "answer": "Safe obstruction clearance in the approach area.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuation of course guidance after transition to VFR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Course guidance from the visual descent point to touchdown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may ATC request a detailed report on an emergency even though a rule has not\nbeen violated?\n",
        "answer": "When priority has been given.\n",
        "choiceone": "Anytime an emergency occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the emergency occurs in controlled airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum fuel requirements in IFR conditions, i\nlanding is forecast to have a 1,500-foot ceiling and 3 miles vi\nETA? Fuel to fly to the first airport of intended landing,\n\nthe first airport of intended\nity at flight-planned\n",
        "answer": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a takeoff into IFR conditions with low ceilings, when should the pilot contact\ndeparture control?\n",
        "answer": "When advised by the tower.\n",
        "choiceone": "Before penetrating the clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upon completing the first turn after takeoff or upon establishing cruise climb on a\nstraight-out departure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For flight under IFR, a person serving as second in command of an aircraft under the\nCAA regulations in an East african State person must have accomplished within the last\n6 months, the recent instrument requirements of\n",
        "answer": "holding procedures, using the navigation systems for intercepting and tracking\ncourses, and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "choiceone": "using the navigation systems for interception and tracking of courses, 6 instrument\nlow approaches and holding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "using the navigation systems to intercept and track 3 inbound/3 outbound courses,\n6 holding patterns and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot is operating in Class G airspace. If existing weather conditions are below those\nfor VFR flight, an IFR flight plan must be filed and an ATC clearance received prior to\n",
        "answer": "entering controlled airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "takeoff if weather conditions are below IFR minimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "entering IFR weather conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command who is authorized to use an autopilot system in place of a second in\ncommand, may take the autopilot check\n",
        "answer": "concurrently with the instrument proficiency check, but at 12 month intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "in any aircraft appropriately equipped, provi\nintervals.\n\ning the check is taken at 6 month\n",
        "choicetwo": "concurrently with the competency check, providing the check is taken at 12 month\nintervals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:\n",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately interrupted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an arrival procedure under an IFR flight plan in VMC con\nis the responsibility of:\n\nions, traffic avoidance\n",
        "answer": "the pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "the approach controller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the radar controller.\n",
        "choicethree": "the airport controller.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (36).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the latest date that a flight engineer in East Africa may perform duties\nif his or her last medical examination was a first-class conducted on August 25, 1999?\n",
        "answer": "August 24, 2000.\n",
        "choiceone": "September 30, 2000.\n",
        "choicetwo": "August 31, 2000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial\nperson does not hold an instrument pilot rating?\n\nplane pilot if that\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 nautical miles (NM).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for\nnight flights, but not limited for day flights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on meteorological conditions?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should notification of an aircraft accident be made to the responsible authority if\nthere was substantial damage and no injuries?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum navigation equipment is required for IFR flight?\n",
        "answer": "Navigation equipment appropriate to the ground facilities to be used.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORILOC receiver, transponder, and DME.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR receiver and, if in ARTS Ill environment, a coded transponder equipped for\naltitude reporting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What international Morse Cod:\nmicrowave landing system?\n\nlentifier is used t\n",
        "answer": "A three letter Morse Code identifier preceded by the Morse Code for the letter\n\n",
        "choiceone": "A two letter Morse Code identifier preceded by the Morse Code for the letters 'IM.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "A three letter Morse Code identifier preceded by the Morse Code for the letters \"ML.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition, if any, may a pilot descend below DH or MDA when using the\napproach light system as the primary visual reference for the intended runway?\n",
        "answer": "The approach light system can be used as a visual reference, except that descent\nbelow 100 feet above TDZE requires that the red light bars be visible and identifiable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Under no condition can the approach light system serve as a necessary visual\nreference for descent below DH or MDA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent to the intended runway is authorized as long as any portion of the\napproach light system can be seen.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recommended entry position to an airport traffic pattern is\n",
        "answer": "to enter 45 degrees at the midpoint of the downwind leg at traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "45 degrees to the base leg just below traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to cross directly over the airport at traffic pattern altitude and join the downwind leg.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ap\nenforcement personnel?\n\nto the carriage of a person in the custody of law\n",
        "answer": "No more than one person considered to be in the maximum risk category may be\ncarried on a flight, and that person must have at least two armed law enforcement\nescorts.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air carrier is not allowed to serve beverages to the person in custody or the law\nenforcement escort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The person in custody must be seated between the escort and the aisle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft is not equipped with an electrical or anticolli\nmay operate that aircraft\n\nin light system, no person\n",
        "answer": "after sunset to sunrise.\n",
        "choiceone": "after dark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour after sunset.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What purpose does the taxiway location sign serve?\n",
        "answer": "Identifies taxiway on which an aircraft is located.\n",
        "choiceone": "Provides general taxiing direction to named runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Denotes entrance to runway from a taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data kept, in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in terminating the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon intercepting the assigned radial, the controller advises you that you are on the\nairway and to \"RESUME OWN NAVIGATION.\u2019 This phrase means that\n",
        "answer": "you are to assume responsibility for your own navigation.\n",
        "choiceone": "you are still in radar contact, but must make position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "radar services are terminated and you will be responsible for position reports.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a commercial airtransport airplane lands at an intermediate airport at 1822Z, what\nis the latest time it may continue a flight without receiving a redispatch authorization?\n",
        "answer": "00222.\n",
        "choiceone": "1922Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1952Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movement area of an airport, what does a \"Destination\" sign indicate?\n",
        "answer": "Direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction from taxiway to runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction from ramp to taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'No Entry\u2019 sign identifies\n",
        "answer": "paved area where aircraft entry is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the upper limit for Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "60,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 56.) You have requested taxi instructions for takeoff using Runway 16.\nThe controller issues the following taxi instructions: \"5H-ABC, Taxi to runway 16.\u201d\nWhere are you required to stop in order to be in compliance with the controller's\ninstructions\n",
        "answer": "5 (Five).\n",
        "choiceone": "6 (Six).\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 (Nine).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a certificate holder deviates from the provisions of regulations which pertain to\nmedical use of oxygen by passengers, a complete report of the incident shall be sent to\nthe Authority within\n",
        "answer": "10 working days.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 working days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days of the deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination flight information for planning an instrument\nflight should be obtained from\n",
        "answer": "the Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "the ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airmen (Class Il).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless suspended or revoked, a flight engineer licence in East Africa:\n",
        "answer": "expires 1 to 2 years after the month of issuance depending on age\n",
        "choiceone": "is issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choicetwo": "expires at the end of the 24th month following the month of issuance or renewal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the line check requirements for the pilot in command for a domestic air carrier?\n",
        "answer": "The line check is required every 12 calendar months in one of the types of airplanes\nto be flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The line check is required only when the pilot is scheduled to fly into special areas\nand airports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line check is required every 12 months in each type aircraft in which the pilot\nmay fly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an engine's rotation is stopped\nas practicable, to the\n\night, the pilot in command must reportit, as soon\n",
        "answer": "appropriate ground radio station.\n",
        "choiceone": "nearest CAA office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operations manager (or director of operations).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a flight, the controller advises \u2018traffic 2 o'clock 5 miles southbound.\" The pilot is\nholding 20 correction for a crosswind from the right. Where should the pilot look for the\ntraffic?\n",
        "answer": "40 degrees to the right of the aircraft's nose.\n",
        "choiceone": "20 degrees to the right of the aircraft's nose.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Straight ahead.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When does Air Traffic Control Services have the responsibility to prevent collisions with\nterrain?\n",
        "answer": "When a flight in accordance with IFR is vectored by radar.\n",
        "choiceone": "Always when ATS are provided.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATS never prevent collisions with terrain.\n",
        "choicethree": "ATS only provides prevention when an aircraft is flying IFR in IMC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following elements\n",
        "answer": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and pre-flight\ninformation bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries\n",
        "choiceone": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP, NOTAM, AIC and checklist\nsummaries\n",
        "choicetwo": "AIP, supplements to AIP; NOTAM and PIB; AIC and checklist summaries\n",
        "choicethree": "AIP including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM, AIC; AIRAC\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on vehicles other than those associated with emergency\nor security shall be\n",
        "answer": "Flashing yellow.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed blue.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flashing blue.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding position signs have\n",
        "answer": "white inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "red inscriptions on a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an IFR flight plan required?\n",
        "answer": "In Class E airspace when IMC exists or in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "When less than VFR conditions exist in either Class E or Class G airspace and in\nClass A airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In all Class E airspace when conditions are below VFR, in Class A airspace, and in\ndefense zone airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the tower and Flight Control Center (FCC) are located on the same airport, which\nfunction is provided by the FCC during those periods when the tower is closed?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Advisory Service.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach control services.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight time limitations established for flight crewmembers include\n",
        "answer": "all commercial flying in any flight crewmember position.\n",
        "choiceone": "only commercial flying in any flight crewmember position in which operations are\nconducted under the CAA Operation of Aircraft regulations of East Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all flight time, except military, in any flight crew-member position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition, if any, may a pilot descend below DH or MDA when using the\napproach light system as the primary visual reference for the intended runway?\n",
        "answer": "The approach light system can be used as a visual reference, except that descent\nbelow 100 feet above TDZE requires that the red light bars be visible and identifiable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Under no condition can the approach light system serve as a necessary visual\nreference for descent below DH or MDA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent to the intended runway is authorized as long as any portion of the\napproach light system can be seen.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot cancel the IFR flight plan prior to completing the flight?\n",
        "answer": "Only in VFR conditions when not in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only if an emergency occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Preferred IFR routes beginning with a fix indicate that departing\nrouted to the fix by\n\nrcraft will normally be\n",
        "answer": "an instrument departure procedure (DP), or radar vectors.\n",
        "choiceone": "the established airway(s) between the departure airport and the fix.\n",
        "choicetwo": "direct route only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person whose duties include the handling or carriage of dangerous articles and/or\nmagnetized materials must have satisfactorily completed an established and approved\ntraining program within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional flight hours within the preceding 6 calendar months are required to\nmaintain IFR currency in a helicopter?\n",
        "answer": "6 instrument approaches, holding procedures and tracking courses must be\naccomplished.\n",
        "choiceone": "three instrument approaches must also be accomplished.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours of actual or simulated instrument time in the same type helicopter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What service is provided by departure control to an IFR flight when operating within the\nouter area of Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Separation from all IFR aircraft and participating VFR aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Separation from all aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position and altitude of all traffic within 2 miles of the IFR pilot's line of flight and\naltitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) capability, the accuracy of\nthe GPS derived\n",
        "answer": "altitude information should not be relied upon to determine aircraft altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "position is not affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity information should be relied upon to determine aircraft groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When information is disseminated about a taxiway closure, it will be located in\n",
        "answer": "NOTAM (L) distribution.\n",
        "choiceone": "FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM (D) distribution.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When information is disseminated for a navigational facility, it will be located in\n",
        "answer": "NOTAM (D) distribution.\n",
        "choiceone": "FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM (L) distribution.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is contained in the Notices to Airman(NOTAM) Publication ?\n",
        "answer": "Current NOTAM(D) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choiceone": "All Current NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Current NOTAM(L) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "No person may operate an aircraft in simulated instrument flight conditions unless the\n",
        "answer": "other control seat is occupied by a safety pilot, who holds at least a private pilot\ncertificate and is appropriately rated.\n",
        "choiceone": "other control seat is occupied by at least an appropriately rated commercial pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot has filed an IFR flight plan and received an IFR clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless suspended or revoked, a flight engineer licence in East Africa:\n",
        "answer": "expires 1 to 2 years after the month of issuance depending on age\n",
        "choiceone": "is issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choicetwo": "expires at the end of the 24th month following the month of issuance or renewal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air operator may schedule a pilot to fly in an airplane, having two pilots and one\nadditional flight crewmember, for no more than\n",
        "answer": "12 hours during any 24 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-1?\n",
        "answer": "217 knots and 1.81 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "221 knots and 1.83 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "223 knots and 2.01 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within ICAO annex 14, Which is the minimum width of a runway with runway code 4?\n",
        "answer": "45 metres\n",
        "choiceone": "35 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "40 metres\n",
        "choicethree": "50 metres\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What service is provided by departure control to an IFR flight when operating within the\nouter area of Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Separation from all IFR aircraft and participating VFR aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Separation from all aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position and altitude of all traffic within 2 miles of the IFR pilot's line of flight and\naltitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 68.) What is the VASI approach slope angle for RWY 12?\n",
        "answer": "3.0 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "2.8 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC transponder is not to be used unless it has been tested, inspected, and found to\ncomply with regulations within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when necessary for takeoff or landing or unless otherwise authorized by the\nCAA, the minimum altitude for IFR flight is\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle over designated mountainous terrain;\nfeet above the highest obstacle over terrain elsewhere.\n\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet over all terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,000 feet over designated mountainous terrain; 2,000 feet over terrain elsewhere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which restriction must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment?\n",
        "answer": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable bin and secured to a passenger seat or the\nfloor structure of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis packaged or covered to avoid possible injury to occupants.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cargo carried in passenger seats must be forward of all passengers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is DME required for an instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In terminal radar service areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot file a composite flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Any time a portion of the flight will be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "When requested or advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time a landing is planned at an intermediate airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ap\nenforcement personnel?\n\nto the carriage of a person in the custody of law\n",
        "answer": "No more than one person considered to be in the maximum risk category may be\ncarried on a flight, and that person must have at least two armed law enforcement\nescorts.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air carrier is not allowed to serve beverages to the person in custody or the law\nenforcement escort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The person in custody must be seated between the escort and the aisle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures for keeping copies of the aircraft maintenance log of the aircraft available to\nappropriate personnel shall be set forth in\n",
        "answer": "the certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maintenance procedures handbook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Operations Specifications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The required preflight action relative to weather reports and fuel requirements is\napplicable to\n",
        "answer": "any flight not in the vicinity of an airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "any flight conducted for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR flights only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For what purpose may cockpit voice recorders and flight data recorders NOT be used?\n",
        "answer": "Determining any certificate action, or civil penalty, arising out of an accident or\noccurrence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Determining causes of accidents and occurrences under investigation by the Civil\nAviation Authority.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identifying procedures that may have been conducive to any accident, or\noccurrence\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tricolor Visual Approach Indicators normally consist of\n",
        "answer": "a single unit, projecting a three-color visual approach path.\n",
        "choiceone": "three separate light units, each projecting a different color approach path.\n",
        "choicetwo": "three separate light projecting units of very high candle power with a daytime range\nof approximately 5 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum qualifications for a person who occupies the other control seat\nas safety pilot during simulated instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot certificate with appropriate category and class ratings for the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Private pilot with instrument rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Private pilot with appropriate category, class, and instrument ratings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If not equipped with required position lights, an aircraft must terminate flight\n",
        "answer": "at sunset.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes after sunset.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour after sunset.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what time period should the nearest ATS office be notified when an aircraft is\ninvolved in an accident which results in substantial damage?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 calendar days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 77.) At which point does the basi\nterminate?\n\ninstrument departure procedure\n",
        "answer": "At STAKK intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "When Helena Departure Control establishes radar contact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Over the BOZEMAN VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum number of hours a pilot may fly in 7 consecutive days as the pilot in\ncommand in a two-pilot crew for air operator is:\n\n",
        "answer": "32 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "35 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial pilot has a type rating in a B-727 and B-737. A flight test is completed in a\nB-747 for the Airline Transport Pilot Certificate. What pilot privileges may be exercised\nregarding these airplanes?\n\n",
        "answer": "ATP - B-747, B-727, and B-737.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial - B-737; ATP - B-727 and B-747.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATP - B-747; Commercial - B-727 and B-737.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is a pilot on an IFR flight plan responsible for avoiding other aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "When weather conditions permit, regardless of whether operating under IFR or VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "At all times when notin radar contact with ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when advised by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operational requirement must be observed when ferrying a large, turbine-engine-\npowered airplane when one of its engines is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The weather conditions at takeoff and destination must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Weather conditions must exceed the basic VFR minimums for the entire route,\nincluding takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The flight cannot be conducted between official sunset and sunrise.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, except by arrangement with the pilot in command of each aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which facility may be substituted for the middle marker during a Category I ILS\napproach?\n",
        "answer": "Compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORIDME FIX.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surveillance radar.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination flight information for planning an instrument\nflight should be obtained from\n",
        "answer": "the Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "the ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airmen (Class Il).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When not flying over high terrain or mountainous areas and where no minimum flight\naltitude has been established, flights in accordance with IFR shall be flown at a level\nwhich is at least:\n",
        "answer": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) How should a pilot determine when the DME at Price/Carbon\nCounty Airport is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The airborne DME may appear normal, but there will be no code tone.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airborne DME will always indicate \u20180\u00b0 mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne DME will \u2018search,\u2019 but will not \u2018lock on.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is a pilot requirement for oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "On unpressurized aircraft, flying above 12,000 feet MSL, pilots shall use oxygen\ncontinuously.\n",
        "choiceone": "Each pilot of a pressurized aircraft operating at FL 180 and above shall have an\napproved quick-donning type oxygen mask.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On pressurized aircraft requiring a flightcrew of two pilots, both shall continuously\nwear oxygen masks whenever the cabin pressure altitude exceeds 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Full scale deflection of a CDI occurs when the course deviation bar or needle\n",
        "answer": "deflects from the center of the scale to either far side of the scale.\n",
        "choiceone": "deflects from left side of the scale to right side of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "deflects from half scale left to half scale right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the localizer, glide slope, marker beacons, approach lighting, and HIRL,\nwhich ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il instrument\napproach to a DH below 150 feet AGL?\n",
        "answer": "TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight time limitations established for flight crewmembers include\n",
        "answer": "all commercial flying in any flight crewmember position.\n",
        "choiceone": "only commercial flying in any flight crewmember position in which operations are\nconducted under the CAA Operation of Aircraft regulations of East Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all flight time, except military, in any flight crew-member position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\nfor a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is required prior to takeoff if snow is adhering to the wings of an air carrier\nairplane?\n",
        "answer": "Ensure that the snow is removed from the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweep off as much snow as possible and the residue must be polished smooth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 15 knots to the normal V(R) speed as the snow will blow off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "imposed on the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence if that person\ndoes not hold an instrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "That person is limited to private pilot privileges at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall a commercial operator retain a record of the load manifest,\nairworthiness release, pilot route certification, flight release, and flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "3 months.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 month.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To serve as second in command of an airplane that is certificated for more than one\npilot , and operated under the CAA regulations, a person must\n",
        "answer": "within the last 12 months become familiar with the required information, and perform\nand log pilot time in the type of airplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log flight training from an authorized flight instructor in the type of\nairplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold at least a commercial pilot certificate with an airplane category rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Conviction for violating any East african Civil Aviation regulation relating to drugs\n",
        "answer": "could result in the suspension or revocation of any licences or rating held.\n",
        "choiceone": "automatically revokes any licences held.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not a consideration for suspension or revocation of any licence held.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RVR is not reported, what meteorologi\nRVR?\n\nil value should you substitute for 2,400\n",
        "answer": "A ground visibility of 600m.\n",
        "choiceone": "A ground visibility of 400m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slant range visibility of 2,400 feet for the final approach segment of the published\napproach procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which passenger announcement(s) must be made after each takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "Passengers should keep seat belts fastened while seated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Keep safety belts fastened while seated and no smoking in the aircraft lavatories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "How to use the passenger oxygen system and that there is a $1,000 fine for\ntampering with a smoke detector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report should be made to ATC without a specific request when notin radar\ncontact?\n",
        "answer": "When leaving final approach fix inbound on final approach.\n",
        "choiceone": "Entering instrument meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correcting an E.T.A. any time a previous E.T.A. is in error in excess of 2 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the minimum safe speed for any particular operation is greater than the maximum\nspeed prescribed in EAC states\u2019 Regulations\n\n",
        "answer": "aircraft may be operated at that speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "operator must have a Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) with the controlling agency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operator must have a Letter of Agreement with ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 199.) You have requested taxi instructions for takeoff using Runway 16.\nThe controller issues the following taxi instructions: \"N123, Taxi to runway 16.\" Where\nare you required to stop in order to be in compliance with the controller's instructions\n\n",
        "answer": "5 (Five).\n",
        "choiceone": "6 (Six).\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 (Nine).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "to be ferried to another base for repair of an\ninoperative engine, which operational requirement must be observed?\n",
        "answer": "Only the required flight crewmembers may be on board the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The existing and forecast weather for departure, en route, and approach must be\nVER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No passengers except authorized maintenance personnel may be carried.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial pilot has a type rating in a B-727 and B-737. A flight test is completed in a\nB-747 for the Airline Transport Pilot Certificate. What pilot privileges may be exercised\nregarding these airplanes?\n\n",
        "answer": "ATP - B-747, B-727, and B-737.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial - B-737; ATP - B-727 and B-747.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATP - B-747; Commercial - B-727 and B-737.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which approach and landing objective is assured when the pilot remains on the proper\nglidepath of the VASI?\n",
        "answer": "Safe obstruction clearance in the approach area.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuation of course guidance after transition to VFR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Course guidance from the visual descent point to touchdown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may ATC request a detailed report on an emergency even though a rule has not\nbeen violated?\n",
        "answer": "When priority has been given.\n",
        "choiceone": "Anytime an emergency occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the emergency occurs in controlled airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum fuel requirements in IFR conditions, i\nlanding is forecast to have a 1,500-foot ceiling and 3 miles vi\nETA? Fuel to fly to the first airport of intended landing,\n\nthe first airport of intended\nity at flight-planned\n",
        "answer": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a takeoff into IFR conditions with low ceilings, when should the pilot contact\ndeparture control?\n",
        "answer": "When advised by the tower.\n",
        "choiceone": "Before penetrating the clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upon completing the first turn after takeoff or upon establishing cruise climb on a\nstraight-out departure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For flight under IFR, a person serving as second in command of an aircraft under the\nCAA regulations in an East african State person must have accomplished within the last\n6 months, the recent instrument requirements of\n",
        "answer": "holding procedures, using the navigation systems for intercepting and tracking\ncourses, and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "choiceone": "using the navigation systems for interception and tracking of courses, 6 instrument\nlow approaches and holding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "using the navigation systems to intercept and track 3 inbound/3 outbound courses,\n6 holding patterns and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot is operating in Class G airspace. If existing weather conditions are below those\nfor VFR flight, an IFR flight plan must be filed and an ATC clearance received prior to\n",
        "answer": "entering controlled airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "takeoff if weather conditions are below IFR minimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "entering IFR weather conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command who is authorized to use an autopilot system in place of a second in\ncommand, may take the autopilot check\n",
        "answer": "concurrently with the instrument proficiency check, but at 12 month intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "in any aircraft appropriately equipped, provi\nintervals.\n\ning the check is taken at 6 month\n",
        "choicetwo": "concurrently with the competency check, providing the check is taken at 12 month\nintervals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:\n",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately interrupted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an arrival procedure under an IFR flight plan in VMC con\nis the responsibility of:\n\nions, traffic avoidance\n",
        "answer": "the pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "the approach controller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the radar controller.\n",
        "choicethree": "the airport controller.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the forecast weather conditions for a destination and alternate airport are\nconsidered marginal for a domestic air operation, what specific action should the pilot\nin command take?\n\n",
        "answer": "List at least one additional alternate airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "List an airport where the forecast weather is not marginal as the alternate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 1 additional hour of fuel based on cruise power settings for the airplane in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 78 and 79.) What is your position relative to the VOR COP southeast\nbound on V86 between the BOZEMAN and LIVINGSTON VORTACs? The No. 1 VOR is\ntuned to 116.1 and the No. 2 VOR is tuned to 112.2.\n",
        "answer": "Past the LVM R-246 and east of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choiceone": "Past the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approaching the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How soon after the conviction for driving wi itoxicated by alcohol or drugs shall it\nbe reported to the CAA, Civil Aviation Security Division?\n",
        "answer": "No later than 60 days after the motor vehicle action.\n",
        "choiceone": "No later than 30 working days after the motor vehicle action.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Required to be reported upon renewal of medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 78.) What is the mi\nfor a flight southeast bound on V86?\n\njum crossing altitude over the BOZEMAN VORTAC\n",
        "answer": "9,300 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "8,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9,700 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the localizer, glide slope, marker beacons, approach lighting, and HIRL,\nwhich ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il instrument\napproach to a DH below 150 feet AGL?\n",
        "answer": "TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A certificated commercial pilot who carries passengers for hire at night or in excess of\n50 NM is required to have at least\n",
        "answer": "an instrument rating in the same category and class of aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "an associated type rating if the airplane is of the multiengine class.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-2?\n",
        "answer": "210 knots and 1.51 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "210 knots and 1.57 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 knots and 1.45 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional flight hours within the preceding 6 calendar months are required to\nmaintain IFR currency in a helicopter?\n",
        "answer": "6 instrument approaches, holding procedures and tracking courses must be\naccomplished.\n",
        "choiceone": "three instrument approaches must also be accomplished.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours of actual or simulated instrument time in the same type helicopter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\nig at 'D' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "3,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) How should a pilot determine when the DME at Price/Carbon\nCounty Airport is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The airborne DME may appear normal, but there will be no code tone.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airborne DME will always indicate \u20180\u00b0 mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne DME will \u2018search,\u2019 but will not \u2018lock on.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting is the value to which the scale of the pressure altimeter is set so the\naltimeter indicates\n",
        "answer": "true altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure altitude at sea level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To comply with ATC instructions for altitude changes of more than 1,000 feet, what rate\nof climb or descent should be used?\n",
        "answer": "As rapidly as practicable to 1,000 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then\nbetween 500 and 1,500 feet per minute until reaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "As rapidly as practicable to 500 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then at\n500 feet per minute until the assigned altitude is reached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet per minute during climb and 500 feet per minute during descents until\nreaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is expected of you as pilot on an IFR flight pla!\nin VFR conditions?\n\nyou are descending or climbing\n",
        "answer": "Execute gentle banks, left and right, at a frequency which permits continuous visual\nscanning of the airspace about you.\n",
        "choiceone": "If on an airway, climb or descend to the right of the centerline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Advise ATC you are in visual conditions and will remain a short distance to the right\nof the centerline while climbing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in area\n6?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition is pressure altitude and density altitude the same value?\n",
        "answer": "At standard temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the altimeter setting is 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When indicated, and pressure altitudes are the same value on the altimeter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS Il provides\n",
        "answer": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maneuvers in all directions to avoid the conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is primarily responsible for maintait\n",
        "answer": "Owner or operator of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The lead mechanic responsible for that aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot in command or operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an operator of an aircraft, which has been involved in an incident, required to\nsubmit a report to the nearest ATS office?\n\n",
        "answer": "Only if requested to do so by the responsible authority\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airborne incident would require that the nearest ATS office be notified\nimmediately?\n\n",
        "answer": "Flight control system malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo compartment door malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin door opened in-flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude may a pilot select upon receiving a VFR-On-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Any appropriate VFR altitude at or above the MEA in VFR weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any altitude at least 1,000 feet above the meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any VFR altitude appropriate for the direction of flight at least 1,000 feet above the\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does a commercial pilot certificate have a specific expiration date?\n",
        "answer": "No, itis issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choiceone": "Yes, it expires at the end of the Regulations month after the month in which it was\nissued.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No, but commercial privileges expire if a flight review is not satisfactorily completed\neach 12 months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum certificate and rating requirements for the pilot in command of a\nturbojet airplane with two engines being operated by a Commuter Air Carrier as defined\nin the Operation of aircraft regulations in the East African region.\n",
        "answer": "Airline transport pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; airplane type\nrating, if required.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airline transport pilot of any category; multiengine class rating; airplane type rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; instrument rating;\nairplane type rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing has:\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).\n",
        "choiceone": "a military aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).\n",
        "choicethree": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate medical attention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When does Air Traffic Control Services have the responsibility to prevent collisions with\nterrain?\n",
        "answer": "When a flight in accordance with IFR is vectored by radar.\n",
        "choiceone": "Always when ATS are provided.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATS never prevent collisions with terrain.\n",
        "choicethree": "ATS only provides prevention when an aircraft is flying IFR in IMC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway-lead-in lighting shall consist:\n",
        "answer": "of groups of at least three white lights, flashing in sequence towards the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "always of a straight row of lights towards the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of a group of at least 5 flashing yellow lights.\n",
        "choicethree": "of an arbitrary amount of green lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aerodrome category for rescue and fire fighting is based on:\n",
        "answer": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane normally using the aerodrome and its\nmaximum fuselage width.\n",
        "choiceone": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane normally using the aerodrome and its\nmaximum fuselage weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "The longest aeroplane maximum width only\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (40).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To meet the requirements for flight under IFR, an aircraft must be equipped with cer\noperable instruments and equipment. One of those required is\n",
        "answer": "a clock with sweep-second pointer or digital presentation.\n",
        "choiceone": "a radar altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a transponder with altitude reporting capability.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-1?\n",
        "answer": "19,400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the recommended procedure for transitioning from VFR to IFR on a composite\nflight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Prior to transitioning to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center close the VFR portion,\nand request ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upon reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center\nand cancel your VFR flight plan, then contact ACC and request an IFR clearance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prior to reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact ACC, request your\nIFR clearance, and instruct them to cancel the VFR flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before beginning any flight under IFR, the pilot in command must become fami\nall available information concerning that flight. In addition, the pilot must\n\n",
        "answer": "be familiar with the runway lengths at airports of intended use, and the alternatives\navailable if the flight cannot be completed.\n",
        "choiceone": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and become familiar with the instrument\napproaches to that airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and confirm adequate takeoff and landing\nperformance at the destination airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While in flight a helicopter and an airplane are converging at a 90degrees, and the\nhelicopter is located to the right of the airplane. Which aircraft has the right-of-way, and\nwhy?\n",
        "answer": "The helicopter, because it is to the right of the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The helicopter, because helicopters have the right-of-way over airplanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airplane, because airplanes have the right-of-way over helicopters.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which document specifically authorizes a person to operate an\ngeographic area?\n\n",
        "answer": "Operations Specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating Certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch Release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot file a composite flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Any time a portion of the flight will be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "When requested or advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time a landing is planned at an intermediate airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an operator of an aircraft, which has been involved in an incident, required to\nsubmit a report to the nearest ATS office?\n\n",
        "answer": "Only if requested to do so by the responsible authority\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "req!\nexperience requirements to act as pilot in command of an airplane under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Four instrument approaches in an airplane, or an approved airplane flight simulator\nor training device.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three hours of simulated or actual instrument flight time in a helicopter and two\ninstrument approaches in an airplane or helicopter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three instrument approaches in an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of operations over an area designated as a mountainous area where no\nother um altitude is prescribed, no person may operate an aircraft under IFR\nbelow an altitude of\n\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an operational check on the aircraft VOR equipment be accomplished when\nused to operate under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the preceding 10 days or 10 hours of flight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the preceding 30 days or 30 hours of flight time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which manoeuvre will be executed by an intercepting aircraft if the pilot of this aircraft\nwants to communicate to the intercepted aircraft \"YOU MAY PROCEED\"?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt break-away manoeuvre from the intercepted aircraft consisting of a\nclimbing turn of 90 degrees or more without crossing the line of flight of the\nintercepted aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rocking aircraft twice in front of the intercepting aircraft, after acknowledgement by\nintercepted aircraft a slow level turn (normally to the left).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Circling the intercepted aircraft in a counter-clockwise pattern for aeroplanes, in a\nclockwise pattern for helicopter.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rocking aircraft and flashing navigational lights at regular intervals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time:\n",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until it stops at\nthe end of the flight (block time).\n",
        "choicetwo": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and temperature on\nthat day.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (41).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 56.) You have requested taxi instructions for takeoff using Runway 16.\nThe controller issues the following taxi instructions: \"5H-ABC, Taxi to runway 16.\u201d\nWhere are you required to stop in order to be in compliance with the controller's\ninstructions\n",
        "answer": "5 (Five).\n",
        "choiceone": "6 (Six).\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 (Nine).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may ATC request a detailed report on an emergency even though a rule has not\nbeen violated?\n",
        "answer": "When priority has been given.\n",
        "choiceone": "Anytime an emergency occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the emergency occurs in controlled airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oxygen requirement for an unpressurized aircraft at 15,000 feet under the\nOperation of Aircraft regulations in East Africa?\n",
        "answer": "Crew must start using oxygen at 12,000 feet and passengers at 14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "All occupants must use oxygen for the entire time at this altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew must use oxygen for the entire time above 14,000 feet and passengers must be\nprovided supplemental oxygen only above 15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airplane is overtaking a helicopter. Which aircraft has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airplane; the airplane pilot should alter course to the left to pass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the left.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an eligibility requirement for the issuance of a private piot licence?\n",
        "answer": "Hold a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Be a high school graduate or equivalent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Read, understand, and speak the English language without impediment or accent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sources of aeronautical information, when used collectively, provide the latest\nstatus of airport conditions (e.g., runway closures, runway lighting, snow conditions)?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Facility Directory, Distant (D) NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual, aeronautical charts, and Distant (D) Notice to\nAirmen (NOTAM's).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport Facility Directory, FDC NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in area\n6?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If, while in Class E airspace, a clearance is received to \u2018maintain VFR conditions on top,\u2019\nthe pilot should maintain a VFR cruising altitude based on the direction of the\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person may not act as a crewmember of a civil aircraft if alcoholic beverages have\nbeen consumed by that person within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-2?\n",
        "answer": "17,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify REIL.\n",
        "answer": "Synchronized flashing lights laterally at each side of the runway threshold.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights for the first 2,000 feet of runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green lights at the threshold and red lights at far end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:\n",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "A NOTAM RAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.\n",
        "choicethree": "An Advisory NOTAM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (42).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airplane is overtaking a helicopter. Which aircraft has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airplane; the airplane pilot should alter course to the left to pass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the left.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an eligibility requirement for the issuance of a private piot licence?\n",
        "answer": "Hold a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Be a high school graduate or equivalent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Read, understand, and speak the English language without impediment or accent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The operator of an aircraft that has been involved in ai\nreport to the nearest responsible office\n\ncident is required to submit a\n",
        "answer": "only if requested to do so.\n",
        "choiceone": "within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft is not equipped with an electrical or anticolli\nmay operate that aircraft\n\nin light system, no person\n",
        "answer": "after sunset to sunrise.\n",
        "choiceone": "after dark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour after sunset.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a \u2018low\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Red.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-3?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 59 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours 9 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour 52 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is an \u2018on course\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Green.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which checks and inspections of flight instruments or instrument systems must be\naccomplished before an aircraft can be flown under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "VOR within 30 days, altimeter systems within 24 calendar months, and transponder\nwithin 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "ELT test within 30 days, altimeter systems within 12 calendar months, and\ntransponder within 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR within 24 calendar months, transponder within 24 calendar months, and\naltimeter system within 12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose for the runway hold position markings on the taxiway?\n",
        "answer": "Holds aircraft short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 68.) What is the VASI approach slope angle for RWY 12?\n",
        "answer": "3.0 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "2.8 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating near other aircraft in flight? They are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, when operated so close to another aircraft they can create a collision\nhazard.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation is grounds for revoking any flight engineer certificate or rating?\n",
        "answer": "Alteration of their flight engineer certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating during a physical deficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flying 1,200 hours in 12 calendar months but logging only 1,000 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While in flight a helicopter and an airplane are converging at a 90degrees, and the\nhelicopter is located to the right of the airplane. Which aircraft has the right-of-way, and\nwhy?\n",
        "answer": "The helicopter, because it is to the right of the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The helicopter, because helicopters have the right-of-way over airplanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airplane, because airplanes have the right-of-way over helicopters.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot descend below 100 feet above the touchdown zone elevation during a\nCategory Il ILS instrument approach when only the approach lights are visible?\n",
        "answer": "When the red terminal bar of the approach light systems are in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "After passing the visual descent point (VDP).\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR is 1,600 feet or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movement area of an airport, what does a \"Destination\" sign indicate?\n",
        "answer": "Direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction from taxiway to runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction from ramp to taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-4?\n",
        "answer": "50.7 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "48.3 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "51.3 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an engine's rotation is stopped\nas practicable, to the\n\night, the pilot in command must reportit, as soon\n",
        "answer": "appropriate ground radio station.\n",
        "choiceone": "nearest CAA office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operations manager (or director of operations).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international convention defining rules relative to the responsibilities of\ninternational air carriers for the carriage of passengers, baggage and freight is the:\n",
        "answer": "Warsaw Convention.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tokyo Convention.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hague Convention.\n",
        "choicethree": "Montreal Convention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to that\nlicence due to illness, the authority must be informed:\n",
        "answer": "After 21 days of consecutive \"illness\"\n",
        "choiceone": "as soon as possible if the illness is expected to last more than 21days\n",
        "choicetwo": "after one calendar month of consecutive illness\n",
        "choicethree": "if still not fit to fly when his/her current medical certificate expires\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"PAPI\" shall consist of:\n",
        "answer": "A wing bar of 4 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two wing bars of 4 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two wing bars of 6 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicethree": "A wing bar of 2 sharp transition multi-lamp equally spaced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on vehicles other than those associated with emergency\nor security shall be\n",
        "answer": "Flashing yellow.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed blue.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flashing blue.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (43).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A series of continuous red lights in the runway centerline lighting indicates that\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "one-half of the runway remains.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ensuring that appropriate aeronautical charts are aboard an aircraft is the responsibility\nof the:\n",
        "answer": "pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight navigator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a commercial pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft\nfor compensation or hire, if that person\n",
        "answer": "is qualified in accordance with EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nwith the applicable parts that apply to the operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "holds appropriate category, class ratings, and meets the recent flight experience\nrequirements of EAC states' Personnel Licensing regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is qualified in accordance with the EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nhas passed a pilot competency check given by an authorized check pilot.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight simulator and an aircraft, the applicant\nis\n",
        "answer": "required to have a current first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have a least a current third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not required to hold a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "imposed on the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence if that person\ndoes not hold an instrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "That person is limited to private pilot privileges at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Haze can give the illusion that the aircraft is\n",
        "answer": "farther from the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choiceone": "closer to the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same distance from the runway as when there is no restriction to visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n25,000 pounds? |Initial weight: 179,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 136,500 Ib\n",
        "answer": "8 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what time period should the nearest ATS office be notified when an aircraft is\ninvolved in an accident which results in substantial damage?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 calendar days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RVR minimums for takeoff or landing are published in an AIP, if RVR is inoperative\nand cannot be reported for the runway at the time. Which of the following would apply?\n",
        "answer": "RVR minimums which are specified in the procedure should be converted and\napplied as ground visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "RVR minimums may be disregarded, providing the runway has an operative HIRL\nsystem.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RVR minimums may be disregarded, providing all other components of the ILS\nsystem are operative.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operations by a required cockpit voice recorder\n",
        "answer": "may be erased or obliterated, except the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "must be erased or obliterated, except for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be erased or obliterated, only once each flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "East Africa a certificate of validation issued to a qualified flight engineer applicant,\npending review of their application, is effective for what maximum period of time?\n",
        "answer": "120 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "60 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "90 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before takeoff, the pilot in command of an aircraft carrying passengers shall ensure that\nall passengers have been orally briefed on the normal and emergency use of oxygen\n",
        "answer": "if the flight involves operations above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "regardless of the altitude at which the flight will operate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the flight involves operations at or above 12,000 feet MSL for more than 30\nminutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movement area of an airport, what does a \"Destination\" sign indicate?\n",
        "answer": "Direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction from taxiway to runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction from ramp to taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air carrier must give instruction on such subjects as respiration, hypoxia, and\ndecompression to crewmembers serving on pressurized airplanes operated above\n",
        "answer": "FL 250.\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 180.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 200.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a requirement regarding the carriage and operation of oxygen equipment for\nmedical use by passengers?\n",
        "answer": "No person may smoke within 10 feet of oxygen storage and dispensing equipment.\n",
        "choiceone": "When oxygen equipment is used for the medical treatment of a patient, the rules\npertaining to emergency exit access are waived.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No person may connect oxygen bottles or any other ancillary equipment until all\npassengers are aboard the aircraft and seated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-4?\n",
        "answer": "50.7 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "48.3 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "51.3 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight time limitations established for flight crewmembers include\n",
        "answer": "all commercial flying in any flight crewmember position.\n",
        "choiceone": "only commercial flying in any flight crewmember position in which operations are\nconducted under the CAA Operation of Aircraft regulations of East Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all flight time, except military, in any flight crew-member position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than in cruise flight, below what altitude are non-safety related cockpit activities\nby flight crewmembers prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "12,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:\n",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.\n",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.\n",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, then:\n",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed\n",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour to\nprovide for continuation of the flight;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;\n",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Required Navigation Performance (RNP) shall be prescribed\n",
        "answer": "by states on the basis of regional air navigation agreements\n",
        "choiceone": "by states but not on the basis of regional air agreements\n",
        "choicetwo": "by ICAO on the basis of regional air navigation agreements\n",
        "choicethree": "by regional air navigation agreements\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (44).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person may not act as a crewmember of a civil aircraft if alcoholic beverages have\nbeen consumed by that person within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does a series of arrows painted on the approach end of a runway signify?\n",
        "answer": "That portion of the runway is not suitable for landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "That area is restricted solely to taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "That portion of the runway is the designated touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "req!\nexperience requirements to act as pilot in command of an airplane under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Four instrument approaches in an airplane, or an approved airplane flight simulator\nor training device.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three hours of simulated or actual instrument flight time in a helicopter and two\ninstrument approaches in an airplane or helicopter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three instrument approaches in an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which checks and inspections of flight instruments or instrument systems must be\naccomplished before an aircraft can be flown under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "VOR within 30 days, altimeter systems within 24 calendar months, and transponder\nwithin 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "ELT test within 30 days, altimeter systems within 12 calendar months, and\ntransponder within 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR within 24 calendar months, transponder within 24 calendar months, and\naltimeter system within 12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A coded transponder equipped with altitude reporting capabil\ncontrolled airspace\n\nis required in all\n",
        "answer": "at and above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "at and above 2,500 feet above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What colors are runway holding position signs?\n",
        "answer": "White with a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red with a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow with a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIRMETs are issued on a scheduled basis every\n",
        "answer": "six hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes after the hour only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes until the AIRMET is canceled.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should notification of an aircraft accident be made to the responsible authority if\nthere was substantial damage and no injuries?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an emergency, a pilot-in-command does not deviate from an CAA regulations\nbut n priority by ATC. To whom or under what condition is the pilot required to\nsubmit a written report?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upon request by ATC, submit a written report to the ATC manager.\n",
        "choiceone": "To the manager of the General Aviation District Office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the manager of the facility in control at the time of the deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is DME required for an instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In terminal radar service areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a two-way radio capable of communicating with ATC on appropriate\nfrequencies, which equipments the helicopter required to have to operate within Class\nB airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An appropriate radar beacon transponder.\n",
        "choiceone": "A VOR or TACAN receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DME, a VOR or TACAN receiver, and an appropriate transponder beacon.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'No Entry\u2019 sign identifies\n",
        "answer": "paved area where aircraft entry is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an operational check on the aircraft VOR equipment be accomplished when\nused to operate under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the preceding 10 days or 10 hours of flight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the preceding 30 days or 30 hours of flight time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should pilots state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "When departing from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "When visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When parallel runways are in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first freedom of the air is:\n",
        "answer": "The right to overfly without landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right to land for a technical stop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The opportunity to operate a commercial flight with passengers on board between\ntwo states.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right to board passengers from the state where the aircraft is registered and to\nfly to an other state.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should be amended\nor cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in excess of:\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choicethree": "60 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:\n",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately interrupted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (45).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are VFR-On-Top operations prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "In Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "During off-airways direct flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When flying through Class B airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 157.) This is an example of\n",
        "answer": "an ILS Critical Area Boundary Sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "an ILS Critical Area Holding Position Sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a Runway Boundary Sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018taxiway ending\u2019 marker\n",
        "answer": "indicates taxiway does not continue.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When instructed by ATC to \u2018Hold short of a runway (ILS critical area, etc.),\" the pilot\nshould stop\n",
        "answer": "so that no part of the aircraft extends beyond the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the nose gear on the hold line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "so the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a night operation, the pilot of aircraft #1 sees only the green light of aircraft #2. If\nthe aircraft are converging, which pilot has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "#1; aircraft #1 is to the right of aircraft #2.\n",
        "choiceone": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the left of aircraft #1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the right of aircraft #1.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of No Entry sign?\n",
        "answer": "Identifies paved area where aircraft are prohibited from entering.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identifies the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When approaching taxiway holding lines from the side with the continuous lines, the\npilot\n",
        "answer": "should not cross the lines without ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "may continue taxiing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "should continue taxiing until all parts of the aircraft have crossed the lines.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To carry passengers for hire in an airplane on cross-country flights of more than 50 NM\nfrom the departure airport, the pilot in command is required to hold at least\n",
        "answer": "a Commercial Pilot Licence with an instrument rating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a Category Il pilot authorization.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition is pressure altitude and density altitude the same value?\n",
        "answer": "At standard temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the altimeter setting is 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When indicated, and pressure altitudes are the same value on the altimeter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to that\nlicence due to illness, the authority must be informed:\n",
        "answer": "After 21 days of consecutive \"illness\"\n",
        "choiceone": "as soon as possible if the illness is expected to last more than 21days\n",
        "choicetwo": "after one calendar month of consecutive illness\n",
        "choicethree": "if still not fit to fly when his/her current medical certificate expires\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:\n",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "A NOTAM RAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.\n",
        "choicethree": "An Advisory NOTAM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The centre line and crossbar lights of a precision approach Category | lighting\nsystem shall be fixed lights, showing variable intensity of the following colour:\n",
        "answer": "white\n",
        "choiceone": "green\n",
        "choicetwo": "blue\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (46).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding position signs have\n",
        "answer": "white inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "red inscriptions on a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an IFR flight plan required?\n",
        "answer": "In Class E airspace when IMC exists or in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "When less than VFR conditions exist in either Class E or Class G airspace and in\nClass A airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In all Class E airspace when conditions are below VFR, in Class A airspace, and in\ndefense zone airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the tower and Flight Control Center (FCC) are located on the same airport, which\nfunction is provided by the FCC during those periods when the tower is closed?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Advisory Service.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach control services.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight time limitations established for flight crewmembers include\n",
        "answer": "all commercial flying in any flight crewmember position.\n",
        "choiceone": "only commercial flying in any flight crewmember position in which operations are\nconducted under the CAA Operation of Aircraft regulations of East Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all flight time, except military, in any flight crew-member position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition, if any, may a pilot descend below DH or MDA when using the\napproach light system as the primary visual reference for the intended runway?\n",
        "answer": "The approach light system can be used as a visual reference, except that descent\nbelow 100 feet above TDZE requires that the red light bars be visible and identifiable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Under no condition can the approach light system serve as a necessary visual\nreference for descent below DH or MDA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent to the intended runway is authorized as long as any portion of the\napproach light system can be seen.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot cancel the IFR flight plan prior to completing the flight?\n",
        "answer": "Only in VFR conditions when not in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only if an emergency occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Preferred IFR routes beginning with a fix indicate that departing\nrouted to the fix by\n\nrcraft will normally be\n",
        "answer": "an instrument departure procedure (DP), or radar vectors.\n",
        "choiceone": "the established airway(s) between the departure airport and the fix.\n",
        "choicetwo": "direct route only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person whose duties include the handling or carriage of dangerous articles and/or\nmagnetized materials must have satisfactorily completed an established and approved\ntraining program within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional flight hours within the preceding 6 calendar months are required to\nmaintain IFR currency in a helicopter?\n",
        "answer": "6 instrument approaches, holding procedures and tracking courses must be\naccomplished.\n",
        "choiceone": "three instrument approaches must also be accomplished.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours of actual or simulated instrument time in the same type helicopter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What service is provided by departure control to an IFR flight when operating within the\nouter area of Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Separation from all IFR aircraft and participating VFR aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Separation from all aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position and altitude of all traffic within 2 miles of the IFR pilot's line of flight and\naltitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) capability, the accuracy of\nthe GPS derived\n",
        "answer": "altitude information should not be relied upon to determine aircraft altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "position is not affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity information should be relied upon to determine aircraft groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When information is disseminated about a taxiway closure, it will be located in\n",
        "answer": "NOTAM (L) distribution.\n",
        "choiceone": "FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM (D) distribution.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When information is disseminated for a navigational facility, it will be located in\n",
        "answer": "NOTAM (D) distribution.\n",
        "choiceone": "FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM (L) distribution.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is contained in the Notices to Airman(NOTAM) Publication ?\n",
        "answer": "Current NOTAM(D) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choiceone": "All Current NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Current NOTAM(L) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "No person may operate an aircraft in simulated instrument flight conditions unless the\n",
        "answer": "other control seat is occupied by a safety pilot, who holds at least a private pilot\ncertificate and is appropriately rated.\n",
        "choiceone": "other control seat is occupied by at least an appropriately rated commercial pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot has filed an IFR flight plan and received an IFR clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless suspended or revoked, a flight engineer licence in East Africa:\n",
        "answer": "expires 1 to 2 years after the month of issuance depending on age\n",
        "choiceone": "is issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choicetwo": "expires at the end of the 24th month following the month of issuance or renewal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air operator may schedule a pilot to fly in an airplane, having two pilots and one\nadditional flight crewmember, for no more than\n",
        "answer": "12 hours during any 24 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-1?\n",
        "answer": "217 knots and 1.81 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "221 knots and 1.83 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "223 knots and 2.01 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within ICAO annex 14, Which is the minimum width of a runway with runway code 4?\n",
        "answer": "45 metres\n",
        "choiceone": "35 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "40 metres\n",
        "choicethree": "50 metres\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (47).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-2?\n",
        "answer": "17,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What colors are runway holding position signs?\n",
        "answer": "White with a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red with a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow with a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 157.) This is an example of\n",
        "answer": "an ILS Critical Area Boundary Sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "an ILS Critical Area Holding Position Sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a Runway Boundary Sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the yellow demarcation bar marking?\n",
        "answer": "Delineates runway with a displaced threshold from a blast pad, stopway or taxiway\nthat precedes the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Delineates entrance to runway from a taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Delineates beginning of runway available for landing when pavement is aligned with\nrunway on approach side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the tower and Flight Control Center (FCC) are located on the same airport, which\nfunction is provided by the FCC during those periods when the tower is closed?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Advisory Service.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach control services.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in Class G airspace in VFR conditions\nduring daylight hours in area 4?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which speed variation should you notify ATC?\n",
        "answer": "When the average true airspeed changes 5 percent or 10 knots, whichever is greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the ground speed changes more than 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time the ground speed changes 10 MPH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot cancel the IFR flight plan prior to completing the flight?\n",
        "answer": "Only in VFR conditions when not in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only if an emergency occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition is guaranteed for all of the following altitude limits: MAA, MCA, MRA,\nMOCA, and MEA? (Non-mountainous area.)\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot obstacle clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Adequate navigation signals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Adequate communications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is primarily responsible for maintait\n",
        "answer": "Owner or operator of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The lead mechanic responsible for that aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot in command or operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When operating a civil aircraft registered in the EAC region, which document is required\nby regulation to be available in the aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "A current, approved Airplane (or Rotorcraft) Flight Manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "A manufacturer's Operations Manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An Owner's Manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating limitations of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane?\n",
        "answer": "No person may operate a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane carrying passengers or\nproperty for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "A \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane is limited to a specified operating radius from its home\nbase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A pilot of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane must hold a commercial pilot certificate when\ncarrying passengers for compensation or hire.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first freedom of the air is:\n",
        "answer": "The right to overfly without landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right to land for a technical stop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The opportunity to operate a commercial flight with passengers on board between\ntwo states.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right to board passengers from the state where the aircraft is registered and to\nfly to an other state.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC has assigned you the transponder code 5320.\nIn case of loosing two way radio communication, you have to squawk:\n",
        "answer": "Mode A Code 7600\n",
        "choiceone": "Mode A Code 5320\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mode A Code 7700\n",
        "choicethree": "Mode A Code 7500\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:\n",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately interrupted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time:\n",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until it stops at\nthe end of the flight (block time).\n",
        "choicetwo": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and temperature on\nthat day.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The centre line and crossbar lights of a precision approach Category | lighting\nsystem shall be fixed lights, showing variable intensity of the following colour:\n",
        "answer": "white\n",
        "choiceone": "green\n",
        "choicetwo": "blue\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (48).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During flight a fire which was extinguished burned the insulation from a transceiver\nwire. What action is required by regulations?\n",
        "answer": "An immediate notification by the operator of the aircraft to the nearest CAA field\noffice.\n",
        "choiceone": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A report must be filed with the avionics inspector at the nearest CAA Flight\nStandards Office\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot, who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS advisory, is\nexpected to notify ATC and\n",
        "answer": "expeditiously return to the ATC clearance in effect prior to the advisory, after the\nconflict is resolved.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request a new ATC clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days must the operator of an aircraft involved in an accident file a\nreport ?\n",
        "answer": "10 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC may assign the MOCA when certain special conditions exist, and when within\n",
        "answer": "22 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-2?\n",
        "answer": "210 knots and 1.51 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "210 knots and 1.57 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 knots and 1.45 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an emergency, a pilot-in-command does not deviate from an CAA regulations\nbut n priority by ATC. To whom or under what condition is the pilot required to\nsubmit a written report?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upon request by ATC, submit a written report to the ATC manager.\n",
        "choiceone": "To the manager of the General Aviation District Office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the manager of the facility in control at the time of the deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition is guaranteed for all of the following altitude limits: MAA, MCA, MRA,\nMOCA, and MEA? (Non-mountainous area.)\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot obstacle clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Adequate navigation signals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Adequate communications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have just landed and the tower tells you to call ground control when clear of the\nrunway. You are considered clear of the runway when\n",
        "answer": "all parts of the aircraft have crossed the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aft end of the aircraft is even with the taxiway location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should pilots state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "When departing from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "When visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When parallel runways are in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'No Entry\u2019 sign identifies\n",
        "answer": "paved area where aircraft entry is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is primarily responsible for maintait\n",
        "answer": "Owner or operator of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The lead mechanic responsible for that aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot in command or operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When approaching taxiway holding lines from the side with the continuous lines, the\npilot\n",
        "answer": "should not cross the lines without ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "may continue taxiing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "should continue taxiing until all parts of the aircraft have crossed the lines.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the yellow demarcation bar marking?\n",
        "answer": "Delineates runway with a displaced threshold from a blast pad, stopway or taxiway\nthat precedes the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Delineates entrance to runway from a taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Delineates beginning of runway available for landing when pavement is aligned with\nrunway on approach side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before beginning any flight under IFR, the pilot in command must become fami\nall available information concerning that flight. In addition, the pilot must\n\n",
        "answer": "be familiar with the runway lengths at airports of intended use, and the alternatives\navailable if the flight cannot be completed.\n",
        "choiceone": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and become familiar with the instrument\napproaches to that airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and confirm adequate takeoff and landing\nperformance at the destination airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of operations over an area designated as a mountainous area where no\nother um altitude is prescribed, no person may operate an aircraft under IFR\nbelow an altitude of\n\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are VFR-On-Top operations prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "In Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "During off-airways direct flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When flying through Class B airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a student pilot\n\n",
        "answer": "17 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "18 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airborne incident would require that the nearest ATS office be notified\nimmediately?\n\n",
        "answer": "Flight control system malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo compartment door malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin door opened in-flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is contained in the Notices to Airman(NOTAM) Publication ?\n",
        "answer": "Current NOTAM(D) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choiceone": "All Current NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Current NOTAM(L) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a two-way radio capable of communicating with ATC on appropriate\nfrequencies, which equipments the helicopter required to have to operate within Class\nB airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An appropriate radar beacon transponder.\n",
        "choiceone": "A VOR or TACAN receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DME, a VOR or TACAN receiver, and an appropriate transponder beacon.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an operator of an aircraft, which has been involved in an incident, required to\nsubmit a report to the nearest ATS office?\n\n",
        "answer": "Only if requested to do so by the responsible authority\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the vertical\nposition of aircraft shall be expressed in term of:\n",
        "answer": "altitude above mean sea level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude above mean sea level at or above the transition altitude\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight level at or below the transition level\n",
        "choicethree": "flight level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Low Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "centimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "metric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "decimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (49).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To operate under IFR below 18,000 feet, a pilot must file an IFR flight plan and receive an\nappropriate ATC clearance prior to.\n",
        "answer": "enter controlled airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "enter weather conditions below VFR minimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "take off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "to be ferried to another base for repair of an\ninoperative engine, which operational requirement must be observed?\n",
        "answer": "Only the required flight crewmembers may be on board the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The existing and forecast weather for departure, en route, and approach must be\nVER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No passengers except authorized maintenance personnel may be carried.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which of the following circumstances will ATC issue a VFR restriction to an IFR\nflight?\n",
        "answer": "When the pilot requests it.\n",
        "choiceone": "Whenever the pilot reports the loss of any navigational aid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When it is necessary to provide separation between IFR and special VFR traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial\nperson does not hold an instrument pilot rating?\n\nplane pilot if that\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 nautical miles (NM).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for\nnight flights, but not limited for day flights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum aircraft equipment is required for operation within Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Two-way communications and Mode C transponder.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two-way commu\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transponder and DME.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To serve as second in command of an airplane that is certificated for more than one\npilot , and operated under the CAA regulations, a person must\n",
        "answer": "within the last 12 months become familiar with the required information, and perform\nand log pilot time in the type of airplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log flight training from an authorized flight instructor in the type of\nairplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold at least a commercial pilot certificate with an airplane category rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lights on a passenger-carrying airplane must be armed or turned on\nduring\n",
        "answer": "taxiing, takeoff, and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "taxiing, takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command must complete a proficiency check or\npreceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rules apply to the pilot in command when operating on a VFR-On-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "VFR and IFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VFR when \u2018in the clear\u2019 and IFR when \u2018in the clouds.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf an unpressurized aircraft is operated between 12,500 feet MSL and 14,000 feet above\nMSL, for a period of 2 hours 20 minutes, how long during that time is the minimum\nflightcrew required to use supplemental oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 50 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours 20 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour 20 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operations by a required cockpit voice recorder\n",
        "answer": "may be erased or obliterated, except the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "must be erased or obliterated, except for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be erased or obliterated, only once each flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How may a pilot satisfy the recent flight experience requirement necessary to act as\npilot in command in IMC in powered aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "six instrument approaches, holding procedures, and intercepting and tracking\ncourses using navigational systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "six instrument approaches and 3 hours under actual or simulated IFR conditions\nwithin the last 6 months; three of the approaches must be in the category of aircraft\ninvolved.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 hours of instrument time under actual or simulated IFR conditions within the last 3\nmonths, including at least six instrument approaches of any kind. Three of the 6\nhours must be in flight in any category aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-5?\n",
        "answer": "218 knots and 1.27 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "219 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "214 knots and 1.26 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot descend below 100 feet above the touchdown zone elevation during a\nCategory Il ILS instrument approach when only the approach lights are visible?\n",
        "answer": "When the red terminal bar of the approach light systems are in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "After passing the visual descent point (VDP).\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR is 1,600 feet or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 71A.) What is your position relative to the Flosi intersection\nNorthbound on V213?\n",
        "answer": "West of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "East of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "West of V213 and past the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) How should a pilot determine when the DME at Price/Carbon\nCounty Airport is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The airborne DME may appear normal, but there will be no code tone.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airborne DME will always indicate \u20180\u00b0 mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne DME will \u2018search,\u2019 but will not \u2018lock on.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is DME required under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet above MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In positive control airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial operator plans to ferry a large, four-engine, reciprocating-engine-powered\nairplane from one facility to another to repair an inoperative engine. Whi\noperational requirement for the three-engine flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weather conditions at the takeoff and destination airports must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The gross weight at takeoff may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum certificated\ngross weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The computed takeoff distance to reach V(1) must not exceed 70 percent of the\neffective runway length.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must be contained in, or attached to, the dispatch release for a\ndomestic flight?\n",
        "answer": "Departure airport, intermediate stops, destinations, alternate airports, and trip\nnumber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Names of all passengers on board and minimum fuel supply.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cargo load, weight and balance data, and identification number of the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have filed an IFR flight plan with a VFR-On-Top clearance in lieu of an assigned\naltitude. If you receive this clearance and fly a course of 180 degrees, at what altitude\nshould you fly? (Assume VFR conditions.)\n",
        "answer": "An even thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any IFR altitude which will enable you to remain in VFR conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An odd thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal range of the tri-color VASI at night?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report should be made to ATC without a specific request when notin radar\ncontact?\n",
        "answer": "When leaving final approach fix inbound on final approach.\n",
        "choiceone": "Entering instrument meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correcting an E.T.A. any time a previous E.T.A. is in error in excess of 2 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot, who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS advisory, is\nexpected to notify ATC and\n",
        "answer": "expeditiously return to the ATC clearance in effect prior to the advisory, after the\nconflict is resolved.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request a new ATC clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is required equipment for powered aircraft during VFR night flights?\n",
        "answer": "An electric landing light if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flashlight with red lens if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sensitive altimeter adjustable for barometric pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to \u201ccommercial operators\" relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "for compensation or hire, engages in the carriage by aircraft in air commerce of\npersons or property, other than as an air carrier.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the owner of a small scheduled airline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "for compensation or hire, engages in the carriage by aircraft in air commerce of\npersons or property, as an air carrier.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air operator may schedule a pilot to fly in an airplane, having two pilots and one\nadditional flight crewmember, for no more than\n",
        "answer": "12 hours during any 24 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) establishes:\n",
        "answer": "standards and recommended international practices for contracting member states.\n",
        "choiceone": "aeronautical standards adopted by all states.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proposals for aeronautical regulations in the form of 18 annexes.\n",
        "choicethree": "standards and recommended practices applied without exception by all states,\nsignatory to the Chicago convention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a pilot in command has reasonable grounds to believe that a person on board\nhas committed or is about to commit, on board the aircraft, an offence against penal law\n",
        "answer": "may deliver such person to the competent authorities\n",
        "choiceone": "may request such person to disembark\n",
        "choicetwo": "may require the assistance of passengers to restrain such person\n",
        "choicethree": "may not require or authorise the assistance of other crew members\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing has:\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).\n",
        "choiceone": "a military aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).\n",
        "choicethree": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate medical attention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway-lead-in lighting shall consist:\n",
        "answer": "of groups of at least three white lights, flashing in sequence towards the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "always of a straight row of lights towards the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of a group of at least 5 flashing yellow lights.\n",
        "choicethree": "of an arbitrary amount of green lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are VFR-On-Top operations prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "In Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "During off-airways direct flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When flying through Class B airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 157.) This is an example of\n",
        "answer": "an ILS Critical Area Boundary Sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "an ILS Critical Area Holding Position Sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a Runway Boundary Sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018taxiway ending\u2019 marker\n",
        "answer": "indicates taxiway does not continue.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When instructed by ATC to \u2018Hold short of a runway (ILS critical area, etc.),\" the pilot\nshould stop\n",
        "answer": "so that no part of the aircraft extends beyond the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the nose gear on the hold line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "so the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a night operation, the pilot of aircraft #1 sees only the green light of aircraft #2. If\nthe aircraft are converging, which pilot has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "#1; aircraft #1 is to the right of aircraft #2.\n",
        "choiceone": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the left of aircraft #1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the right of aircraft #1.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of No Entry sign?\n",
        "answer": "Identifies paved area where aircraft are prohibited from entering.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identifies the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When approaching taxiway holding lines from the side with the continuous lines, the\npilot\n",
        "answer": "should not cross the lines without ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "may continue taxiing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "should continue taxiing until all parts of the aircraft have crossed the lines.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To carry passengers for hire in an airplane on cross-country flights of more than 50 NM\nfrom the departure airport, the pilot in command is required to hold at least\n",
        "answer": "a Commercial Pilot Licence with an instrument rating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a Category Il pilot authorization.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition is pressure altitude and density altitude the same value?\n",
        "answer": "At standard temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the altimeter setting is 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When indicated, and pressure altitudes are the same value on the altimeter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to that\nlicence due to illness, the authority must be informed:\n",
        "answer": "After 21 days of consecutive \"illness\"\n",
        "choiceone": "as soon as possible if the illness is expected to last more than 21days\n",
        "choicetwo": "after one calendar month of consecutive illness\n",
        "choicethree": "if still not fit to fly when his/her current medical certificate expires\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:\n",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "A NOTAM RAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.\n",
        "choicethree": "An Advisory NOTAM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The centre line and crossbar lights of a precision approach Category | lighting\nsystem shall be fixed lights, showing variable intensity of the following colour:\n",
        "answer": "white\n",
        "choiceone": "green\n",
        "choicetwo": "blue\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (50).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018selecting an altitude when operating with a VFR-\n\nOn-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum IFR altitude, minimum distance from clouds, and visibility appropriate to\naltitude selected.\n",
        "choiceone": "At least 500 feet above the lowest MEA, or appropriate MOCA, and at least 1,000 feet\nabove the existing meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At least 1,000 feet above the lowest MEA, appropriate MOCA, or existing\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is required to operate an aircraft towing an advertising banner?\n",
        "answer": "A certificate of waiver issued by the CAA.\n",
        "choiceone": "Approval from ATC to operate in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A safety link at each end of the towline which has a breaking strength not less than\n80% of the aircraft's gross weight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RVR is not reported, what meteorologi\nRVR?\n\nil value should you substitute for 2,400\n",
        "answer": "A ground visibility of 600m.\n",
        "choiceone": "A ground visibility of 400m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slant range visibility of 2,400 feet for the final approach segment of the published\napproach procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum\nbelow 10,000 feet MSL?\n\nicated airspeed a turbine-powered\n\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "288 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An approved cockpit voice recorder is required equipment in\n",
        "answer": "multiengine, turbine-powered airplanes having a passenger seating configuration of\n20 or more seats.\n",
        "choiceone": "large turbine-powered airplanes having a maximum passenger capacity of 20 or\nmore seats.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all aircraft operated in commuter air carrier service having a passenger seating\nconfiguration of 20 seats or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are necessary before ATC can authorize a visual approach?\n",
        "answer": "You must have the airport in sight or a preceding aircraft to be followed, and be able\nto proceed to the airport in VFR conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "You must have the preceding aircraft in sight, and be able to remain in VFR weather\nconditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You must have the airport in sight or the preceding aircraft in sight, and be able to\nproceed to, and land in IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum weather conditions that must be forecast to list an airport as an\nalternate when the airport has no approved IAP?\n",
        "answer": "The ceiling and visibility at ETA must allow descent from MEA, approach, and\nlanding, under basic VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ceiling and visibility at ETA, 2,000 feet and 3 miles, respectively.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ceiling and visibility from 2 hours before until 2 hours after ETA, 2,000 feet and 3\nmiles, respectively.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot descend below 100 feet above the touchdown zone elevation during a\nCategory Il ILS instrument approach when only the approach lights are visible?\n",
        "answer": "When the red terminal bar of the approach light systems are in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "After passing the visual descent point (VDP).\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR is 1,600 feet or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pilot-in-command or second-in-command time used to satisfy the aeronautical\nexperience requirements for the flight engineer licence must have been obtained on\n",
        "answer": "a transport category airplane or equivalent military airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "an airplane on which a flight engineer is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at least a three-engine transport, if turbojet-powered.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the upper limit for Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "60,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to carrying passengers at night, the pilot in command must have accom,\nrequired takeoffs and landings in\n",
        "answer": "the same category, class, and type of aircraft (if a type rating is required).\n",
        "choiceone": "any category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same category and class of aircraft to be used.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If weather conditions are such that it is required to designate an alternate airport on\nyour IFR flight plan, you should plan to carry enough fuel to arrive at the first airport of\nintended landing, fly from that airport to the alternate airport, and fly thereafter for\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes at slow cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the forecast weather conditions for a destination and alternate airport are\nconsidered marginal for a domestic air operation, what specific action should the pilot\nin command take?\n\n",
        "answer": "List at least one additional alternate airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "List an airport where the forecast weather is not marginal as the alternate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 1 additional hour of fuel based on cruise power settings for the airplane in use.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the lan:\nRWY 4R approach at BOS?\n\nig distance available for the VOR/DME RNAV\n",
        "answer": "8,850 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "7.000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10,005 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pilot in command of a civil aircraft must have an instrument rating only when\noperating\n",
        "answer": "under IFR, in weather conditions less than the minimum for VFR flight, and in a Class\nA airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "under IFR in positive control airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in weather conditions less than the minimum prescribed for VFR flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n25,000 pounds? |Initial weight: 179,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 136,500 Ib\n",
        "answer": "8 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) capability, the accuracy of\nthe GPS derived\n",
        "answer": "altitude information should not be relied upon to determine aircraft altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "position is not affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity information should be relied upon to determine aircraft groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The required preflight action relative to weather reports and fuel requirements is\napplicable to\n",
        "answer": "any flight not in the vicinity of an airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "any flight conducted for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR flights only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cockpit voice recorder must be operated\n",
        "answer": "from the start of the before starting engine checklist to completion of final checklist\nupon termination of flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "from the start of the before starting engine checklist to completion of checklist prior\nto engine shutdown.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when starting to taxi for takeoff to the engine shutdown checklist after termination of\nthe flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report should be made to ATC without a specific request when notin radar\ncontact?\n",
        "answer": "When leaving final approach fix inbound on final approach.\n",
        "choiceone": "Entering instrument meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correcting an E.T.A. any time a previous E.T.A. is in error in excess of 2 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an off-airways IFR flight over nonmountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 SM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What restrictions must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment of an airplane operated under the CAA regulations in an east african\nstate?\n",
        "answer": "Cargo may be carried aft of a divider if properly secured by a safety belt or other\ntiedown devices to withstand certain load stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "All cargo must be separated from the passengers by a partition capable of\nwithstanding certain load stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable flame resistant bin and the bin must be\nsecured to the floor structure of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when necessary for takeoff or landing or unless otherwise authorized by the\nCAA, the minimum altitude for IFR flight is\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle over designated mountainous terrain;\nfeet above the highest obstacle over terrain elsewhere.\n\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet over all terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,000 feet over designated mountainous terrain; 2,000 feet over terrain elsewhere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ing altitude is appropriate for VFR on Top on a westbound flight below 18,000\n\n",
        "answer": "Even thousand-foot levels plus 500 feet, but not below MEA.\n",
        "choiceone": "Even thousand-foot levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Odd thousand-foot levels plus 500 feet, but not below MEA.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the vertical\nposition of aircraft shall be expressed in term of:\n",
        "answer": "altitude above mean sea level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude above mean sea level at or above the transition altitude\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight level at or below the transition level\n",
        "choicethree": "flight level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (51).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the latest date that a flight engineer in East Africa may perform duties\nif his or her last medical examination was a first-class conducted on August 25, 1999?\n",
        "answer": "August 24, 2000.\n",
        "choiceone": "September 30, 2000.\n",
        "choicetwo": "August 31, 2000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf an unpressurized aircraft is operated between 12,500 feet MSL and 14,000 feet above\nMSL, for a period of 2 hours 20 minutes, how long during that time is the minimum\nflightcrew required to use supplemental oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 50 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours 20 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour 20 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "MEA is an altitude which assures\n",
        "answer": "acceptable navigational signal coverage and meets obstruction clearance\nrequirements.\n",
        "choiceone": "obstacle clearance, accurate navigational signals from more than one VORTAC, and\naccurate DME mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a 1,000-foot obstacle clearance within 2 miles of an airway and assures accurate\nDME mileage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the purpose of REIL?\n",
        "answer": "Identification of a runway surrounded by a preponderance of other lighting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identification of the touchdown zone to prevent landing short.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Establish visual descent guidance information during an approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless a higher speed is required due to turbulence or icing and ATC is notified, the\nmaximum holding speed for a civil turbojet holding at a civil airport at 18,000 feet above\nMSL is:\n",
        "answer": "265 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "250 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft's transponder fails during flight within Class D airspace.\n",
        "answer": "No deviation is required because a transponder is not required in Class D airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot should immediately request clearance to depart the Class D airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot must immediately request priority handling to proceed to destination.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft's operation in flight was substantially affected by an alteration or repair, the\naircraft documents must show that it was test flown and approved for return to service\nby an appropriately-rated pilot prior to being operated\n",
        "answer": "with passengers aboard.\n",
        "choiceone": "under VFR or IFR rules.\n",
        "choicetwo": "for compensation or hire.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does a pilot normally obtain the current altimeter setting during an IFR flight in\nClass E airspace below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "ATC periodically advises the pilot of the proper altimeter setting.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot should contact ARTCC at least every 100 NM and request the altimeter\nsetting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Control Centers along the route broadcast the weather information at 15\nminutes past the hour.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "served in the same capacity on other airplanes of the same group is\n",
        "answer": "transition training.\n",
        "choiceone": "difference training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "upgrade training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for determining that the altimeter system has been checked and\nfound to meet safety requirements for a particular instrument flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Owner.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a commercial airtransport airplane lands at an intermediate airport at 1822Z, what\nis the latest time it may continue a flight without receiving a redispatch authorization?\n",
        "answer": "00222.\n",
        "choiceone": "1922Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1952Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of Flight Data Computer (FDC) NOTAMs?-\n",
        "answer": "To advise of changes in flight data which affect instrument approach procedure\n(IAP), aeronautical charts, and flight restrictions prior to normal publication.\n",
        "choiceone": "To provide the latest information on the status of navigation facilities to all flight\ncontrol center facilities for scheduled broadcasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To issue notices for all airports and navigation facilities in the shortest possible time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum qualifications for a person who occupies the other control seat\nas safety pilot during simulated instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot certificate with appropriate category and class ratings for the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Private pilot with instrument rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Private pilot with appropriate category, class, and instrument ratings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "req!\nexperience requirements to act as pilot in command of an airplane under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Four instrument approaches in an airplane, or an approved airplane flight simulator\nor training device.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three hours of simulated or actual instrument flight time in a helicopter and two\ninstrument approaches in an airplane or helicopter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three instrument approaches in an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a temporary replacement is received for an airman's medi\nmaximum time is this document valid?\n\nil certificate, for what\n",
        "answer": "45 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For helicopters, what jum conditions must exist at the destination airport to avoid\nlisting an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a standard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From the ETA to 1 hour after the ETA, reports and forecasts indicate a ceiling 1,000\nfeet above the airport elevation, or at least 400 feet above the lowest applicable\napproach minima, whichever is higher, and visibility 2 statute miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, reports and forecasts indicate a ceiling of\n1,000 feet above the airport elevation and visibility 2 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft for domestic flight has a delay while on the ground, at an intermediate\nairport. How long before a redispatch release is required?\n",
        "answer": "Not more than 1 hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Not more than 2 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 6 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reach a weight of\n151,500 pounds?|Initial weight: 181,500 Ib[Zero fuel weight: 126,000 Ib\n",
        "answer": "13 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight attendant crewmember is required on aircraft having a passenger seating\nconfiguration, excluding any pilot seat, of\n",
        "answer": "20 or more\n",
        "choiceone": "15 or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19 or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the localizer, glide slope, marker beacons, approach lighting, and HIRL,\nwhich ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il instrument\napproach to a DH below 150 feet AGL?\n",
        "answer": "TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane that is equipped with retractable landing gear,\nflaps, and controllable-pitch propeller, a person is required to\n",
        "answer": "receive and log ground and flight training in such an airplane, and obtain a logbook\nendorsement certifying proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "make at least six takeoffs and landings in such an airplane within the preceding 6\nmonths.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold a multiengine airplane class rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum number of hours that a supplemental airline pilot may fly, as a\ncrewmember, in a commercial operation, in any 30 consecutive days is\n",
        "answer": "100 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "120 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "300 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an IFR off-airways flight over mountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within a horizontal distance of 5 NM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7,500 feet above the highest obstacle within a horizontal distance of 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial operator plans to ferry a large, four-engine, reciprocating-engine-powered\nairplane from one facility to another to repair an inoperative engine. Whi\noperational requirement for the three-engine flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weather conditions at the takeoff and destination airports must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The gross weight at takeoff may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum certificated\ngross weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The computed takeoff distance to reach V(1) must not exceed 70 percent of the\neffective runway length.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the climb-out phase of a flight the pilot-in-command becomes incapacitated.\nThe co-pilot takes over control of the aircraft and decides that he will return for landing.\nWhat action has to be taken after landing?\n",
        "answer": "This is a serious incident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an incident.\n",
        "choiceone": "This is an accident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an accident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation.\nThe operator must inform the Authority by writing an Irregularity Report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an irregularity.\nThe pilot-in-command or the Operator must deposit a report on behalf of the\ninvolved airport Authority within the following 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (52).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight training device and/or approved flight\nsimulator, the applicant is\n",
        "answer": "required to have a first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have at least a third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not required to have a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lights on a passenger-carrying airplane must be armed or turned on\nduring\n",
        "answer": "taxiing, takeoff, and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "taxiing, takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding position signs have\n",
        "answer": "white inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "red inscriptions on a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the maximum altitude that Class G airspace will exist?\n(Does not include airspace less than 1,500 feet AGL.)\n",
        "answer": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What recent experience is required to be eligible for the practical test for the original\nissue of a Category Il authorization?\n",
        "answer": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches, three of which may be flown to\nthe Category | DH.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches flown manually to the Category |\nDH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the previous 12 calendar months, six ILS approaches flown by use of an\napproach coupler to the Category | or Category Il DH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the line check requirements for the pilot in command for a domestic air carrier?\n",
        "answer": "The line check is required every 12 calendar months in one of the types of airplanes\nto be flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The line check is required only when the pilot is scheduled to fly into special areas\nand airports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line check is required every 12 months in each type aircraft in which the pilot\nmay fly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A coded transponder equipped with altitude reporting capabil\ncontrolled airspace\n\nis required in all\n",
        "answer": "at and above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "at and above 2,500 feet above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operation of a cockpit voice recorder in a large\npressurized airplane with four reciprocating engines\n",
        "answer": "may all be erasedexcept for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "may be erased except for the last 30 minutes prior to landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may all be erased, as the voice recorder is not required on an aircraft with\nreciprocating engines.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a definition of the term \u2018crewmember\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "A person assigned to perform duty in an aircraft during flight time.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only a pilot, flight engineer, or flight navigator assigned to duty in an aircraft during\nflight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any person assigned to duty in an aircraft during flight except a pilot or flight\nengineer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial pilot - airplane, if that\nperson does not hold an instrument rating? The carriage of passengers\n",
        "answer": "for hire on cross-country flights in excess of 50 NM or for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for night flights, but not limited for\nday flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is limited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 71A.) What is your position relative to the Flosi intersection\nNorthbound on V213?\n",
        "answer": "West of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "East of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "West of V213 and past the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acommercial pilot in command in EAC is required to hold a type rating?\n",
        "answer": "When operating any aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating an aircraft having a gross weight of more than 12,500 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When operating a multiengine aircraft having a gross weight of more than 6,000\npounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command must complete a proficiency check or\npreceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the normal upper limit for Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 130.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot flying a single-engine airplane observes a multiengine airplane approaching from\nthe left. Which pilot should give way?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot of the multiengine airplane should give way\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot of the single-engine airplane should give way\n",
        "choicetwo": "Each pilot should alter course to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum fuel requirements in IFR conditions, i\nlanding is forecast to have a 1,500-foot ceiling and 3 miles vi\nETA? Fuel to fly to the first airport of intended landing,\n\nthe first airport of intended\nity at flight-planned\n",
        "answer": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the minimum safe speed for any particular operation is greater than the maximum\nspeed prescribed in EAC states\u2019 Regulations\n\n",
        "answer": "aircraft may be operated at that speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "operator must have a Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) with the controlling agency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operator must have a Letter of Agreement with ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight attendant crewmember is required on aircraft having a passenger seating\nconfiguration, excluding any pilot seat, of\n",
        "answer": "20 or more\n",
        "choiceone": "15 or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19 or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an operational check on the aircraft VOR equipment be accomplished when\nused to operate under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the preceding 10 days or 10 hours of flight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the preceding 30 days or 30 hours of flight time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Preferred IFR routes beginning with a fix indicate that departing\nrouted to the fix by\n\nrcraft will normally be\n",
        "answer": "an instrument departure procedure (DP), or radar vectors.\n",
        "choiceone": "the established airway(s) between the departure airport and the fix.\n",
        "choicetwo": "direct route only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with the Operation of Aircraft regulations in the EAC, supplemental\noxygen must be used by the required minimum flightcrew for that time exceeding 30\nminutes while at cabin pressure altitude\n",
        "answer": "12,500 feet MSL up to and including 1,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,500 feet MSL up to and including 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12,000 feet MSL up to and including 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oxygen requirement for an unpressurized aircraft at 15,000 feet under the\nOperation of Aircraft regulations in East Africa?\n",
        "answer": "Crew must start using oxygen at 12,000 feet and passengers at 14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "All occupants must use oxygen for the entire time at this altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew must use oxygen for the entire time above 14,000 feet and passengers must be\nprovided supplemental oxygen only above 15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you obtain the pressure altitude on flights below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Set your altimeter to 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choiceone": "Use your computer to change the indicated altitude to pressure altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Contact an FSS and ask for the pressure altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an air carrier airplane be DME equipped?\n",
        "answer": "Whenever VOR navigational receivers are required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In Class E airspace for all IFR or VFR on Top operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For flights at or above FL 180.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:\n",
        "answer": "Control zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Changing of flight rules from IFR to VFR is possible\n",
        "answer": "If the commander so requests\n",
        "choiceone": "If instructed by ATC so long as VMC is forecasted during the next 30 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "If instructed by ATC so long as VMC is forecasted during the next 60 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when leaving controlled airspace\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (53).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have filed an IFR flight plan with a VFR-On-Top clearance in lieu of an assigned\naltitude. If you receive this clearance and fly a course of 180 degrees, at what altitude\nshould you fly? (Assume VFR conditions.)\n",
        "answer": "An even thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any IFR altitude which will enable you to remain in VFR conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An odd thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To serve as second in command of an airplane that is certificated for more than one\npilot , and operated under the CAA regulations, a person must\n",
        "answer": "within the last 12 months become familiar with the required information, and perform\nand log pilot time in the type of airplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log flight training from an authorized flight instructor in the type of\nairplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold at least a commercial pilot certificate with an airplane category rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What is the approximate fuel consumed when holding\nunder Operating Conditions 0-3?\n",
        "answer": "2,940 pounds.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,520 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,250 pounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial operator plans to ferry a large, four-engine, reciprocating-engine-powered\nairplane from one facility to another to repair an inoperative engine. Whi\noperational requirement for the three-engine flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weather conditions at the takeoff and destination airports must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The gross weight at takeoff may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum certificated\ngross weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The computed takeoff distance to reach V(1) must not exceed 70 percent of the\neffective runway length.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is a pilot on an IFR flight plan responsible for avoiding other aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "When weather conditions permit, regardless of whether operating under IFR or VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "At all times when notin radar contact with ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when advised by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the purpose of REIL?\n",
        "answer": "Identification of a runway surrounded by a preponderance of other lighting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identification of the touchdown zone to prevent landing short.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Establish visual descent guidance information during an approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When departing from an airport located outside controlled airspace during IMC, you\nmust file an IFR flight plan and receive a clearance before\n",
        "answer": "entering Class E airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "takeoff.\n",
        "choicetwo": "entering IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL under special VFR during\ndaylight hours in area 5?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 mile; (I) 2,000 feet; (J) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Portable electronic devices which may cause interference with the navigation or\ncommunication system may not be operated on an civil aircraft registered in an EAC\nstate being flown\n",
        "answer": "in air carrier operations.\n",
        "choiceone": "along route airways.\n",
        "choicetwo": "within the EAC\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n16,000 pounds?IInitial weight: 175,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 138,000 Ib\n",
        "answer": "9 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airborne incident would require that the nearest ATS office be notified\nimmediately?\n\n",
        "answer": "Flight control system malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo compartment door malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin door opened in-flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to the operational control of a flight are in relation to\n",
        "answer": "ercising authority over initiating, conducting, or terminating a flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "the specific duties of any required crewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "acting as the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, except by arrangement with the pilot in command of each aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC may assign the MOCA when certain special conditions exist, and when within\n",
        "answer": "22 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How often must a crewmember actually operate the airplane emergency equipment,\n\n",
        "answer": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A dispatch release for a domestic flight must contain or have attached to it\n",
        "answer": "minimum fuel supply and weather information for the complete flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "trip number and weight and balance data.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weather information for the complete flight and a crew list.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, the pilot in command in East africa shall to hold a type\nrating when operating any\n",
        "answer": "aircraft of more than 12,500 pounds maximum certificated takeoff weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft that is certificated for more than one pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "multiengine airplane having a gross weight of more than 12,000 pounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An abbreviated departure clearance '...CLEARED AS FILED...\u2019 will always con\u2019\nname\n",
        "answer": "of the destination airport filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "and number of the STAR to be flown when filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of the first compulsory reporting point if not in a radar environment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in\nClass G airspace during daylight hours for area 2?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-On-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1200 feet AGL). What is the in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operation in Class E airspace during daylight hours for area 1?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "By regulation, who shall provide the pilot in command of a domestic operations\ninformation concerning weather, and irregularities of facilities and services?\n\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person whose duties include the handling or carriage of dangerous articles and/or\nmagnetized materials must have satisfactorily completed an established and approved\ntraining program within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airspace is defined as a transition area when designated in conjunction with an\nairport which has a prescribed IAP?\n\n",
        "answer": "The Class E airspace extending upward from 700 feet or more above the surface and\nterminating at the base of the overlying controlled airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "That Class D airspace extending from the surface and terminating at the base of the\ncontinental control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Class C airspace extending from the surface to 700 or 1,200 feet AGL, where\ndesignated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 78 and 79.) What is your position relative to the VOR COP southeast\nbound on V86 between the BOZEMAN and LIVINGSTON VORTACs? The No. 1 VOR is\ntuned to 116.1 and the No. 2 VOR is tuned to 112.2.\n",
        "answer": "Past the LVM R-246 and east of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choiceone": "Past the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approaching the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless a higher speed is required due to turbulence or icing and ATC is notified, the\nmaximum holding speed for a civil turbojet holding at a civil airport at 18,000 feet above\nMSL is:\n",
        "answer": "265 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "250 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is required to submit a written report on a deviation that occurs during an\nemergency?\n",
        "answer": "Person who declares the emergency.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatcher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC has assigned you the transponder code 5320.\nIn case of loosing two way radio communication, you have to squawk:\n",
        "answer": "Mode A Code 7600\n",
        "choiceone": "Mode A Code 5320\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mode A Code 7700\n",
        "choicethree": "Mode A Code 7500\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (54).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a gyroplane carrying passengers, what must the pilot\naccomplish in that gyroplane to meet recent daytime flight experience requirements?\n",
        "answer": "Make three takeoffs and landings within the preceding 90 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Make nine takeoffs and landings within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Make three takeoffs and landings to a full stop within the preceding 90 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial pilot - airplane, if that\nperson does not hold an instrument rating? The carriage of passengers\n",
        "answer": "for hire on cross-country flights in excess of 50 NM or for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for night flights, but not limited for\nday flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is limited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an instrument approach, under what conditions, if any, is the holding pattern\ncourse reversal not required?\n",
        "answer": "When radar vectors are provided.\n",
        "choiceone": "When cleared for the approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "None, since it is always mandatory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What type of entry is recommended to the missed approach\nholding pattern if the inbound heading is 050 degrees?\n",
        "answer": "Teardrop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Parallel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 133.) What is the minimum altitude descent procedure if cleared for the\nS4LS 9 approach from Seal Beach VORTAC?\n",
        "answer": "Descend and maintain 3,000 to JASER INT, descend to 2,500 while established on\nthe LOC course inbound, intercept and maintain the GS to 991 (DH).\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend and maintain 3,000 to JASER INT, descend to and maintain 2,500 until\ncrossing SWAN LAKE, descend and maintain 1,260 until crossing AGNES, and to\n991 (DH) after passing AGNES.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descend and maintain 3,000 to JASER INT, descend to 2,800 when established on\nthe LOC course, intercept and maintain the GS to 991 (DH).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airplanes are required to be equipped with a ground proximity warning glide\nslope deviation alerting system?\n",
        "answer": "All turbine powered airplanes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Passenger-carrying turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Large turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum amount of flight instruction an authorized instructor may give in\nany 24 consecutive hours?\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "Regulations hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude and route should be used if the pilot is flying in IFR weather conditions\nand has two-way radio communications failure?\n",
        "answer": "Continue on the route specified in the clearance and fly the highest of the following:\nthe last assigned altitude, altitude ATC has informed the pilot to expect, or to the\nmaximum Elevation Altitude( MEA)\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend to MEA and, if clear of clouds, proceed to the nearest appropriate airport. If\nnot clear of clouds, maintain the highest of the MEAs along the clearance route.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly the most direct route to the destination, maintaining the last assigned altitude or\nMEA, whichever is higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When operating under IFR with a VFR-On-Top clearance, what altitude should be\nmaintained?\n",
        "answer": "A VFR cruising altitude appropriate to the magnetic course being flown and as\nrestricted by ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "The last IFR altitude assigned by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An IFR cruising altitude appropriate to the magnetic course being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operation of a cockpit voice recorder in a large\npressurized airplane with four reciprocating engines\n",
        "answer": "may all be erasedexcept for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "may be erased except for the last 30 minutes prior to landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may all be erased, as the voice recorder is not required on an aircraft with\nreciprocating engines.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a requirement governing the carriage of cargo, on a scheduled passenger\nflight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Cargo must be carried in an approved rack, bin, or compartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo not stowed in an approved bin must be secured by a safety belt or approved\ntiedown device.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo carried in the passenger compartment must be packaged and stowed\nahead of the foremost seated passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "By regulation, who shall provide the pilot in command of a domestic operations\ninformation concerning weather, and irregularities of facilities and services?\n\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which service is provided for IFR arrivals by a Flight Control Center( FCC) located on an\nairport without a control tower?\n\n",
        "answer": "Airport advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All functions of approach control.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine the pressure altitude on an airport without a tower or Flight\nControl Center?\n",
        "answer": "Set the altimeter to 29.92\" Hg and read the altitude indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Set the altimeter to the current altimeter setting of a station within 100 miles and\ncorrect this indicated altitude with local temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Use your computer and correct the field elevation for temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what time period should the nearest ATS office be notified when an aircraft is\ninvolved in an accident which results in substantial damage?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 calendar days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are certain areas that start 3 nautical miles from the coastline of the EAC. and\nextend outward, classified as Warning Areas?\n",
        "answer": "To warn pilots of nonparticipating aircraft of a potential danger within the area.\n",
        "choiceone": "To inform pilots of participating aircraft to maintain extreme vigilance while\nconducting flight within the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To warn all aircraft pilots that flying within the area may be extremely hazardous to\naircraft and occupants.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What period of time must a person be hospitalized before an injury may be defined as a\n\u2018serious injury\"?\n",
        "answer": "48 hours; commencing within 7 days after date of the injury.\n",
        "choiceone": "72 hours; commencing within 10 days after date of injury.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days, with no other extenuating circumstances.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which passenger announcement(s) must be made after each takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "Passengers should keep seat belts fastened while seated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Keep safety belts fastened while seated and no smoking in the aircraft lavatories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "How to use the passenger oxygen system and that there is a $1,000 fine for\ntampering with a smoke detector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal range of the tri-color VASI at night?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 89.) What are the oxygen requirements for an IFR flight northeast bound\nfrom Bryce Canyon on V382 at the lowest appropriate altitude in an unpressurized\naircraft?\n",
        "answer": "The required minimum crew must be provided and use supplemental oxygen, and all\noccupants must be provided supplemental oxygen for the entire flight above 15,000\nfeet.\n",
        "choiceone": "The required minimum crew must be provided and use supplemental oxygen for that\npart of the flight of more than 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The required minimum crew must be provided and use supplemental oxygen for that\npart of the flight of more than 30 minutes, and the passengers must be provided\nsupplemental oxygen.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 124.) A pilot receives this ATC clearance:|'..CLEARED TO THE ABC\n\nVORTAC. HOLD SOUTH ON THE ONE EIGHT ZERO RADIAL..\"|Whatis the\nrecommended procedure to enter the holding pattern?\n",
        "answer": "Teardrop only.\n",
        "choiceone": "Parallel only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is required prior to takeoff if snow is adhering to the wings of an air carrier\nairplane?\n",
        "answer": "Ensure that the snow is removed from the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweep off as much snow as possible and the residue must be polished smooth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 15 knots to the normal V(R) speed as the snow will blow off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the preparation of a required load manifest?\n",
        "answer": "The certificate holder.\n",
        "choiceone": "PIC or the Dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Company official designated by the Administrator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whatis a difference between an SDF and an Localizer type Directional Aid(LDA) facility?\n",
        "answer": "The SDF course width is either 6 degrees or 12 degrees while the LDA course width\nis approximately 5 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "The SDF course has no glide slope guidance while the LDA does.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The SDF has no marker beacons while the LDA has at least an OM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the position of LABER relative to the reference facility?\n",
        "answer": "198 degrees , 8 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "316 degrees, 24.3 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "177 degrees , 10 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the floor of Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum certificate and rating requirements for the pilot in command of a\nturbojet airplane with two engines being operated by a Commuter Air Carrier as defined\nin the Operation of aircraft regulations in the East African region.\n",
        "answer": "Airline transport pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; airplane type\nrating, if required.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airline transport pilot of any category; multiengine class rating; airplane type rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; instrument rating;\nairplane type rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (55).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pilot elects to proceed to the selected alternate, the lan\nairport should be the\n\nimums used at that\n",
        "answer": "minimums specified for the approach procedure selected.\n",
        "choiceone": "alternate minimums shown on the approach chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "minimums shown for that airport in a separate listing of 'IFR Alternate Minimums.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, the tow pilot is required to\nhave\n",
        "answer": "a logbook endorsement from an authorized glider instructor certifying receipt of\nground and flight training in gliders, and be proficient with techniques and\nprocedures for safe towing of gliders.\n",
        "choiceone": "at least a private pilot certificate with a category rating for powered aircraft, and\nmade and logged at least three flights as pilot or observer in a glider being towed by\nan airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a logbook record of having made at least three flights as sole manipulator of the\ncontrols of a glider being towed by an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the normal upper limit for Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The required preflight action relative to weather reports and fuel requirements is\napplicable to\n",
        "answer": "any flight not in the vicinity of an airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "any flight conducted for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR flights only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude may a pilot select upon receiving a VFR-On-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Any appropriate VFR altitude at or above the MEA in VFR weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any altitude at least 1,000 feet above the meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any VFR altitude appropriate for the direction of flight at least 1,000 feet above the\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a commercial pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft\nfor compensation or hire, if that person\n",
        "answer": "is qualified in accordance with EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nwith the applicable parts that apply to the operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "holds appropriate category, class ratings, and meets the recent flight experience\nrequirements of EAC states' Personnel Licensing regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is qualified in accordance with the EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nhas passed a pilot competency check given by an authorized check pilot.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A dispatch release for a domestic flight must contain or have attached to it\n",
        "answer": "minimum fuel supply and weather information for the complete flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "trip number and weight and balance data.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weather information for the complete flight and a crew list.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum navigation equipment is required for IFR flight?\n",
        "answer": "Navigation equipment appropriate to the ground facilities to be used.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORILOC receiver, transponder, and DME.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR receiver and, if in ARTS Ill environment, a coded transponder equipped for\naltitude reporting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight training device and/or approved flight\nsimulator, the applicant is\n",
        "answer": "required to have a first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have at least a third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not required to have a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When instructed by ATC to \u2018Hold short of a runway (ILS critical area, etc.),\" the pilot\nshould stop\n",
        "answer": "so that no part of the aircraft extends beyond the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the nose gear on the hold line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "so the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot-in-command of an airplane with more than 200 horsepower, a person is\nrequired to\n",
        "answer": "receive and log ground and flight training from an authorized instructor in such an\nairplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log ground and flight training from a qualified pilot in such an airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "obtain an endorsement from a qualified pilot stating that the person is proficient to\noperate such an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recommended entry position to an airport traffic pattern is\n",
        "answer": "to enter 45 degrees at the midpoint of the downwind leg at traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "45 degrees to the base leg just below traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to cross directly over the airport at traffic pattern altitude and join the downwind leg.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the latest date that a flight engineer in East Africa may perform duties\nif his or her last medical examination was a first-class conducted on August 25, 1999?\n",
        "answer": "August 24, 2000.\n",
        "choiceone": "September 30, 2000.\n",
        "choicetwo": "August 31, 2000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the maximum altitude that Class G airspace will exist?\n(Does not include airspace less than 1,500 feet AGL.)\n",
        "answer": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 138.) What night operations, if any, are authorized between the\napproach end of the runway and the threshold lights?\n",
        "answer": "Taxi and takeoff operations are permitted, providing the takeoff operations are\ntoward the visible green threshold lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "No aircraft operations are permitted short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only taxi operations are permitted in the area short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With regard to flight crewmember duties, which of the following operations are\nconsidered to be in the \u2018critical phase of flight\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Taxi, takeoff, landing, and all other operations conducted below 10,000 feet,\nexcluding cruise flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "Taxi, takeoff, landing, and all other operations conducted below 10,000 feet MSL,\nincluding cruise flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent, approach, landing, and taxi operations, irrespective of altitudes MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an off-airways IFR flight over nonmountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 SM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:\n",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.\n",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.\n",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Member states should introduce specific security measures for the air transport of the\nfollowing groups of potentially disruptive passengers defined below:\n",
        "answer": "Deportees, inadmissible persons and persons in lawful custody\n",
        "choiceone": "Deportees and persons in lawful custody only\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deportees and inadmissible persons only\n",
        "choicethree": "None of the answers is correct\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (56).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To operate under IFR below 18,000 feet, a pilot must file an IFR flight plan and receive an\nappropriate ATC clearance prior to.\n",
        "answer": "enter controlled airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "enter weather conditions below VFR minimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "take off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "to be ferried to another base for repair of an\ninoperative engine, which operational requirement must be observed?\n",
        "answer": "Only the required flight crewmembers may be on board the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The existing and forecast weather for departure, en route, and approach must be\nVER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No passengers except authorized maintenance personnel may be carried.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which of the following circumstances will ATC issue a VFR restriction to an IFR\nflight?\n",
        "answer": "When the pilot requests it.\n",
        "choiceone": "Whenever the pilot reports the loss of any navigational aid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When it is necessary to provide separation between IFR and special VFR traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial\nperson does not hold an instrument pilot rating?\n\nplane pilot if that\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 nautical miles (NM).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for\nnight flights, but not limited for day flights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum aircraft equipment is required for operation within Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Two-way communications and Mode C transponder.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two-way commu\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transponder and DME.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To serve as second in command of an airplane that is certificated for more than one\npilot , and operated under the CAA regulations, a person must\n",
        "answer": "within the last 12 months become familiar with the required information, and perform\nand log pilot time in the type of airplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log flight training from an authorized flight instructor in the type of\nairplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold at least a commercial pilot certificate with an airplane category rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lights on a passenger-carrying airplane must be armed or turned on\nduring\n",
        "answer": "taxiing, takeoff, and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "taxiing, takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command must complete a proficiency check or\npreceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rules apply to the pilot in command when operating on a VFR-On-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "VFR and IFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VFR when \u2018in the clear\u2019 and IFR when \u2018in the clouds.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf an unpressurized aircraft is operated between 12,500 feet MSL and 14,000 feet above\nMSL, for a period of 2 hours 20 minutes, how long during that time is the minimum\nflightcrew required to use supplemental oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 50 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours 20 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour 20 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operations by a required cockpit voice recorder\n",
        "answer": "may be erased or obliterated, except the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "must be erased or obliterated, except for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be erased or obliterated, only once each flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How may a pilot satisfy the recent flight experience requirement necessary to act as\npilot in command in IMC in powered aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "six instrument approaches, holding procedures, and intercepting and tracking\ncourses using navigational systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "six instrument approaches and 3 hours under actual or simulated IFR conditions\nwithin the last 6 months; three of the approaches must be in the category of aircraft\ninvolved.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 hours of instrument time under actual or simulated IFR conditions within the last 3\nmonths, including at least six instrument approaches of any kind. Three of the 6\nhours must be in flight in any category aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-5?\n",
        "answer": "218 knots and 1.27 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "219 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "214 knots and 1.26 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot descend below 100 feet above the touchdown zone elevation during a\nCategory Il ILS instrument approach when only the approach lights are visible?\n",
        "answer": "When the red terminal bar of the approach light systems are in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "After passing the visual descent point (VDP).\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR is 1,600 feet or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 71A.) What is your position relative to the Flosi intersection\nNorthbound on V213?\n",
        "answer": "West of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "East of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "West of V213 and past the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) How should a pilot determine when the DME at Price/Carbon\nCounty Airport is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The airborne DME may appear normal, but there will be no code tone.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airborne DME will always indicate \u20180\u00b0 mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne DME will \u2018search,\u2019 but will not \u2018lock on.\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is DME required under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet above MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In positive control airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial operator plans to ferry a large, four-engine, reciprocating-engine-powered\nairplane from one facility to another to repair an inoperative engine. Whi\noperational requirement for the three-engine flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weather conditions at the takeoff and destination airports must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The gross weight at takeoff may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum certificated\ngross weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The computed takeoff distance to reach V(1) must not exceed 70 percent of the\neffective runway length.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must be contained in, or attached to, the dispatch release for a\ndomestic flight?\n",
        "answer": "Departure airport, intermediate stops, destinations, alternate airports, and trip\nnumber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Names of all passengers on board and minimum fuel supply.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cargo load, weight and balance data, and identification number of the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have filed an IFR flight plan with a VFR-On-Top clearance in lieu of an assigned\naltitude. If you receive this clearance and fly a course of 180 degrees, at what altitude\nshould you fly? (Assume VFR conditions.)\n",
        "answer": "An even thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any IFR altitude which will enable you to remain in VFR conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An odd thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal range of the tri-color VASI at night?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report should be made to ATC without a specific request when notin radar\ncontact?\n",
        "answer": "When leaving final approach fix inbound on final approach.\n",
        "choiceone": "Entering instrument meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correcting an E.T.A. any time a previous E.T.A. is in error in excess of 2 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot, who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS advisory, is\nexpected to notify ATC and\n",
        "answer": "expeditiously return to the ATC clearance in effect prior to the advisory, after the\nconflict is resolved.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request a new ATC clearance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is required equipment for powered aircraft during VFR night flights?\n",
        "answer": "An electric landing light if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flashlight with red lens if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sensitive altimeter adjustable for barometric pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to \u201ccommercial operators\" relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "for compensation or hire, engages in the carriage by aircraft in air commerce of\npersons or property, other than as an air carrier.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the owner of a small scheduled airline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "for compensation or hire, engages in the carriage by aircraft in air commerce of\npersons or property, as an air carrier.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air operator may schedule a pilot to fly in an airplane, having two pilots and one\nadditional flight crewmember, for no more than\n",
        "answer": "12 hours during any 24 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) establishes:\n",
        "answer": "standards and recommended international practices for contracting member states.\n",
        "choiceone": "aeronautical standards adopted by all states.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proposals for aeronautical regulations in the form of 18 annexes.\n",
        "choicethree": "standards and recommended practices applied without exception by all states,\nsignatory to the Chicago convention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a pilot in command has reasonable grounds to believe that a person on board\nhas committed or is about to commit, on board the aircraft, an offence against penal law\n",
        "answer": "may deliver such person to the competent authorities\n",
        "choiceone": "may request such person to disembark\n",
        "choicetwo": "may require the assistance of passengers to restrain such person\n",
        "choicethree": "may not require or authorise the assistance of other crew members\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing has:\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).\n",
        "choiceone": "a military aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).\n",
        "choicethree": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate medical attention.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway-lead-in lighting shall consist:\n",
        "answer": "of groups of at least three white lights, flashing in sequence towards the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "always of a straight row of lights towards the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of a group of at least 5 flashing yellow lights.\n",
        "choicethree": "of an arbitrary amount of green lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (57).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-1?\n",
        "answer": "19,400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Commercial pilots are required to have a valid and appropriate pilot certificate in their\nphysical possession or readily accessible in the aircraft when\n",
        "answer": "acting as pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "piloting for hire only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "carrying passengers only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight attendant crewmember is required on aircraft having a passenger seating\nconfiguration, excluding any pilot seat, of\n",
        "answer": "20 or more\n",
        "choiceone": "15 or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19 or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to the operational control of a flight are in relation to\n",
        "answer": "ercising authority over initiating, conducting, or terminating a flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "the specific duties of any required crewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "acting as the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot file a composite flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Any time a portion of the flight will be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "When requested or advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time a landing is planned at an intermediate airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a required instrument on a multiengine aircraft becomes inoperative, which document\ndictates whether the flight may continue en route?\n",
        "answer": "An approved Minimum Equipment List for the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Original dispatch release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-3?\n",
        "answer": "215 knots and 1.44 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "217 knots and 1.50 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "216 knots and 1.40 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS Il provides\n",
        "answer": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maneuvers in all directions to avoid the conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A standard airworthiness certificate remains in effect as long as the aircraft receives\n",
        "answer": "required maintenance and inspections.\n",
        "choiceone": "an annual inspection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an annual inspection and a 100-hour inspection prior to their expiration dates.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) capability, the accuracy of\nthe GPS derived\n",
        "answer": "altitude information should not be relied upon to determine aircraft altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "position is not affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity information should be relied upon to determine aircraft groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, the tow pilot is required to\nhave\n",
        "answer": "a logbook endorsement from an authorized glider instructor certifying receipt of\nground and flight training in gliders, and be proficient with techniques and\nprocedures for safe towing of gliders.\n",
        "choiceone": "at least a private pilot certificate with a category rating for powered aircraft, and\nmade and logged at least three flights as pilot or observer in a glider being towed by\nan airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a logbook record of having made at least three flights as sole manipulator of the\ncontrols of a glider being towed by an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To carry passengers for hire in an airplane on cross-country flights of more than 50 NM\nfrom the departure airport, the pilot in command is required to hold at least\n",
        "answer": "a Commercial Pilot Licence with an instrument rating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a Category Il pilot authorization.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does a pilot normally obtain the current altimeter setting during an IFR flight in\nClass E airspace below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "ATC periodically advises the pilot of the proper altimeter setting.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot should contact ARTCC at least every 100 NM and request the altimeter\nsetting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Control Centers along the route broadcast the weather information at 15\nminutes past the hour.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a definition of the term \u2018crewmember\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "A person assigned to perform duty in an aircraft during flight time.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only a pilot, flight engineer, or flight navigator assigned to duty in an aircraft during\nflight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any person assigned to duty in an aircraft during flight except a pilot or flight\nengineer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intoxicated person creates a disturbance aboard an aircraft, the certificate holder\nmust submit a report, concerning the incident, to the responsible authority within\n",
        "answer": "5 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An approved cockpit voice recorder is required equipment in\n",
        "answer": "multiengine, turbine-powered airplanes having a passenger seating configuration of\n20 or more seats.\n",
        "choiceone": "large turbine-powered airplanes having a maximum passenger capacity of 20 or\nmore seats.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all aircraft operated in commuter air carrier service having a passenger seating\nconfiguration of 20 seats or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "becomes necessary to shut down one engine on a three-engine turbojet airplane,\ninvolved in domestic flight, the pilot in command:\n\n",
        "answer": "may continue to the planned destination if this is considered as safe as landing at\nthe nearest suitable airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "must land at the nearest suitable airport, in point of time, at which a safe landing can\nbe made.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may continue to the planned destination if approved by the company aircraft\ndispatcher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum flight time in 24 consecutive hours that an air operator may schedule a\npilot in a two-pilot crew without a rest period is\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in Class G airspace in VFR conditions\nduring daylight hours in area 4?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Civil Aviation Regulation, Medical certificates for flight crew classes are:\n",
        "answer": "1and2\n",
        "choiceone": "1,2and3\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,3 and 4\n",
        "choicethree": "class 1 only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft is subjected to unlawful interference, the pilot-in-command shall\nindicate the situation by setting the transponder to Mode A, Code\n",
        "answer": "7500.\n",
        "choiceone": "7700.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7600.\n",
        "choicethree": "7000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the climb-out phase of a flight the pilot-in-command becomes incapacitated.\nThe co-pilot takes over control of the aircraft and decides that he will return for landing.\nWhat action has to be taken after landing?\n",
        "answer": "This is a serious incident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an incident.\n",
        "choiceone": "This is an accident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an accident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation.\nThe operator must inform the Authority by writing an Irregularity Report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an irregularity.\nThe pilot-in-command or the Operator must deposit a report on behalf of the\ninvolved airport Authority within the following 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (58).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a physical deficiency under the standards specified in any EAC state,\nCAA regulations for their medical certificate.\n",
        "answer": "may not perform flight engineer duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "must surrender the medical certificate to an CAA inspector.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must have a recheck by an CAA approved medical examiner before returning to\nflight crewmember duties.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the use of airborne weather-avoidance radar for the recog!\nof certain weather conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "The radarscope provides no assurance of avoiding instrument weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "The avoidance of hail is assured when flying between and just clear of the most\nintense echoes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The clear area between intense echoes indicates that visual sighting of storms can\nbe maintained when flying between the echoes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a required instrument on a multiengine aircraft becomes inoperative, which document\ndictates whether the flight may continue en route?\n",
        "answer": "An approved Minimum Equipment List for the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Original dispatch release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the purpose of REIL?\n",
        "answer": "Identification of a runway surrounded by a preponderance of other lighting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identification of the touchdown zone to prevent landing short.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Establish visual descent guidance information during an approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of certain portable electronic devices is pro!\noperated under\n\nited on airships that are being\n",
        "answer": "IFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DVFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are considered aircraft class ratings?\n",
        "answer": "Single-engine land, multiengine land, single-engine sea, and multiengine sea.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transport, normal, utility, and acrobatic.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airplane, rotorcraft, glider, and lighter-than-air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "imposed on the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence if that person\ndoes not hold an instrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "That person is limited to private pilot privileges at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can the pilot of an airline find the latest NOTAMs?\n",
        "answer": "Any company dispatch facility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices To Airmen publication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is NOT a required item on the load manifest?\n",
        "answer": "List of passenger names and the weight of each.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft registration number or flight number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identification of crewmembers and their crew position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify REIL.\n",
        "answer": "Synchronized flashing lights laterally at each side of the runway threshold.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights for the first 2,000 feet of runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green lights at the threshold and red lights at far end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which data must be recorded in the aircraft log or other appropriate log by a pilot\nmaking a VOR operational check for IFR operations?\n",
        "answer": "Place of operational check, amount of bearing error, date of check, and signature.\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR name or identification, date of check, amount of bearing error, and signature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Date of check, VOR name or identification, place of operational check, and amount of\nbearing error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 138.) What night operations, if any, are authorized between the\napproach end of the runway and the threshold lights?\n",
        "answer": "Taxi and takeoff operations are permitted, providing the takeoff operations are\ntoward the visible green threshold lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "No aircraft operations are permitted short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only taxi operations are permitted in the area short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the tower and Flight Control Center (FCC) are located on the same airport, which\nfunction is provided by the FCC during those periods when the tower is closed?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Advisory Service.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach control services.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What flight time may a pilot log as second in command?\n",
        "answer": "All flight time when qualified and occupying a crewmember station in an aircraft that\nrequires more than one pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "All flight time while acting as second in command in aircraft configured for more than\none pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only that flight time during which the second in command is the sole manipulator of\nthe controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the lan:\nRWY 4R approach at BOS?\n\nig distance available for the VOR/DME RNAV\n",
        "answer": "8,850 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "7.000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10,005 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in area\n6?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures for keeping copies of the aircraft maintenance log of the aircraft available to\nappropriate personnel shall be set forth in\n",
        "answer": "the certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maintenance procedures handbook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Operations Specifications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-5?\n",
        "answer": "218 knots and 1.27 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "219 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "214 knots and 1.26 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an alternate airport is required, what are the weather minimums that must be\nforecast at the ETA for an alternate airport that has a precision approach procedure?\n\n",
        "answer": "600 foot ceiling and 2 statute miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ceiling 200 feet above the approach minimums and at least 1 statute mile visibility,\nbut not less than the minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ceiling 200 feet above field elevation and visibility 1 statute mile, but not less than\nthe minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-3?\n",
        "answer": "215 knots and 1.44 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "217 knots and 1.50 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "216 knots and 1.40 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition, if any, may a pilot descend below DH or MDA when using the\napproach light system as the primary visual reference for the intended runway?\n",
        "answer": "The approach light system can be used as a visual reference, except that descent\nbelow 100 feet above TDZE requires that the red light bars be visible and identifiable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Under no condition can the approach light system serve as a necessary visual\nreference for descent below DH or MDA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent to the intended runway is authorized as long as any portion of the\napproach light system can be seen.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What restrictions must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment of an airplane operated under the CAA regulations in an east african\nstate?\n",
        "answer": "Cargo may be carried aft of a divider if properly secured by a safety belt or other\ntiedown devices to withstand certain load stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "All cargo must be separated from the passengers by a partition capable of\nwithstanding certain load stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable flame resistant bin and the bin must be\nsecured to the floor structure of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While you are flying at FL250, you hear ATC give an altimeter setting of 28.92\" Hg in\nyour area. At what pressure altitude are you flying?\n",
        "answer": "25,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "24,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "26,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a commerciar flight to be released to an island airport for which an alternate airport\nis not available, a turbojet-powered airplane must have enough fuel to fly to that airport\nand thereafter to fly\n",
        "answer": "at least 2 hours at normal cruising fuel consumption.\n",
        "choiceone": "for 3 hours at normal cruising fuel consumption.\n",
        "choicetwo": "back to the departure airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should be amended\nor cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in excess of:\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choicethree": "60 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an air carrier airplane be DME equipped?\n",
        "answer": "Whenever VOR navigational receivers are required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In Class E airspace for all IFR or VFR on Top operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For flights at or above FL 180.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, then:\n",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed\n",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour to\nprovide for continuation of the flight;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;\n",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (59).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have filed an IFR flight plan with a VFR-On-Top clearance in lieu of an assigned\naltitude. If you receive this clearance and fly a course of 180 degrees, at what altitude\nshould you fly? (Assume VFR conditions.)\n",
        "answer": "An even thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any IFR altitude which will enable you to remain in VFR conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An odd thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To serve as second in command of an airplane that is certificated for more than one\npilot , and operated under the CAA regulations, a person must\n",
        "answer": "within the last 12 months become familiar with the required information, and perform\nand log pilot time in the type of airplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log flight training from an authorized flight instructor in the type of\nairplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold at least a commercial pilot certificate with an airplane category rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What is the approximate fuel consumed when holding\nunder Operating Conditions 0-3?\n",
        "answer": "2,940 pounds.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,520 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,250 pounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial operator plans to ferry a large, four-engine, reciprocating-engine-powered\nairplane from one facility to another to repair an inoperative engine. Whi\noperational requirement for the three-engine flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weather conditions at the takeoff and destination airports must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The gross weight at takeoff may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum certificated\ngross weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The computed takeoff distance to reach V(1) must not exceed 70 percent of the\neffective runway length.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is a pilot on an IFR flight plan responsible for avoiding other aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "When weather conditions permit, regardless of whether operating under IFR or VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "At all times when notin radar contact with ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when advised by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the purpose of REIL?\n",
        "answer": "Identification of a runway surrounded by a preponderance of other lighting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identification of the touchdown zone to prevent landing short.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Establish visual descent guidance information during an approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When departing from an airport located outside controlled airspace during IMC, you\nmust file an IFR flight plan and receive a clearance before\n",
        "answer": "entering Class E airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "takeoff.\n",
        "choicetwo": "entering IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL under special VFR during\ndaylight hours in area 5?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 mile; (I) 2,000 feet; (J) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Portable electronic devices which may cause interference with the navigation or\ncommunication system may not be operated on an civil aircraft registered in an EAC\nstate being flown\n",
        "answer": "in air carrier operations.\n",
        "choiceone": "along route airways.\n",
        "choicetwo": "within the EAC\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n16,000 pounds?IInitial weight: 175,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 138,000 Ib\n",
        "answer": "9 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airborne incident would require that the nearest ATS office be notified\nimmediately?\n\n",
        "answer": "Flight control system malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo compartment door malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin door opened in-flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to the operational control of a flight are in relation to\n",
        "answer": "ercising authority over initiating, conducting, or terminating a flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "the specific duties of any required crewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "acting as the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, except by arrangement with the pilot in command of each aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC may assign the MOCA when certain special conditions exist, and when within\n",
        "answer": "22 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How often must a crewmember actually operate the airplane emergency equipment,\n\n",
        "answer": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A dispatch release for a domestic flight must contain or have attached to it\n",
        "answer": "minimum fuel supply and weather information for the complete flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "trip number and weight and balance data.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weather information for the complete flight and a crew list.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, the pilot in command in East africa shall to hold a type\nrating when operating any\n",
        "answer": "aircraft of more than 12,500 pounds maximum certificated takeoff weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft that is certificated for more than one pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "multiengine airplane having a gross weight of more than 12,000 pounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An abbreviated departure clearance '...CLEARED AS FILED...\u2019 will always con\u2019\nname\n",
        "answer": "of the destination airport filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "and number of the STAR to be flown when filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of the first compulsory reporting point if not in a radar environment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in\nClass G airspace during daylight hours for area 2?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-On-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1200 feet AGL). What is the in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operation in Class E airspace during daylight hours for area 1?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "By regulation, who shall provide the pilot in command of a domestic operations\ninformation concerning weather, and irregularities of facilities and services?\n\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person whose duties include the handling or carriage of dangerous articles and/or\nmagnetized materials must have satisfactorily completed an established and approved\ntraining program within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airspace is defined as a transition area when designated in conjunction with an\nairport which has a prescribed IAP?\n\n",
        "answer": "The Class E airspace extending upward from 700 feet or more above the surface and\nterminating at the base of the overlying controlled airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "That Class D airspace extending from the surface and terminating at the base of the\ncontinental control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Class C airspace extending from the surface to 700 or 1,200 feet AGL, where\ndesignated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 78 and 79.) What is your position relative to the VOR COP southeast\nbound on V86 between the BOZEMAN and LIVINGSTON VORTACs? The No. 1 VOR is\ntuned to 116.1 and the No. 2 VOR is tuned to 112.2.\n",
        "answer": "Past the LVM R-246 and east of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choiceone": "Past the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approaching the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless a higher speed is required due to turbulence or icing and ATC is notified, the\nmaximum holding speed for a civil turbojet holding at a civil airport at 18,000 feet above\nMSL is:\n",
        "answer": "265 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "250 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is required to submit a written report on a deviation that occurs during an\nemergency?\n",
        "answer": "Person who declares the emergency.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatcher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC has assigned you the transponder code 5320.\nIn case of loosing two way radio communication, you have to squawk:\n",
        "answer": "Mode A Code 7600\n",
        "choiceone": "Mode A Code 5320\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mode A Code 7700\n",
        "choicethree": "Mode A Code 7500\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days must the operator of an aircraft involved in an accident file a\nreport ?\n",
        "answer": "10 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Conviction for violating any East african Civil Aviation regulation relating to drugs\n",
        "answer": "could result in the suspension or revocation of any licences or rating held.\n",
        "choiceone": "automatically revokes any licences held.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not a consideration for suspension or revocation of any licence held.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For IFR planning purposes, what are the compulsory reporting points when using\nVORIDME or VORTAC fixes to define a direct route not on established airways?\n",
        "answer": "Fixes selected to define the route.\n",
        "choiceone": "There are no compulsory reporting points unless advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the changeover points.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating near other aircraft in flight? They are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, when operated so close to another aircraft they can create a collision\nhazard.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have just landed and the tower tells you to call ground control when clear of the\nrunway. You are considered clear of the runway when\n",
        "answer": "all parts of the aircraft have crossed the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aft end of the aircraft is even with the taxiway location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating limitations of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane?\n",
        "answer": "No person may operate a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane carrying passengers or\nproperty for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "A \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane is limited to a specified operating radius from its home\nbase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A pilot of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane must hold a commercial pilot certificate when\ncarrying passengers for compensation or hire.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS Il provides\n",
        "answer": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maneuvers in all directions to avoid the conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS ll, resolution\nadvisory (RA) is expected to\n",
        "answer": "notify ATC of the deviation as soon as practicable.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request ATC clearance for the deviation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An abbreviated departure clearance '...CLEARED AS FILED...\u2019 will always con\u2019\nname\n",
        "answer": "of the destination airport filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "and number of the STAR to be flown when filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of the first compulsory reporting point if not in a radar environment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is DME required for an instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In terminal radar service areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot flying a single-engine airplane observes a multiengine airplane approaching from\nthe left. Which pilot should give way?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot of the multiengine airplane should give way\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot of the single-engine airplane should give way\n",
        "choicetwo": "Each pilot should alter course to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018taxiway ending\u2019 marker\n",
        "answer": "indicates taxiway does not continue.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which manoeuvre will be executed by an intercepting aircraft if the pilot of this aircraft\nwants to communicate to the intercepted aircraft \"YOU MAY PROCEED\"?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt break-away manoeuvre from the intercepted aircraft consisting of a\nclimbing turn of 90 degrees or more without crossing the line of flight of the\nintercepted aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rocking aircraft twice in front of the intercepting aircraft, after acknowledgement by\nintercepted aircraft a slow level turn (normally to the left).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Circling the intercepted aircraft in a counter-clockwise pattern for aeroplanes, in a\nclockwise pattern for helicopter.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rocking aircraft and flashing navigational lights at regular intervals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:\n",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.\n",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.\n",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Define aerodrome traffic.\n",
        "answer": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome.\n",
        "choiceone": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All traffic on the movement area and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "All traffic in the aerodrome circuit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"PAPI\" shall consist of:\n",
        "answer": "A wing bar of 4 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two wing bars of 4 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two wing bars of 6 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicethree": "A wing bar of 2 sharp transition multi-lamp equally spaced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (60).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before takeoff, the pilot in command of an aircraft carrying passengers shall ensure that\nall passengers have been orally briefed on the normal and emergency use of oxygen\n",
        "answer": "if the flight involves operations above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "regardless of the altitude at which the flight will operate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the flight involves operations at or above 12,000 feet MSL for more than 30\nminutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL under special VFR during\ndaylight hours in area 5?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 mile; (I) 2,000 feet; (J) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What is the approximate fuel consumed when holding\nunder Operating Conditions 0-1?\n",
        "answer": "1,625 pounds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,950 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,440 pounds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional flight hours within the preceding 6 calendar months are required to\nmaintain IFR currency in a helicopter?\n",
        "answer": "6 instrument approaches, holding procedures and tracking courses must be\naccomplished.\n",
        "choiceone": "three instrument approaches must also be accomplished.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours of actual or simulated instrument time in the same type helicopter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During flight a fire which was extinguished burned the insulation from a transceiver\nwire. What action is required by regulations?\n",
        "answer": "An immediate notification by the operator of the aircraft to the nearest CAA field\noffice.\n",
        "choiceone": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A report must be filed with the avionics inspector at the nearest CAA Flight\nStandards Office\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A series of continuous red lights in the runway centerline lighting indicates that\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "one-half of the runway remains.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airplanes are required to be equipped with a ground proximity warning glide\nslope deviation alerting system?\n",
        "answer": "All turbine powered airplanes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Passenger-carrying turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Large turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial\nperson does not hold an instrument pilot rating?\n\nplane pilot if that\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 nautical miles (NM).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for\nnight flights, but not limited for day flights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The carriage of passengers for hire by a commercial pilot is\n",
        "answer": "not authorized in a \u2018limited\u2019 category aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized in a \u2018utility\u2019 category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized in \u2018restricted\u2019 category aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "MOAs are established to\n",
        "answer": "separate certain military activities from IFR traffic.\n",
        "choiceone": "prohibit all civil aircraft because of hazardous or secret activities.\n",
        "choicetwo": "restrict civil aircraft during periods of high-density training activities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is NOT a required item on the load manifest?\n",
        "answer": "List of passenger names and the weight of each.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft registration number or flight number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identification of crewmembers and their crew position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures for keeping copies of the aircraft maintenance log of the aircraft available to\nappropriate personnel shall be set forth in\n",
        "answer": "the certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maintenance procedures handbook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Operations Specifications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A coded transponder equipped with altitude reporting capabil\ncontrolled airspace\n\nis required in all\n",
        "answer": "at and above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "at and above 2,500 feet above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized when carrying passengers for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not authorized when visibilities are less than 3 SM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n16,000 pounds?IInitial weight: 175,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 138,000 Ib\n",
        "answer": "9 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pilot loses visual reference while circling to land from an instrument approach and\nATC radar service is not available, the missed approach action should be to\n",
        "answer": "make a climbing turn toward the landing runway and continue the turn until\nestablished on the missed approach course.\n",
        "choiceone": "execute a climbing turn to parallel the published final approach course and climb to\nthe initial approach altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "climb to the published circling minimums then proceed direct to the final approach\nfix.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data kept, in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in terminating the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 days.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of runway lighting con:\neach side of the runway threshold?\n\nsts of a pair of synchronized flashing lights, one on\n",
        "answer": "REIL.\n",
        "choiceone": "RAIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "HIRL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude and route should be used if the pilot is flying in IFR weather conditions\nand has two-way radio communications failure?\n",
        "answer": "Continue on the route specified in the clearance and fly the highest of the following:\nthe last assigned altitude, altitude ATC has informed the pilot to expect, or to the\nmaximum Elevation Altitude( MEA)\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend to MEA and, if clear of clouds, proceed to the nearest appropriate airport. If\nnot clear of clouds, maintain the highest of the MEAs along the clearance route.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly the most direct route to the destination, maintaining the last assigned altitude or\nMEA, whichever is higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is required equipment for powered\nflights?\n\n",
        "answer": "Anticollision light system.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gyroscopic direction indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gyroscopic bank-and-pitch indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which restriction must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment?\n",
        "answer": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable bin and secured to a passenger seat or the\nfloor structure of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis packaged or covered to avoid possible injury to occupants.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cargo carried in passenger seats must be forward of all passengers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 78.) What is the mi\nfor a flight southeast bound on V86?\n\njum crossing altitude over the BOZEMAN VORTAC\n",
        "answer": "9,300 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "8,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9,700 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What\nG airspace?\n\nplane to operate under VFR in Class\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot ceiling; 2-miles flight visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile flight visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following elements\n",
        "answer": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and pre-flight\ninformation bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries\n",
        "choiceone": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP, NOTAM, AIC and checklist\nsummaries\n",
        "choicetwo": "AIP, supplements to AIP; NOTAM and PIB; AIC and checklist summaries\n",
        "choicethree": "AIP including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM, AIC; AIRAC\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-1?\n",
        "answer": "19,400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Commercial pilots are required to have a valid and appropriate pilot certificate in their\nphysical possession or readily accessible in the aircraft when\n",
        "answer": "acting as pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "piloting for hire only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "carrying passengers only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight attendant crewmember is required on aircraft having a passenger seating\nconfiguration, excluding any pilot seat, of\n",
        "answer": "20 or more\n",
        "choiceone": "15 or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19 or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to the operational control of a flight are in relation to\n",
        "answer": "ercising authority over initiating, conducting, or terminating a flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "the specific duties of any required crewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "acting as the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot file a composite flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Any time a portion of the flight will be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "When requested or advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time a landing is planned at an intermediate airport.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a required instrument on a multiengine aircraft becomes inoperative, which document\ndictates whether the flight may continue en route?\n",
        "answer": "An approved Minimum Equipment List for the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Original dispatch release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-3?\n",
        "answer": "215 knots and 1.44 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "217 knots and 1.50 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "216 knots and 1.40 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS Il provides\n",
        "answer": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maneuvers in all directions to avoid the conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A standard airworthiness certificate remains in effect as long as the aircraft receives\n",
        "answer": "required maintenance and inspections.\n",
        "choiceone": "an annual inspection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an annual inspection and a 100-hour inspection prior to their expiration dates.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) capability, the accuracy of\nthe GPS derived\n",
        "answer": "altitude information should not be relied upon to determine aircraft altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "position is not affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity information should be relied upon to determine aircraft groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, the tow pilot is required to\nhave\n",
        "answer": "a logbook endorsement from an authorized glider instructor certifying receipt of\nground and flight training in gliders, and be proficient with techniques and\nprocedures for safe towing of gliders.\n",
        "choiceone": "at least a private pilot certificate with a category rating for powered aircraft, and\nmade and logged at least three flights as pilot or observer in a glider being towed by\nan airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a logbook record of having made at least three flights as sole manipulator of the\ncontrols of a glider being towed by an airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To carry passengers for hire in an airplane on cross-country flights of more than 50 NM\nfrom the departure airport, the pilot in command is required to hold at least\n",
        "answer": "a Commercial Pilot Licence with an instrument rating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a Category Il pilot authorization.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does a pilot normally obtain the current altimeter setting during an IFR flight in\nClass E airspace below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "ATC periodically advises the pilot of the proper altimeter setting.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot should contact ARTCC at least every 100 NM and request the altimeter\nsetting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Control Centers along the route broadcast the weather information at 15\nminutes past the hour.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a definition of the term \u2018crewmember\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "A person assigned to perform duty in an aircraft during flight time.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only a pilot, flight engineer, or flight navigator assigned to duty in an aircraft during\nflight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any person assigned to duty in an aircraft during flight except a pilot or flight\nengineer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intoxicated person creates a disturbance aboard an aircraft, the certificate holder\nmust submit a report, concerning the incident, to the responsible authority within\n",
        "answer": "5 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An approved cockpit voice recorder is required equipment in\n",
        "answer": "multiengine, turbine-powered airplanes having a passenger seating configuration of\n20 or more seats.\n",
        "choiceone": "large turbine-powered airplanes having a maximum passenger capacity of 20 or\nmore seats.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all aircraft operated in commuter air carrier service having a passenger seating\nconfiguration of 20 seats or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "becomes necessary to shut down one engine on a three-engine turbojet airplane,\ninvolved in domestic flight, the pilot in command:\n\n",
        "answer": "may continue to the planned destination if this is considered as safe as landing at\nthe nearest suitable airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "must land at the nearest suitable airport, in point of time, at which a safe landing can\nbe made.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may continue to the planned destination if approved by the company aircraft\ndispatcher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum flight time in 24 consecutive hours that an air operator may schedule a\npilot in a two-pilot crew without a rest period is\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in Class G airspace in VFR conditions\nduring daylight hours in area 4?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Civil Aviation Regulation, Medical certificates for flight crew classes are:\n",
        "answer": "1and2\n",
        "choiceone": "1,2and3\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,3 and 4\n",
        "choicethree": "class 1 only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft is subjected to unlawful interference, the pilot-in-command shall\nindicate the situation by setting the transponder to Mode A, Code\n",
        "answer": "7500.\n",
        "choiceone": "7700.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7600.\n",
        "choicethree": "7000.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the climb-out phase of a flight the pilot-in-command becomes incapacitated.\nThe co-pilot takes over control of the aircraft and decides that he will return for landing.\nWhat action has to be taken after landing?\n",
        "answer": "This is a serious incident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an incident.\n",
        "choiceone": "This is an accident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an accident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation.\nThe operator must inform the Authority by writing an Irregularity Report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an irregularity.\nThe pilot-in-command or the Operator must deposit a report on behalf of the\ninvolved airport Authority within the following 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot of a turbine-powered airplane should climb as rapidly as practicable after taking\noff to what altitude?\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to carrying passengers at night, the pilot in command must have accom,\nrequired takeoffs and landings in\n",
        "answer": "the same category, class, and type of aircraft (if a type rating is required).\n",
        "choiceone": "any category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same category and class of aircraft to be used.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As each blade flaps up and down, it produces a shift of the center of its mass. When the\nblade flaps up, the CG moves closer to its axis of rotation, giving that blade a tendency\nto\n",
        "answer": "accelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as Coriolis effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "stabilize its rotational velocity, thus compensating for dissymmetry of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as translating tendency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you obtain the pressure altitude on flights below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Set your altimeter to 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choiceone": "Use your computer to change the indicated altitude to pressure altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Contact an FSS and ask for the pressure altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To comply with ATC instructions for altitude changes of more than 1,000 feet, what rate\nof climb or descent should be used?\n",
        "answer": "As rapidly as practicable to 1,000 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then\nbetween 500 and 1,500 feet per minute until reaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "As rapidly as practicable to 500 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then at\n500 feet per minute until the assigned altitude is reached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet per minute during climb and 500 feet per minute during descents until\nreaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What point at the destination should be used to compute estimated time en route on an\nIFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "The point of first intended landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The final approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The initial approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the normal upper limit for Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall a commercial operator retain a record of the load manifest,\nairworthiness release, pilot route certification, flight release, and flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "3 months.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 month.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 months.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum IFR altitude you may fly in an unpressurized aircraft without\nproviding passengers with supplemental oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "12,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which facility may be substituted for the middle marker during a Category I ILS\napproach?\n",
        "answer": "Compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORIDME FIX.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surveillance radar.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which passenger announcement(s) must be made after each takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "Passengers should keep seat belts fastened while seated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Keep safety belts fastened while seated and no smoking in the aircraft lavatories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "How to use the passenger oxygen system and that there is a $1,000 fine for\ntampering with a smoke detector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is contained in the Notices to Airman(NOTAM) Publication ?\n",
        "answer": "Current NOTAM(D) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choiceone": "All Current NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Current NOTAM(L) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If there is a required emergency exit located in the flightcrew compartment, the door\nwhich separates the compartment from the passenger cabin must be\n",
        "answer": "latched open during takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "unlocked during takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "locked at all times, except during any emergency declared by the pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ensuring that appropriate aeronautical charts are aboard an aircraft is the responsibility\nof the:\n",
        "answer": "pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight navigator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information concerning parachute jumping sites may be found in the\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Graphic Notices and Supplemental Data.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum\nbelow 10,000 feet MSL?\n\nicated airspeed a turbine-powered\n\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "288 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is required equipment for powered aircraft during VFR night flights?\n",
        "answer": "An electric landing light if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flashlight with red lens if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sensitive altimeter adjustable for barometric pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than in cruise flight, below what altitude are non-safety related cockpit activities\nby flight crewmembers prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "12,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/airlaw\\atpl (9).pdf"
    }
]